var words = 
[
    {
        "question": "لَإِبْرَاهِيمَ",
        "answer": "(was) surely Ibrahim",
        "pcklId": "57",
        "rootWordId": 6,
        "tlit": "la-ib'rāhīma",
        "frequency": "69",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "83",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " وَإِنَّ مِنْ شِيعَتِهِ لَإِبْرَاهِيمَ",
        "rootWord": "إِبْرَاهِيم",
        "rootWordType": "proper noun",
        "wazn": "إِبْرَاهِيم",
        "waznEnglish": "Ibrahim",
        "waznTlit": "ib'rāhīm",
        "waznType": "Proper noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "يَا إِبْرَاهِيمُ",
        "answer": "O Ibrahim",
        "pcklId": "58",
        "rootWordId": 6,
        "tlit": "yāib'rāhīmu",
        "frequency": "69",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "104",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " وَنَادَيْنَاهُ أَنْ يَا إِبْرَاهِيمُ",
        "rootWord": "إِبْرَاهِيم",
        "rootWordType": "proper noun",
        "wazn": "إِبْرَاهِيم",
        "waznEnglish": "Ibrahim",
        "waznTlit": "ib'rāhīm",
        "waznType": "Proper noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "إِبْرَاهِيمَ",
        "answer": "Ibrahim",
        "pcklId": "59",
        "rootWordId": 6,
        "tlit": "ib'rāhīma",
        "frequency": "69",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "109",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " سَلَامٌ عَلَىٰ إِبْرَاهِيمَ",
        "rootWord": "إِبْرَاهِيم",
        "rootWordType": "proper noun",
        "wazn": "إِبْرَاهِيم",
        "waznEnglish": "Ibrahim",
        "waznTlit": "ib'rāhīm",
        "waznType": "Proper noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "أَبَقَ",
        "answer": "he ran away",
        "pcklId": "0",
        "rootWordId": 7,
        "tlit": "abaqa",
        "frequency": "1",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "140",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " إِذْ أَبَقَ إِلَى الْفُلْكِ الْمَشْحُونِ",
        "rootWord": "أ ب ق",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أ ب ق",
        "waznEnglish": "to run away, to flee",
        "waznTlit": "hamza bā qāf",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "أَوَآبَاؤُنَا",
        "answer": "Or our fathers",
        "pcklId": "50",
        "rootWordId": 10,
        "tlit": "awaābāunā",
        "frequency": "117",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "17",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " أَوَآبَاؤُنَا الْأَوَّلُونَ",
        "rootWord": "أ ب و",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "آبَاء",
        "waznEnglish": "forefathers, fathers, parents",
        "waznTlit": "ābā",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "آبَاءَهُمْ",
        "answer": "their fathers",
        "pcklId": "51",
        "rootWordId": 10,
        "tlit": "ābāahum",
        "frequency": "117",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "69",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّهُمْ أَلْفَوْا آبَاءَهُمْ ضَالِّينَ",
        "rootWord": "أ ب و",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "آبَاء",
        "waznEnglish": "forefathers, fathers, parents",
        "waznTlit": "ābā",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "آبَائِكُمُ",
        "answer": "(of) your forefathers",
        "pcklId": "52",
        "rootWordId": 10,
        "tlit": "ābāikumu",
        "frequency": "117",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "126",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " اللَّهَ رَبَّكُمْ وَرَبَّ آبَائِكُمُ الْأَوَّلِينَ",
        "rootWord": "أ ب و",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "آبَاء",
        "waznEnglish": "forefathers, fathers, parents",
        "waznTlit": "ābā",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "لِأَبِيهِ",
        "answer": "to his father",
        "pcklId": "104",
        "rootWordId": 10,
        "tlit": "li-abīhi",
        "frequency": "117",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "85",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " إِذْ قَالَ لِأَبِيهِ وَقَوْمِهِ مَاذَا تَعْبُدُونَ",
        "rootWord": "أ ب و",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَبٌ",
        "waznEnglish": "father",
        "waznTlit": "abun",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "يَا أَبَتِ",
        "answer": "O my father",
        "pcklId": "105",
        "rootWordId": 10,
        "tlit": "yāabati",
        "frequency": "117",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "102",
        "wordnum": "17",
        "arabicAyah": " قَالَ يَا أَبَتِ افْعَلْ مَا تُؤْمَرُ سَتَجِدُنِي إِنْ شَاءَ اللَّهُ مِنَ الصَّابِرِينَ",
        "rootWord": "أ ب و",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَبٌ",
        "waznEnglish": "father",
        "waznTlit": "abun",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "تَأْتُونَنَا",
        "answer": "come (to) us",
        "pcklId": "214",
        "rootWordId": 12,
        "tlit": "tatūnanā",
        "frequency": "549",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "28",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " قَالُوا إِنَّكُمْ كُنْتُمْ تَأْتُونَنَا عَنِ الْيَمِينِ",
        "rootWord": "أ ت ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَتَى",
        "waznEnglish": "to come, to bring",
        "waznTlit": "atā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "فَأْتُوا",
        "answer": "Then bring",
        "pcklId": "215",
        "rootWordId": 12,
        "tlit": "fatū",
        "frequency": "549",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "157",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " فَأْتُوا بِكِتَابِكُمْ إِنْ كُنْتُمْ صَادِقِينَ",
        "rootWord": "أ ت ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَتَى",
        "waznEnglish": "to come, to bring",
        "waznTlit": "atā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَآتَيْنَاهُمَا",
        "answer": "And We gave both of them",
        "pcklId": "486",
        "rootWordId": 12,
        "tlit": "waātaynāhumā",
        "frequency": "549",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "117",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " وَآتَيْنَاهُمَا الْكِتَابَ الْمُسْتَبِينَ",
        "rootWord": "أ ت ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "آتَى",
        "waznEnglish": "to give",
        "waznTlit": "ātā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form IV)"
    },
    {
        "question": "آثَارِهِمْ",
        "answer": "their footsteps",
        "pcklId": "13",
        "rootWordId": 14,
        "tlit": "āthārihim",
        "frequency": "21",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "70",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " فَهُمْ عَلَىٰ آثَارِهِمْ يُهْرَعُونَ",
        "rootWord": "أ ث ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَثَر",
        "waznEnglish": "footsteps, tracks, impressions",
        "waznTlit": "athar",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْآخِرِينَ",
        "answer": "the later generations",
        "pcklId": "122",
        "rootWordId": 22,
        "tlit": "l-ākhirīna",
        "frequency": "250",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "78",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " وَتَرَكْنَا عَلَيْهِ فِي الْآخِرِينَ",
        "rootWord": "أ خ ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "آخِر",
        "waznEnglish": "Hereafter, end, last, later generations",
        "waznTlit": "ākhir",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْآخِرِينَ",
        "answer": "the later generations",
        "pcklId": "123",
        "rootWordId": 22,
        "tlit": "l-ākhirīna",
        "frequency": "250",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "108",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " وَتَرَكْنَا عَلَيْهِ فِي الْآخِرِينَ",
        "rootWord": "أ خ ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "آخِر",
        "waznEnglish": "Hereafter, end, last, later generations",
        "waznTlit": "ākhir",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْآخِرِينَ",
        "answer": "the later generations",
        "pcklId": "124",
        "rootWordId": 22,
        "tlit": "l-ākhirīna",
        "frequency": "250",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "119",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " وَتَرَكْنَا عَلَيْهِمَا فِي الْآخِرِينَ",
        "rootWord": "أ خ ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "آخِر",
        "waznEnglish": "Hereafter, end, last, later generations",
        "waznTlit": "ākhir",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْآخِرِينَ",
        "answer": "the later generations",
        "pcklId": "125",
        "rootWordId": 22,
        "tlit": "l-ākhirīna",
        "frequency": "250",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "129",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " وَتَرَكْنَا عَلَيْهِ فِي الْآخِرِينَ",
        "rootWord": "أ خ ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "آخِر",
        "waznEnglish": "Hereafter, end, last, later generations",
        "waznTlit": "ākhir",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْآخَرِينَ",
        "answer": "the others",
        "pcklId": "205",
        "rootWordId": 22,
        "tlit": "l-ākharīna",
        "frequency": "250",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "82",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " ثُمَّ أَغْرَقْنَا الْآخَرِينَ",
        "rootWord": "أ خ ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "آخَر",
        "waznEnglish": "other, last",
        "waznTlit": "ākhar",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْآخَرِينَ",
        "answer": "the others",
        "pcklId": "206",
        "rootWordId": 22,
        "tlit": "l-ākharīna",
        "frequency": "250",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "136",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " ثُمَّ دَمَّرْنَا الْآخَرِينَ",
        "rootWord": "أ خ ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "آخَر",
        "waznEnglish": "other, last",
        "waznTlit": "ākhar",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "إِذْ",
        "answer": "When",
        "pcklId": "193",
        "rootWordId": 26,
        "tlit": "idh",
        "frequency": "239",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "84",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " إِذْ جَاءَ رَبَّهُ بِقَلْبٍ سَلِيمٍ",
        "rootWord": "إِذ",
        "rootWordType": "time adverb",
        "wazn": "إِذ",
        "waznEnglish": "when",
        "waznTlit": "idh",
        "waznType": "Time adverb"
    },
    {
        "question": "إِذْ",
        "answer": "When",
        "pcklId": "194",
        "rootWordId": 26,
        "tlit": "idh",
        "frequency": "239",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "85",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " إِذْ قَالَ لِأَبِيهِ وَقَوْمِهِ مَاذَا تَعْبُدُونَ",
        "rootWord": "إِذ",
        "rootWordType": "time adverb",
        "wazn": "إِذ",
        "waznEnglish": "when",
        "waznTlit": "idh",
        "waznType": "Time adverb"
    },
    {
        "question": "إِذْ",
        "answer": "When",
        "pcklId": "195",
        "rootWordId": 26,
        "tlit": "idh",
        "frequency": "239",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "124",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " إِذْ قَالَ لِقَوْمِهِ أَلَا تَتَّقُونَ",
        "rootWord": "إِذ",
        "rootWordType": "time adverb",
        "wazn": "إِذ",
        "waznEnglish": "when",
        "waznTlit": "idh",
        "waznType": "Time adverb"
    },
    {
        "question": "إِذْ",
        "answer": "When",
        "pcklId": "196",
        "rootWordId": 26,
        "tlit": "idh",
        "frequency": "239",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "134",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " إِذْ نَجَّيْنَاهُ وَأَهْلَهُ أَجْمَعِينَ",
        "rootWord": "إِذ",
        "rootWordType": "time adverb",
        "wazn": "إِذ",
        "waznEnglish": "when",
        "waznTlit": "idh",
        "waznType": "Time adverb"
    },
    {
        "question": "إِذْ",
        "answer": "When",
        "pcklId": "197",
        "rootWordId": 26,
        "tlit": "idh",
        "frequency": "239",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "140",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " إِذْ أَبَقَ إِلَى الْفُلْكِ الْمَشْحُونِ",
        "rootWord": "إِذ",
        "rootWordType": "time adverb",
        "wazn": "إِذ",
        "waznEnglish": "when",
        "waznTlit": "idh",
        "waznType": "Time adverb"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَإِذَا",
        "answer": "And when",
        "pcklId": "259",
        "rootWordId": 27,
        "tlit": "wa-idhā",
        "frequency": "409",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "13",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " وَإِذَا ذُكِّرُوا لَا يَذْكُرُونَ",
        "rootWord": "إِذَا",
        "rootWordType": "nominal",
        "wazn": "إِذَا",
        "waznEnglish": "when",
        "waznTlit": "idhā",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Time adverb)"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَإِذَا",
        "answer": "And when",
        "pcklId": "260",
        "rootWordId": 27,
        "tlit": "wa-idhā",
        "frequency": "409",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "14",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " وَإِذَا رَأَوْا آيَةً يَسْتَسْخِرُونَ",
        "rootWord": "إِذَا",
        "rootWordType": "nominal",
        "wazn": "إِذَا",
        "waznEnglish": "when",
        "waznTlit": "idhā",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Time adverb)"
    },
    {
        "question": "أَإِذَا",
        "answer": "Is it when",
        "pcklId": "261",
        "rootWordId": 27,
        "tlit": "a-idhā",
        "frequency": "409",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "16",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " أَإِذَا مِتْنَا وَكُنَّا تُرَابًا وَعِظَامًا أَإِنَّا لَمَبْعُوثُونَ",
        "rootWord": "إِذَا",
        "rootWordType": "nominal",
        "wazn": "إِذَا",
        "waznEnglish": "when",
        "waznTlit": "idhā",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Time adverb)"
    },
    {
        "question": "فَإِذَا",
        "answer": "then, behold",
        "pcklId": "262",
        "rootWordId": 27,
        "tlit": "fa-idhā",
        "frequency": "409",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "19",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " فَإِنَّمَا هِيَ زَجْرَةٌ وَاحِدَةٌ فَإِذَا هُمْ يَنْظُرُونَ",
        "rootWord": "إِذَا",
        "rootWordType": "nominal",
        "wazn": "إِذَا",
        "waznEnglish": "when",
        "waznTlit": "idhā",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Time adverb)"
    },
    {
        "question": "إِذَا",
        "answer": "when",
        "pcklId": "263",
        "rootWordId": 27,
        "tlit": "idhā",
        "frequency": "409",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "35",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّهُمْ كَانُوا إِذَا قِيلَ لَهُمْ لَا إِلَٰهَ إِلَّا اللَّهُ يَسْتَكْبِرُونَ",
        "rootWord": "إِذَا",
        "rootWordType": "nominal",
        "wazn": "إِذَا",
        "waznEnglish": "when",
        "waznTlit": "idhā",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Time adverb)"
    },
    {
        "question": "أَإِذَا",
        "answer": "Is (it) when",
        "pcklId": "264",
        "rootWordId": 27,
        "tlit": "a-idhā",
        "frequency": "409",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "53",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " أَإِذَا مِتْنَا وَكُنَّا تُرَابًا وَعِظَامًا أَإِنَّا لَمَدِينُونَ",
        "rootWord": "إِذَا",
        "rootWordType": "nominal",
        "wazn": "إِذَا",
        "waznEnglish": "when",
        "waznTlit": "idhā",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Time adverb)"
    },
    {
        "question": "فَإِذَا",
        "answer": "But when",
        "pcklId": "265",
        "rootWordId": 27,
        "tlit": "fa-idhā",
        "frequency": "409",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "177",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " فَإِذَا نَزَلَ بِسَاحَتِهِمْ فَسَاءَ صَبَاحُ الْمُنْذَرِينَ",
        "rootWord": "إِذَا",
        "rootWordType": "nominal",
        "wazn": "إِذَا",
        "waznEnglish": "when",
        "waznTlit": "idhā",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Time adverb)"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَالْأَرْضِ",
        "answer": "and the earth",
        "pcklId": "332",
        "rootWordId": 32,
        "tlit": "wal-arḍi",
        "frequency": "461",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "5",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " رَبُّ السَّمَاوَاتِ وَالْأَرْضِ وَمَا بَيْنَهُمَا وَرَبُّ الْمَشَارِقِ",
        "rootWord": "أ ر ض",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أ ر ض",
        "waznEnglish": "the Earth, land",
        "waznTlit": "hamza rā ḍād",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "بِإِسْحَاقَ",
        "answer": "of Isaac",
        "pcklId": "14",
        "rootWordId": 39,
        "tlit": "bi-is'ḥāqa",
        "frequency": "17",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "112",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " وَبَشَّرْنَاهُ بِإِسْحَاقَ نَبِيًّا مِنَ الصَّالِحِينَ",
        "rootWord": "إِسْحَاق",
        "rootWordType": "proper noun",
        "wazn": "إِسْحَاق",
        "waznEnglish": "Isaac",
        "waznTlit": "is'ḥāq",
        "waznType": "Proper noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "إِسْحَاقَ",
        "answer": "Isaac",
        "pcklId": "15",
        "rootWordId": 39,
        "tlit": "is'ḥāqa",
        "frequency": "17",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "113",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " وَبَارَكْنَا عَلَيْهِ وَعَلَىٰ إِسْحَاقَ",
        "rootWord": "إِسْحَاق",
        "rootWordType": "proper noun",
        "wazn": "إِسْحَاق",
        "waznEnglish": "Isaac",
        "waznTlit": "is'ḥāq",
        "waznType": "Proper noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "أَصْلِ",
        "answer": "(the) bottom",
        "pcklId": "1",
        "rootWordId": 49,
        "tlit": "aṣli",
        "frequency": "10",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "64",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّهَا شَجَرَةٌ تَخْرُجُ فِي أَصْلِ الْجَحِيمِ",
        "rootWord": "أ ص ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَصْل",
        "waznEnglish": "root, bottom",
        "waznTlit": "aṣl",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "أَئِفْكًا",
        "answer": "Is it falsehood ",
        "pcklId": "21",
        "rootWordId": 52,
        "tlit": "a-if'kan",
        "frequency": "30",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "86",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " أَئِفْكًا آلِهَةً دُونَ اللَّهِ تُرِيدُونَ",
        "rootWord": "أ ف ك",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "إِفْك",
        "waznEnglish": "lie, falsehood",
        "waznTlit": "if'k",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "إِفْكِهِمْ",
        "answer": "their falsehood",
        "pcklId": "22",
        "rootWordId": 52,
        "tlit": "if'kihim",
        "frequency": "30",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "151",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " أَلَا إِنَّهُمْ مِنْ إِفْكِهِمْ لَيَقُولُونَ",
        "rootWord": "أ ف ك",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "إِفْك",
        "waznEnglish": "lie, falsehood",
        "waznTlit": "if'k",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "تَأْكُلُونَ",
        "answer": "you eat",
        "pcklId": "79",
        "rootWordId": 54,
        "tlit": "takulūna",
        "frequency": "109",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "91",
        "wordnum": "6",
        "arabicAyah": " فَرَاغَ إِلَىٰ آلِهَتِهِمْ فَقَالَ أَلَا تَأْكُلُونَ",
        "rootWord": "أ ك ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَكَلَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to eat, to consume",
        "waznTlit": "akala",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "لَآكِلُونَ",
        "answer": "(will) surely eat",
        "pcklId": "106",
        "rootWordId": 54,
        "tlit": "laākilūna",
        "frequency": "109",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "66",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " فَإِنَّهُمْ لَآكِلُونَ مِنْهَا فَمَالِئُونَ مِنْهَا الْبُطُونَ",
        "rootWord": "أ ك ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ءَاكِلُون",
        "waznEnglish": "those who eat",
        "waznTlit": "ākilūn",
        "waznType": "Active participle"
    },
    {
        "question": "أَلْفٍ",
        "answer": "thousand",
        "pcklId": "16",
        "rootWordId": 56,
        "tlit": "alfin",
        "frequency": "22",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "147",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " وَأَرْسَلْنَاهُ إِلَىٰ مِائَةِ أَلْفٍ أَوْ يَزِيدُونَ",
        "rootWord": "أ ل ف",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَلْف",
        "waznEnglish": "thousand",
        "waznTlit": "alf",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "إِلَّا",
        "answer": "Except",
        "pcklId": "426",
        "rootWordId": 58,
        "tlit": "illā",
        "frequency": "663",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "10",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " إِلَّا مَنْ خَطِفَ الْخَطْفَةَ فَأَتْبَعَهُ شِهَابٌ ثَاقِبٌ",
        "rootWord": "إِلَّا",
        "rootWordType": "particle",
        "wazn": "إِلَّا",
        "waznEnglish": "except",
        "waznTlit": "illā",
        "waznType": "Particle (Restriction particle)"
    },
    {
        "question": "إِلَّا",
        "answer": "except",
        "pcklId": "427",
        "rootWordId": 58,
        "tlit": "illā",
        "frequency": "663",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "15",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " وَقَالُوا إِنْ هَٰذَا إِلَّا سِحْرٌ مُبِينٌ",
        "rootWord": "إِلَّا",
        "rootWordType": "particle",
        "wazn": "إِلَّا",
        "waznEnglish": "except",
        "waznTlit": "illā",
        "waznType": "Particle (Restriction particle)"
    },
    {
        "question": "إِلَّا",
        "answer": "except",
        "pcklId": "428",
        "rootWordId": 58,
        "tlit": "illā",
        "frequency": "663",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "35",
        "wordnum": "8",
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّهُمْ كَانُوا إِذَا قِيلَ لَهُمْ لَا إِلَٰهَ إِلَّا اللَّهُ يَسْتَكْبِرُونَ",
        "rootWord": "إِلَّا",
        "rootWordType": "particle",
        "wazn": "إِلَّا",
        "waznEnglish": "except",
        "waznTlit": "illā",
        "waznType": "Particle (Restriction particle)"
    },
    {
        "question": "إِلَّا",
        "answer": "except",
        "pcklId": "429",
        "rootWordId": 58,
        "tlit": "illā",
        "frequency": "663",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "39",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " وَمَا تُجْزَوْنَ إِلَّا مَا كُنْتُمْ تَعْمَلُونَ",
        "rootWord": "إِلَّا",
        "rootWordType": "particle",
        "wazn": "إِلَّا",
        "waznEnglish": "except",
        "waznTlit": "illā",
        "waznType": "Particle (Restriction particle)"
    },
    {
        "question": "إِلَّا",
        "answer": "Except",
        "pcklId": "430",
        "rootWordId": 58,
        "tlit": "illā",
        "frequency": "663",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "40",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " إِلَّا عِبَادَ اللَّهِ الْمُخْلَصِينَ",
        "rootWord": "إِلَّا",
        "rootWordType": "particle",
        "wazn": "إِلَّا",
        "waznEnglish": "except",
        "waznTlit": "illā",
        "waznType": "Particle (Restriction particle)"
    },
    {
        "question": "إِلَّا",
        "answer": "Except",
        "pcklId": "431",
        "rootWordId": 58,
        "tlit": "illā",
        "frequency": "663",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "59",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " إِلَّا مَوْتَتَنَا الْأُولَىٰ وَمَا نَحْنُ بِمُعَذَّبِينَ",
        "rootWord": "إِلَّا",
        "rootWordType": "particle",
        "wazn": "إِلَّا",
        "waznEnglish": "except",
        "waznTlit": "illā",
        "waznType": "Particle (Restriction particle)"
    },
    {
        "question": "إِلَّا",
        "answer": "Except",
        "pcklId": "432",
        "rootWordId": 58,
        "tlit": "illā",
        "frequency": "663",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "74",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " إِلَّا عِبَادَ اللَّهِ الْمُخْلَصِينَ",
        "rootWord": "إِلَّا",
        "rootWordType": "particle",
        "wazn": "إِلَّا",
        "waznEnglish": "except",
        "waznTlit": "illā",
        "waznType": "Particle (Restriction particle)"
    },
    {
        "question": "إِلَّا",
        "answer": "Except",
        "pcklId": "433",
        "rootWordId": 58,
        "tlit": "illā",
        "frequency": "663",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "128",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " إِلَّا عِبَادَ اللَّهِ الْمُخْلَصِينَ",
        "rootWord": "إِلَّا",
        "rootWordType": "particle",
        "wazn": "إِلَّا",
        "waznEnglish": "except",
        "waznTlit": "illā",
        "waznType": "Particle (Restriction particle)"
    },
    {
        "question": "إِلَّا",
        "answer": "Except",
        "pcklId": "434",
        "rootWordId": 58,
        "tlit": "illā",
        "frequency": "663",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "135",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " إِلَّا عَجُوزًا فِي الْغَابِرِينَ",
        "rootWord": "إِلَّا",
        "rootWordType": "particle",
        "wazn": "إِلَّا",
        "waznEnglish": "except",
        "waznTlit": "illā",
        "waznType": "Particle (Restriction particle)"
    },
    {
        "question": "إِلَّا",
        "answer": "Except",
        "pcklId": "435",
        "rootWordId": 58,
        "tlit": "illā",
        "frequency": "663",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "160",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " إِلَّا عِبَادَ اللَّهِ الْمُخْلَصِينَ",
        "rootWord": "إِلَّا",
        "rootWordType": "particle",
        "wazn": "إِلَّا",
        "waznEnglish": "except",
        "waznTlit": "illā",
        "waznType": "Particle (Restriction particle)"
    },
    {
        "question": "إِلَّا",
        "answer": "Except",
        "pcklId": "436",
        "rootWordId": 58,
        "tlit": "illā",
        "frequency": "663",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "163",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " إِلَّا مَنْ هُوَ صَالِ الْجَحِيمِ",
        "rootWord": "إِلَّا",
        "rootWordType": "particle",
        "wazn": "إِلَّا",
        "waznEnglish": "except",
        "waznTlit": "illā",
        "waznType": "Particle (Restriction particle)"
    },
    {
        "question": "إِلَّا",
        "answer": "except",
        "pcklId": "437",
        "rootWordId": 58,
        "tlit": "illā",
        "frequency": "663",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "164",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " وَمَا مِنَّا إِلَّا لَهُ مَقَامٌ مَعْلُومٌ",
        "rootWord": "إِلَّا",
        "rootWordType": "particle",
        "wazn": "إِلَّا",
        "waznEnglish": "except",
        "waznTlit": "illā",
        "waznType": "Particle (Restriction particle)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الَّذِي",
        "answer": "which",
        "pcklId": "1048",
        "rootWordId": 59,
        "tlit": "alladhī",
        "frequency": "1464",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "21",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " هَٰذَا يَوْمُ الْفَصْلِ الَّذِي كُنْتُمْ بِهِ تُكَذِّبُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ٱلَّذِى",
        "rootWordType": "nominal",
        "wazn": "ٱلَّذِى",
        "waznEnglish": "who, which, that",
        "waznTlit": "alladhī",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Relative pronoun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الَّذِينَ",
        "answer": "those who",
        "pcklId": "1049",
        "rootWordId": 59,
        "tlit": "alladhīna",
        "frequency": "1464",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "22",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " احْشُرُوا الَّذِينَ ظَلَمُوا وَأَزْوَاجَهُمْ وَمَا كَانُوا يَعْبُدُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ٱلَّذِى",
        "rootWordType": "nominal",
        "wazn": "ٱلَّذِى",
        "waznEnglish": "who, which, that",
        "waznTlit": "alladhī",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Relative pronoun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْأَلِيمِ",
        "answer": "painful",
        "pcklId": "52",
        "rootWordId": 60,
        "tlit": "l-alīmi",
        "frequency": "75",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "38",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّكُمْ لَذَائِقُو الْعَذَابِ الْأَلِيمِ",
        "rootWord": "أ ل م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَلِيم",
        "waznEnglish": "painful",
        "waznTlit": "alīm",
        "waznType": "Adjective"
    },
    {
        "question": "إِلَٰهَكُمْ",
        "answer": "your Lord",
        "pcklId": "113",
        "rootWordId": 61,
        "tlit": "ilāhakum",
        "frequency": "2851",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "4",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّ إِلَٰهَكُمْ لَوَاحِدٌ",
        "rootWord": "أ ل ه",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "إِلَٰه",
        "waznEnglish": "god",
        "waznTlit": "ilāh",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "إِلَٰهَ",
        "answer": "god",
        "pcklId": "114",
        "rootWordId": 61,
        "tlit": "ilāha",
        "frequency": "2851",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "35",
        "wordnum": "7",
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّهُمْ كَانُوا إِذَا قِيلَ لَهُمْ لَا إِلَٰهَ إِلَّا اللَّهُ يَسْتَكْبِرُونَ",
        "rootWord": "أ ل ه",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "إِلَٰه",
        "waznEnglish": "god",
        "waznTlit": "ilāh",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "آلِهَتِنَا",
        "answer": "our gods",
        "pcklId": "115",
        "rootWordId": 61,
        "tlit": "ālihatinā",
        "frequency": "2851",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "36",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " وَيَقُولُونَ أَئِنَّا لَتَارِكُو آلِهَتِنَا لِشَاعِرٍ مَجْنُونٍ",
        "rootWord": "أ ل ه",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "إِلَٰه",
        "waznEnglish": "god",
        "waznTlit": "ilāh",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "آلِهَةً",
        "answer": "gods",
        "pcklId": "116",
        "rootWordId": 61,
        "tlit": "ālihatan",
        "frequency": "2851",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "86",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " أَئِفْكًا آلِهَةً دُونَ اللَّهِ تُرِيدُونَ",
        "rootWord": "أ ل ه",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "إِلَٰه",
        "waznEnglish": "god",
        "waznTlit": "ilāh",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "آلِهَتِهِمْ",
        "answer": "their gods",
        "pcklId": "117",
        "rootWordId": 61,
        "tlit": "ālihatihim",
        "frequency": "2851",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "91",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " فَرَاغَ إِلَىٰ آلِهَتِهِمْ فَقَالَ أَلَا تَأْكُلُونَ",
        "rootWord": "أ ل ه",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "إِلَٰه",
        "waznEnglish": "god",
        "waznTlit": "ilāh",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "اللَّهِ",
        "answer": "Allah",
        "pcklId": "2246",
        "rootWordId": 61,
        "tlit": "l-lahi",
        "frequency": "2851",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "23",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " مِنْ دُونِ اللَّهِ فَاهْدُوهُمْ إِلَىٰ صِرَاطِ الْجَحِيمِ",
        "rootWord": "أ ل ه",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ٱللَّه",
        "waznEnglish": "Allah",
        "waznTlit": "allah",
        "waznType": "Proper noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "اللَّهُ",
        "answer": "Allah",
        "pcklId": "2247",
        "rootWordId": 61,
        "tlit": "l-lahu",
        "frequency": "2851",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "35",
        "wordnum": "9",
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّهُمْ كَانُوا إِذَا قِيلَ لَهُمْ لَا إِلَٰهَ إِلَّا اللَّهُ يَسْتَكْبِرُونَ",
        "rootWord": "أ ل ه",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ٱللَّه",
        "waznEnglish": "Allah",
        "waznTlit": "allah",
        "waznType": "Proper noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "اللَّهِ",
        "answer": "(of) Allah",
        "pcklId": "2248",
        "rootWordId": 61,
        "tlit": "l-lahi",
        "frequency": "2851",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "40",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " إِلَّا عِبَادَ اللَّهِ الْمُخْلَصِينَ",
        "rootWord": "أ ل ه",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ٱللَّه",
        "waznEnglish": "Allah",
        "waznTlit": "allah",
        "waznType": "Proper noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "تَاللَّهِ",
        "answer": "By Allah",
        "pcklId": "2249",
        "rootWordId": 61,
        "tlit": "tal-lahi",
        "frequency": "2851",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "56",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " قَالَ تَاللَّهِ إِنْ كِدْتَ لَتُرْدِينِ",
        "rootWord": "أ ل ه",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ٱللَّه",
        "waznEnglish": "Allah",
        "waznTlit": "allah",
        "waznType": "Proper noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "اللَّهِ",
        "answer": "(of) Allah",
        "pcklId": "2250",
        "rootWordId": 61,
        "tlit": "l-lahi",
        "frequency": "2851",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "74",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " إِلَّا عِبَادَ اللَّهِ الْمُخْلَصِينَ",
        "rootWord": "أ ل ه",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ٱللَّه",
        "waznEnglish": "Allah",
        "waznTlit": "allah",
        "waznType": "Proper noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "اللَّهِ",
        "answer": "Allah ",
        "pcklId": "2251",
        "rootWordId": 61,
        "tlit": "l-lahi",
        "frequency": "2851",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "86",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " أَئِفْكًا آلِهَةً دُونَ اللَّهِ تُرِيدُونَ",
        "rootWord": "أ ل ه",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ٱللَّه",
        "waznEnglish": "Allah",
        "waznTlit": "allah",
        "waznType": "Proper noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَاللَّهُ",
        "answer": "While Allah",
        "pcklId": "2252",
        "rootWordId": 61,
        "tlit": "wal-lahu",
        "frequency": "2851",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "96",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " وَاللَّهُ خَلَقَكُمْ وَمَا تَعْمَلُونَ",
        "rootWord": "أ ل ه",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ٱللَّه",
        "waznEnglish": "Allah",
        "waznTlit": "allah",
        "waznType": "Proper noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "اللَّهُ",
        "answer": "Allah wills",
        "pcklId": "2253",
        "rootWordId": 61,
        "tlit": "l-lahu",
        "frequency": "2851",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "102",
        "wordnum": "24",
        "arabicAyah": " افْعَلْ مَا تُؤْمَرُ سَتَجِدُنِي إِنْ شَاءَ اللَّهُ مِنَ الصَّابِرِينَ",
        "rootWord": "أ ل ه",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ٱللَّه",
        "waznEnglish": "Allah",
        "waznTlit": "allah",
        "waznType": "Proper noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "اللَّهَ",
        "answer": "Allah",
        "pcklId": "2254",
        "rootWordId": 61,
        "tlit": "al-laha",
        "frequency": "2851",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "126",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " اللَّهَ رَبَّكُمْ وَرَبَّ آبَائِكُمُ الْأَوَّلِينَ",
        "rootWord": "أ ل ه",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ٱللَّه",
        "waznEnglish": "Allah",
        "waznTlit": "allah",
        "waznType": "Proper noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "اللَّهِ",
        "answer": "(of) Allah",
        "pcklId": "2255",
        "rootWordId": 61,
        "tlit": "l-lahi",
        "frequency": "2851",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "128",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " إِلَّا عِبَادَ اللَّهِ الْمُخْلَصِينَ",
        "rootWord": "أ ل ه",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ٱللَّه",
        "waznEnglish": "Allah",
        "waznTlit": "allah",
        "waznType": "Proper noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "اللَّهُ",
        "answer": "Allah has begotten",
        "pcklId": "2256",
        "rootWordId": 61,
        "tlit": "l-lahu",
        "frequency": "2851",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "152",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " وَلَدَ اللَّهُ وَإِنَّهُمْ لَكَاذِبُونَ",
        "rootWord": "أ ل ه",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ٱللَّه",
        "waznEnglish": "Allah",
        "waznTlit": "allah",
        "waznType": "Proper noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "اللَّهِ",
        "answer": "(to) Allah",
        "pcklId": "2257",
        "rootWordId": 61,
        "tlit": "l-lahi",
        "frequency": "2851",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "159",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " سُبْحَانَ اللَّهِ عَمَّا يَصِفُونَ",
        "rootWord": "أ ل ه",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ٱللَّه",
        "waznEnglish": "Allah",
        "waznTlit": "allah",
        "waznType": "Proper noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "اللَّهِ",
        "answer": "(of) Allah",
        "pcklId": "2258",
        "rootWordId": 61,
        "tlit": "l-lahi",
        "frequency": "2851",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "160",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " إِلَّا عِبَادَ اللَّهِ الْمُخْلَصِينَ",
        "rootWord": "أ ل ه",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ٱللَّه",
        "waznEnglish": "Allah",
        "waznTlit": "allah",
        "waznType": "Proper noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "اللَّهِ",
        "answer": "(of) Allah",
        "pcklId": "2259",
        "rootWordId": 61,
        "tlit": "l-lahi",
        "frequency": "2851",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "169",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " لَكُنَّا عِبَادَ اللَّهِ الْمُخْلَصِينَ",
        "rootWord": "أ ل ه",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ٱللَّه",
        "waznEnglish": "Allah",
        "waznTlit": "allah",
        "waznType": "Proper noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "لِلَّهِ",
        "answer": "(be) to Allah",
        "pcklId": "2260",
        "rootWordId": 61,
        "tlit": "lillahi",
        "frequency": "2851",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "182",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " وَالْحَمْدُ لِلَّهِ رَبِّ الْعَالَمِينَ",
        "rootWord": "أ ل ه",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ٱللَّه",
        "waznEnglish": "Allah",
        "waznTlit": "allah",
        "waznType": "Proper noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "إِلَى",
        "answer": "to",
        "pcklId": "554",
        "rootWordId": 63,
        "tlit": "ilā",
        "frequency": "742",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "8",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " لَا يَسَّمَّعُونَ إِلَى الْمَلَإِ الْأَعْلَىٰ وَيُقْذَفُونَ مِنْ كُلِّ جَانِبٍ",
        "rootWord": "إِلَىٰ",
        "rootWordType": "preposition",
        "wazn": "إِلَىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "to, toward, until",
        "waznTlit": "ilā",
        "waznType": "Preposition"
    },
    {
        "question": "إِلَىٰ",
        "answer": "to",
        "pcklId": "555",
        "rootWordId": 63,
        "tlit": "ilā",
        "frequency": "742",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "23",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " فَاهْدُوهُمْ إِلَىٰ صِرَاطِ الْجَحِيمِ",
        "rootWord": "إِلَىٰ",
        "rootWordType": "preposition",
        "wazn": "إِلَىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "to, toward, until",
        "waznTlit": "ilā",
        "waznType": "Preposition"
    },
    {
        "question": "لَإِلَى",
        "answer": "(will) surely be to",
        "pcklId": "556",
        "rootWordId": 63,
        "tlit": "la-ilā",
        "frequency": "742",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "68",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " ثُمَّ إِنَّ مَرْجِعَهُمْ لَإِلَى الْجَحِيمِ",
        "rootWord": "إِلَىٰ",
        "rootWordType": "preposition",
        "wazn": "إِلَىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "to, toward, until",
        "waznTlit": "ilā",
        "waznType": "Preposition"
    },
    {
        "question": "إِلَىٰ",
        "answer": "to",
        "pcklId": "557",
        "rootWordId": 63,
        "tlit": "ilā",
        "frequency": "742",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "91",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " فَرَاغَ إِلَىٰ آلِهَتِهِمْ فَقَالَ أَلَا تَأْكُلُونَ",
        "rootWord": "إِلَىٰ",
        "rootWordType": "preposition",
        "wazn": "إِلَىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "to, toward, until",
        "waznTlit": "ilā",
        "waznType": "Preposition"
    },
    {
        "question": "إِلَيْهِ",
        "answer": "towards him",
        "pcklId": "558",
        "rootWordId": 63,
        "tlit": "ilayhi",
        "frequency": "742",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "94",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " فَأَقْبَلُوا إِلَيْهِ يَزِفُّونَ",
        "rootWord": "إِلَىٰ",
        "rootWordType": "preposition",
        "wazn": "إِلَىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "to, toward, until",
        "waznTlit": "ilā",
        "waznType": "Preposition"
    },
    {
        "question": "إِلَىٰ",
        "answer": "to",
        "pcklId": "559",
        "rootWordId": 63,
        "tlit": "ilā",
        "frequency": "742",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "99",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " وَقَالَ إِنِّي ذَاهِبٌ إِلَىٰ رَبِّي سَيَهْدِينِ",
        "rootWord": "إِلَىٰ",
        "rootWordType": "preposition",
        "wazn": "إِلَىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "to, toward, until",
        "waznTlit": "ilā",
        "waznType": "Preposition"
    },
    {
        "question": "إِلَى",
        "answer": "to",
        "pcklId": "560",
        "rootWordId": 63,
        "tlit": "ilā",
        "frequency": "742",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "140",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " إِذْ أَبَقَ إِلَى الْفُلْكِ الْمَشْحُونِ",
        "rootWord": "إِلَىٰ",
        "rootWordType": "preposition",
        "wazn": "إِلَىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "to, toward, until",
        "waznTlit": "ilā",
        "waznType": "Preposition"
    },
    {
        "question": "إِلَىٰ",
        "answer": "until",
        "pcklId": "561",
        "rootWordId": 63,
        "tlit": "ilā",
        "frequency": "742",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "144",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " لَلَبِثَ فِي بَطْنِهِ إِلَىٰ يَوْمِ يُبْعَثُونَ",
        "rootWord": "إِلَىٰ",
        "rootWordType": "preposition",
        "wazn": "إِلَىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "to, toward, until",
        "waznTlit": "ilā",
        "waznType": "Preposition"
    },
    {
        "question": "إِلَىٰ",
        "answer": "to",
        "pcklId": "562",
        "rootWordId": 63,
        "tlit": "ilā",
        "frequency": "742",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "147",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " وَأَرْسَلْنَاهُ إِلَىٰ مِائَةِ أَلْفٍ أَوْ يَزِيدُونَ",
        "rootWord": "إِلَىٰ",
        "rootWordType": "preposition",
        "wazn": "إِلَىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "to, toward, until",
        "waznTlit": "ilā",
        "waznType": "Preposition"
    },
    {
        "question": "إِلَىٰ",
        "answer": "for",
        "pcklId": "563",
        "rootWordId": 63,
        "tlit": "ilā",
        "frequency": "742",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "148",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " فَآمَنُوا فَمَتَّعْنَاهُمْ إِلَىٰ حِينٍ",
        "rootWord": "إِلَىٰ",
        "rootWordType": "preposition",
        "wazn": "إِلَىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "to, toward, until",
        "waznTlit": "ilā",
        "waznType": "Preposition"
    },
    {
        "question": "إِلْيَاسَ",
        "answer": "Elijah",
        "pcklId": "1",
        "rootWordId": 64,
        "tlit": "il'yāsa",
        "frequency": "3",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "123",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " وَإِنَّ إِلْيَاسَ لَمِنَ الْمُرْسَلِينَ",
        "rootWord": "إِلْيَاس",
        "rootWordType": "proper noun",
        "wazn": "إِلْيَاس",
        "waznEnglish": "Elijah",
        "waznTlit": "il'yās",
        "waznType": "Proper noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "إِلْ يَاسِينَ",
        "answer": "Elijah",
        "pcklId": "2",
        "rootWordId": 64,
        "tlit": "il yāsīna",
        "frequency": "3",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "130",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " سَلَامٌ عَلَىٰ إِلْ يَاسِينَ",
        "rootWord": "إِلْيَاس",
        "rootWordType": "proper noun",
        "wazn": "إِلْيَاس",
        "waznEnglish": "Elijah",
        "waznTlit": "il'yās",
        "waznType": "Proper noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "أَمْ",
        "answer": "or",
        "pcklId": "72",
        "rootWordId": 66,
        "tlit": "am",
        "frequency": "137",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "11",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " فَاسْتَفْتِهِمْ أَهُمْ أَشَدُّ خَلْقًا أَمْ مَنْ خَلَقْنَا",
        "rootWord": "أَم",
        "rootWordType": "coordinating conjunction",
        "wazn": "أَم",
        "waznEnglish": "or",
        "waznTlit": "am",
        "waznType": "Coordinating conjunction"
    },
    {
        "question": "أَمْ",
        "answer": "or",
        "pcklId": "73",
        "rootWordId": 66,
        "tlit": "am",
        "frequency": "137",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "62",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " أَذَٰلِكَ خَيْرٌ نُزُلًا أَمْ شَجَرَةُ الزَّقُّومِ",
        "rootWord": "أَم",
        "rootWordType": "coordinating conjunction",
        "wazn": "أَم",
        "waznEnglish": "or",
        "waznTlit": "am",
        "waznType": "Coordinating conjunction"
    },
    {
        "question": "أَمْ",
        "answer": "Or",
        "pcklId": "74",
        "rootWordId": 66,
        "tlit": "am",
        "frequency": "137",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "150",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " أَمْ خَلَقْنَا الْمَلَائِكَةَ إِنَاثًا وَهُمْ شَاهِدُونَ",
        "rootWord": "أَم",
        "rootWordType": "coordinating conjunction",
        "wazn": "أَم",
        "waznEnglish": "or",
        "waznTlit": "am",
        "waznType": "Coordinating conjunction"
    },
    {
        "question": "أَمْ",
        "answer": "Or",
        "pcklId": "75",
        "rootWordId": 66,
        "tlit": "am",
        "frequency": "137",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "156",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " أَمْ لَكُمْ سُلْطَانٌ مُبِينٌ",
        "rootWord": "أَم",
        "rootWordType": "coordinating conjunction",
        "wazn": "أَم",
        "waznEnglish": "or",
        "waznTlit": "am",
        "waznType": "Coordinating conjunction"
    },
    {
        "question": "تُؤْمَرُ",
        "answer": "you are commanded",
        "pcklId": "63",
        "rootWordId": 69,
        "tlit": "tu'maru",
        "frequency": "248",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "102",
        "wordnum": "20",
        "arabicAyah": " قَالَ يَا أَبَتِ افْعَلْ مَا تُؤْمَرُ سَتَجِدُنِي إِنْ شَاءَ اللَّهُ مِنَ الصَّابِرِينَ",
        "rootWord": "أ م ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَمَرَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to order, to command",
        "waznTlit": "amara",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "فَآمَنُوا",
        "answer": "And they believed",
        "pcklId": "428",
        "rootWordId": 75,
        "tlit": "faāmanū",
        "frequency": "879",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "148",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " فَآمَنُوا فَمَتَّعْنَاهُمْ إِلَىٰ حِينٍ",
        "rootWord": "أ م ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ءَامَنَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to believe",
        "waznTlit": "āmana",
        "waznType": "Verb (form IV)"
    },
    {
        "question": "مُؤْمِنِينَ",
        "answer": "believers",
        "pcklId": "810",
        "rootWordId": 75,
        "tlit": "mu'minīna",
        "frequency": "879",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "29",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " قَالُوا بَلْ لَمْ تَكُونُوا مُؤْمِنِينَ",
        "rootWord": "أ م ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مُؤْمِن",
        "waznEnglish": "you are secure",
        "waznTlit": "mu'min",
        "waznType": "Active participle (form IV) (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْمُؤْمِنِينَ",
        "answer": "believing",
        "pcklId": "811",
        "rootWordId": 75,
        "tlit": "l-mu'minīna",
        "frequency": "879",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "111",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّهُ مِنْ عِبَادِنَا الْمُؤْمِنِينَ",
        "rootWord": "أ م ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مُؤْمِن",
        "waznEnglish": "you are secure",
        "waznTlit": "mu'min",
        "waznType": "Active participle (form IV) (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْمُؤْمِنِينَ",
        "answer": "believing",
        "pcklId": "847",
        "rootWordId": 75,
        "tlit": "l-mu'minīna",
        "frequency": "879",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "81",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّهُ مِنْ عِبَادِنَا الْمُؤْمِنِينَ",
        "rootWord": "أ م ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مُؤْمِن",
        "waznEnglish": "you are secure",
        "waznTlit": "mu'min",
        "waznType": "Active participle (form IV) (Adjective)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْمُؤْمِنِينَ",
        "answer": "believing",
        "pcklId": "848",
        "rootWordId": 75,
        "tlit": "l-mu'minīna",
        "frequency": "879",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "122",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّهُمَا مِنْ عِبَادِنَا الْمُؤْمِنِينَ",
        "rootWord": "أ م ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مُؤْمِن",
        "waznEnglish": "you are secure",
        "waznTlit": "mu'min",
        "waznType": "Active participle (form IV) (Adjective)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْمُؤْمِنِينَ",
        "answer": "believing",
        "pcklId": "849",
        "rootWordId": 75,
        "tlit": "l-mu'minīna",
        "frequency": "879",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "132",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّهُ مِنْ عِبَادِنَا الْمُؤْمِنِينَ",
        "rootWord": "أ م ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مُؤْمِن",
        "waznEnglish": "you are secure",
        "waznTlit": "mu'min",
        "waznType": "Active participle (form IV) (Adjective)"
    },
    {
        "question": "إِنَاثًا",
        "answer": "females",
        "pcklId": "12",
        "rootWordId": 77,
        "tlit": "ināthan",
        "frequency": "30",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "150",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " أَمْ خَلَقْنَا الْمَلَائِكَةَ إِنَاثًا وَهُمْ شَاهِدُونَ",
        "rootWord": "أ ن ث",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أُنثَىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "and the female",
        "waznTlit": "unthā",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَأَهْلَهُ",
        "answer": "and his family",
        "pcklId": "103",
        "rootWordId": 82,
        "tlit": "wa-ahlahu",
        "frequency": "127",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "76",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " وَنَجَّيْنَاهُ وَأَهْلَهُ مِنَ الْكَرْبِ الْعَظِيمِ",
        "rootWord": "أ ه ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أ ه ل",
        "waznEnglish": "(the) People",
        "waznTlit": "hamza hā lām",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَأَهْلَهُ",
        "answer": "and his family",
        "pcklId": "104",
        "rootWordId": 82,
        "tlit": "wa-ahlahu",
        "frequency": "127",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "134",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " إِذْ نَجَّيْنَاهُ وَأَهْلَهُ أَجْمَعِينَ",
        "rootWord": "أ ه ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أ ه ل",
        "waznEnglish": "(the) People",
        "waznTlit": "hamza hā lām",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْأُولَىٰ",
        "answer": "the first",
        "pcklId": "35",
        "rootWordId": 85,
        "tlit": "l-ūlā",
        "frequency": "170",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "59",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " إِلَّا مَوْتَتَنَا الْأُولَىٰ وَمَا نَحْنُ بِمُعَذَّبِينَ",
        "rootWord": "أ و ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَوَّل",
        "waznEnglish": "(the) first",
        "waznTlit": "awwal",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْأَوَّلِينَ",
        "answer": "the former (people)",
        "pcklId": "36",
        "rootWordId": 85,
        "tlit": "l-awalīna",
        "frequency": "170",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "168",
        "wordnum": "6",
        "arabicAyah": " لَوْ أَنَّ عِنْدَنَا ذِكْرًا مِنَ الْأَوَّلِينَ",
        "rootWord": "أ و ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَوَّل",
        "waznEnglish": "(the) first",
        "waznTlit": "awwal",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْأَوَّلُونَ",
        "answer": "former",
        "pcklId": "73",
        "rootWordId": 85,
        "tlit": "l-awalūna",
        "frequency": "170",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "17",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " أَوَآبَاؤُنَا الْأَوَّلُونَ",
        "rootWord": "أ و ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَوَّل",
        "waznEnglish": "(the) first",
        "waznTlit": "awwal",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Adjective)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْأَوَّلِينَ",
        "answer": "(of) the former (people)",
        "pcklId": "74",
        "rootWordId": 85,
        "tlit": "l-awalīna",
        "frequency": "170",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "71",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " وَلَقَدْ ضَلَّ قَبْلَهُمْ أَكْثَرُ الْأَوَّلِينَ",
        "rootWord": "أ و ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَوَّل",
        "waznEnglish": "(the) first",
        "waznTlit": "awwal",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Adjective)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْأَوَّلِينَ",
        "answer": "(of) your forefathers",
        "pcklId": "75",
        "rootWordId": 85,
        "tlit": "l-awalīna",
        "frequency": "170",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "126",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " اللَّهَ رَبَّكُمْ وَرَبَّ آبَائِكُمُ الْأَوَّلِينَ",
        "rootWord": "أ و ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَوَّل",
        "waznEnglish": "(the) first",
        "waznTlit": "awwal",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Adjective)"
    },
    {
        "question": "آيَةً",
        "answer": "a Sign",
        "pcklId": "312",
        "rootWordId": 90,
        "tlit": "āyatan",
        "frequency": "382",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "14",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " وَإِذَا رَأَوْا آيَةً يَسْتَسْخِرُونَ",
        "rootWord": "أ ي ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أ ي ي",
        "waznEnglish": "Our Signs",
        "waznTlit": "hamza yā yā",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَبَارَكْنَا",
        "answer": "And We blessed",
        "pcklId": "6",
        "rootWordId": 118,
        "tlit": "wabāraknā",
        "frequency": "32",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "113",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " وَبَارَكْنَا عَلَيْهِ وَعَلَىٰ إِسْحَاقَ وَمِنْ ذُرِّيَّتِهِمَا مُحْسِنٌ وَظَالِمٌ لِنَفْسِهِ مُبِينٌ",
        "rootWord": "ب ر ك",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "بَٰرَكَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to bless",
        "waznTlit": "bāraka",
        "waznType": "Verb (form III)"
    },
    {
        "question": "فَبَشَّرْنَاهُ",
        "answer": "So We gave him the glad tidings",
        "pcklId": "29",
        "rootWordId": 128,
        "tlit": "fabasharnāhu",
        "frequency": "123",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "101",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " فَبَشَّرْنَاهُ بِغُلَامٍ حَلِيمٍ",
        "rootWord": "ب ش ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "بُشِّرَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to give glad tidings",
        "waznTlit": "bushira",
        "waznType": "Verb (form II)"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَبَشَّرْنَاهُ",
        "answer": "And We gave him glad tidings",
        "pcklId": "30",
        "rootWordId": 128,
        "tlit": "wabasharnāhu",
        "frequency": "123",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "112",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " وَبَشَّرْنَاهُ بِإِسْحَاقَ نَبِيًّا مِنَ الصَّالِحِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ب ش ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "بُشِّرَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to give glad tidings",
        "waznTlit": "bushira",
        "waznType": "Verb (form II)"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَأَبْصِرْهُمْ",
        "answer": "And see them",
        "pcklId": "21",
        "rootWordId": 129,
        "tlit": "wa-abṣir'hum",
        "frequency": "148",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "175",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " وَأَبْصِرْهُمْ فَسَوْفَ يُبْصِرُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ب ص ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَبْصَرَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to see",
        "waznTlit": "abṣara",
        "waznType": "Verb (form IV)"
    },
    {
        "question": "يُبْصِرُونَ",
        "answer": "they will see",
        "pcklId": "22",
        "rootWordId": 129,
        "tlit": "yub'ṣirūna",
        "frequency": "148",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "175",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " وَأَبْصِرْهُمْ فَسَوْفَ يُبْصِرُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ب ص ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَبْصَرَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to see",
        "waznTlit": "abṣara",
        "waznType": "Verb (form IV)"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَأَبْصِرْ",
        "answer": "And see",
        "pcklId": "23",
        "rootWordId": 129,
        "tlit": "wa-abṣir",
        "frequency": "148",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "179",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " وَأَبْصِرْ فَسَوْفَ يُبْصِرُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ب ص ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَبْصَرَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to see",
        "waznTlit": "abṣara",
        "waznType": "Verb (form IV)"
    },
    {
        "question": "يُبْصِرُونَ",
        "answer": "they will see",
        "pcklId": "24",
        "rootWordId": 129,
        "tlit": "yub'ṣirūna",
        "frequency": "148",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "179",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " وَأَبْصِرْ فَسَوْفَ يُبْصِرُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ب ص ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَبْصَرَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to see",
        "waznTlit": "abṣara",
        "waznType": "Verb (form IV)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْبُطُونَ",
        "answer": "(their) bellies",
        "pcklId": "14",
        "rootWordId": 136,
        "tlit": "l-buṭūna",
        "frequency": "25",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "66",
        "wordnum": "6",
        "arabicAyah": " فَإِنَّهُمْ لَآكِلُونَ مِنْهَا فَمَالِئُونَ مِنْهَا الْبُطُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ب ط ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "بَطْن",
        "waznEnglish": "(is) concealed",
        "waznTlit": "baṭn",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "بَطْنِهِ",
        "answer": "its belly",
        "pcklId": "15",
        "rootWordId": 136,
        "tlit": "baṭnihi",
        "frequency": "25",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "144",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " لَلَبِثَ فِي بَطْنِهِ إِلَىٰ يَوْمِ يُبْعَثُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ب ط ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "بَطْن",
        "waznEnglish": "(is) concealed",
        "waznTlit": "baṭn",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "يُبْعَثُونَ",
        "answer": "they are resurrected",
        "pcklId": "43",
        "rootWordId": 137,
        "tlit": "yub'ʿathūna",
        "frequency": "67",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "144",
        "wordnum": "6",
        "arabicAyah": " لَلَبِثَ فِي بَطْنِهِ إِلَىٰ يَوْمِ يُبْعَثُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ب ع ث",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "بَعَثَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to raise, to resurrect, to send",
        "waznTlit": "baʿatha",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "لَمَبْعُوثُونَ",
        "answer": "be certainly resurrected",
        "pcklId": "63",
        "rootWordId": 137,
        "tlit": "lamabʿūthūna",
        "frequency": "67",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "16",
        "wordnum": "7",
        "arabicAyah": " أَإِذَا مِتْنَا وَكُنَّا تُرَابًا وَعِظَامًا أَإِنَّا لَمَبْعُوثُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ب ع ث",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مَّبْعُوثُون",
        "waznEnglish": "We revived you",
        "waznTlit": "mabʿūthūn",
        "waznType": "Passive participle"
    },
    {
        "question": "بَعْضُهُمْ",
        "answer": "some of them",
        "pcklId": "122",
        "rootWordId": 141,
        "tlit": "baʿḍuhum",
        "frequency": "158",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "27",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " وَأَقْبَلَ بَعْضُهُمْ عَلَىٰ بَعْضٍ يَتَسَاءَلُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ب ع ض",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "بَعْض",
        "waznEnglish": "some of you",
        "waznTlit": "baʿḍ",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "بَعْضٍ",
        "answer": "others",
        "pcklId": "123",
        "rootWordId": 141,
        "tlit": "baʿḍin",
        "frequency": "158",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "27",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " وَأَقْبَلَ بَعْضُهُمْ عَلَىٰ بَعْضٍ يَتَسَاءَلُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ب ع ض",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "بَعْض",
        "waznEnglish": "some of you",
        "waznTlit": "baʿḍ",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "بَعْضُهُمْ",
        "answer": "some of them",
        "pcklId": "124",
        "rootWordId": 141,
        "tlit": "baʿḍuhum",
        "frequency": "158",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "50",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " فَأَقْبَلَ بَعْضُهُمْ عَلَىٰ بَعْضٍ يَتَسَاءَلُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ب ع ض",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "بَعْض",
        "waznEnglish": "some of you",
        "waznTlit": "baʿḍ",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "بَعْضٍ",
        "answer": "others",
        "pcklId": "125",
        "rootWordId": 141,
        "tlit": "baʿḍin",
        "frequency": "158",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "50",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " فَأَقْبَلَ بَعْضُهُمْ عَلَىٰ بَعْضٍ يَتَسَاءَلُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ب ع ض",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "بَعْض",
        "waznEnglish": "some of you",
        "waznTlit": "baʿḍ",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "بَعْلًا",
        "answer": "Baal",
        "pcklId": "6",
        "rootWordId": 142,
        "tlit": "baʿlan",
        "frequency": "7",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "125",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " أَتَدْعُونَ بَعْلًا وَتَذَرُونَ أَحْسَنَ الْخَالِقِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ب ع ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "بَعْل",
        "waznEnglish": "And their husbands",
        "waznTlit": "baʿl",
        "waznType": "Proper noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْبَاقِينَ",
        "answer": "the survivors",
        "pcklId": "18",
        "rootWordId": 150,
        "tlit": "l-bāqīna",
        "frequency": "21",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "77",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " وَجَعَلْنَا ذُرِّيَّتَهُ هُمُ الْبَاقِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ب ق ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "بَاقِين",
        "waznEnglish": "remained",
        "waznTlit": "bāqīn",
        "waznType": "Active participle"
    },
    {
        "question": "بَلَغَ",
        "answer": "he reached",
        "pcklId": "29",
        "rootWordId": 157,
        "tlit": "balagha",
        "frequency": "77",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "102",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " فَلَمَّا بَلَغَ مَعَهُ السَّعْيَ قَالَ يَا بُنَيَّ إِنِّي أَرَىٰ فِي الْمَنَامِ أَنِّي أَذْبَحُكَ",
        "rootWord": "ب ل غ",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "بَلَغَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to reach",
        "waznTlit": "balagha",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْبَلَاءُ",
        "answer": "the trial",
        "pcklId": "34",
        "rootWordId": 158,
        "tlit": "l-balāu",
        "frequency": "38",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "106",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّ هَٰذَا لَهُوَ الْبَلَاءُ الْمُبِينُ",
        "rootWord": "ب ل و",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "بَلَآء",
        "waznEnglish": "And surely We will test you",
        "waznTlit": "balā",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "ابْنُوا",
        "answer": "Build",
        "pcklId": "3",
        "rootWordId": 160,
        "tlit": "ib'nū",
        "frequency": "184",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "97",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " قَالُوا ابْنُوا لَهُ بُنْيَانًا فَأَلْقُوهُ فِي الْجَحِيمِ",
        "rootWord": "ب ن ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "بَنَىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "to construct, to build",
        "waznTlit": "banā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْبَنَاتُ",
        "answer": "(have) daughters",
        "pcklId": "92",
        "rootWordId": 160,
        "tlit": "l-banātu",
        "frequency": "184",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "149",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " فَاسْتَفْتِهِمْ أَلِرَبِّكَ الْبَنَاتُ وَلَهُمُ الْبَنُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ب ن ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "بَنَات",
        "waznEnglish": "they built",
        "waznTlit": "banāt",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْبَنَاتِ",
        "answer": "[the] daughters",
        "pcklId": "93",
        "rootWordId": 160,
        "tlit": "l-banāti",
        "frequency": "184",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "153",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " أَصْطَفَى الْبَنَاتِ عَلَى الْبَنِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ب ن ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "بَنَات",
        "waznEnglish": "they built",
        "waznTlit": "banāt",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "يَا بُنَيَّ",
        "answer": "O my son",
        "pcklId": "159",
        "rootWordId": 160,
        "tlit": "yābunayya",
        "frequency": "184",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "102",
        "wordnum": "6",
        "arabicAyah": " يَا بُنَيَّ إِنِّي أَرَىٰ فِي الْمَنَامِ أَنِّي أَذْبَحُكَ فَانْظُرْ مَاذَا تَرَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ب ن ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "بُنَىّ",
        "waznEnglish": "they built",
        "waznTlit": "buna",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْبَنُونَ",
        "answer": "(are) sons",
        "pcklId": "160",
        "rootWordId": 160,
        "tlit": "l-banūna",
        "frequency": "184",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "149",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " فَاسْتَفْتِهِمْ أَلِرَبِّكَ الْبَنَاتُ وَلَهُمُ الْبَنُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ب ن ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "بُنَىّ",
        "waznEnglish": "they built",
        "waznTlit": "buna",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْبَنِينَ",
        "answer": "sons",
        "pcklId": "161",
        "rootWordId": 160,
        "tlit": "l-banīna",
        "frequency": "184",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "153",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " أَصْطَفَى الْبَنَاتِ عَلَى الْبَنِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ب ن ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "بُنَىّ",
        "waznEnglish": "they built",
        "waznTlit": "buna",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "بُنْيَانًا",
        "answer": "a structure",
        "pcklId": "181",
        "rootWordId": 160,
        "tlit": "bun'yānan",
        "frequency": "184",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "97",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " قَالُوا ابْنُوا لَهُ بُنْيَانًا فَأَلْقُوهُ فِي الْجَحِيمِ",
        "rootWord": "ب ن ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "بُنْيَٰن",
        "waznEnglish": "they built",
        "waznTlit": "bun'yān",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "بَيْضَاءَ",
        "answer": "White",
        "pcklId": "10",
        "rootWordId": 171,
        "tlit": "bayḍāa",
        "frequency": "12",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "46",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " بَيْضَاءَ لَذَّةٍ لِلشَّارِبِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ب ي ض",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَبْيَض",
        "waznEnglish": "would become white",
        "waznTlit": "abyaḍ",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Adjective)"
    },
    {
        "question": "بَيْضٌ",
        "answer": "eggs",
        "pcklId": "11",
        "rootWordId": 171,
        "tlit": "bayḍun",
        "frequency": "12",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "49",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " كَأَنَّهُنَّ بَيْضٌ مَكْنُونٌ",
        "rootWord": "ب ي ض",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "بَيْض",
        "waznEnglish": "would become white",
        "waznTlit": "bayḍ",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "بَيْنَهُمَا",
        "answer": "(is) between both of them",
        "pcklId": "235",
        "rootWordId": 173,
        "tlit": "baynahumā",
        "frequency": "523",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "5",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " رَبُّ السَّمَاوَاتِ وَالْأَرْضِ وَمَا بَيْنَهُمَا وَرَبُّ الْمَشَارِقِ",
        "rootWord": "ب ي ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "بَيْن",
        "waznEnglish": "to make clear",
        "waznTlit": "bayn",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Location adverb)"
    },
    {
        "question": "بَيْنَهُ",
        "answer": "between Him",
        "pcklId": "236",
        "rootWordId": 173,
        "tlit": "baynahu",
        "frequency": "523",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "158",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " وَجَعَلُوا بَيْنَهُ وَبَيْنَ الْجِنَّةِ نَسَبًا",
        "rootWord": "ب ي ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "بَيْن",
        "waznEnglish": "to make clear",
        "waznTlit": "bayn",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Location adverb)"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَبَيْنَ",
        "answer": "and between",
        "pcklId": "237",
        "rootWordId": 173,
        "tlit": "wabayna",
        "frequency": "523",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "158",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " وَجَعَلُوا بَيْنَهُ وَبَيْنَ الْجِنَّةِ نَسَبًا",
        "rootWord": "ب ي ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "بَيْن",
        "waznEnglish": "to make clear",
        "waznTlit": "bayn",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Location adverb)"
    },
    {
        "question": "مُبِينٌ",
        "answer": "clear",
        "pcklId": "452",
        "rootWordId": 173,
        "tlit": "mubīnun",
        "frequency": "523",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "15",
        "wordnum": "6",
        "arabicAyah": " وَقَالُوا إِنْ هَٰذَا إِلَّا سِحْرٌ مُبِينٌ",
        "rootWord": "ب ي ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مُّبِين",
        "waznEnglish": "to make clear",
        "waznTlit": "mubīn",
        "waznType": "Active participle (form IV) (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْمُبِينُ",
        "answer": "clear",
        "pcklId": "453",
        "rootWordId": 173,
        "tlit": "l-mubīnu",
        "frequency": "523",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "106",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّ هَٰذَا لَهُوَ الْبَلَاءُ الْمُبِينُ",
        "rootWord": "ب ي ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مُّبِين",
        "waznEnglish": "to make clear",
        "waznTlit": "mubīn",
        "waznType": "Active participle (form IV) (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "مُبِينٌ",
        "answer": "clear",
        "pcklId": "454",
        "rootWordId": 173,
        "tlit": "mubīnun",
        "frequency": "523",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "156",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " أَمْ لَكُمْ سُلْطَانٌ مُبِينٌ",
        "rootWord": "ب ي ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مُّبِين",
        "waznEnglish": "to make clear",
        "waznTlit": "mubīn",
        "waznType": "Active participle (form IV) (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "مُبِينٌ",
        "answer": "clear",
        "pcklId": "510",
        "rootWordId": 173,
        "tlit": "mubīnun",
        "frequency": "523",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "113",
        "wordnum": "10",
        "arabicAyah": " وَمِنْ ذُرِّيَّتِهِمَا مُحْسِنٌ وَظَالِمٌ لِنَفْسِهِ مُبِينٌ",
        "rootWord": "ب ي ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مُّبِين",
        "waznEnglish": "to make clear",
        "waznTlit": "mubīn",
        "waznType": "Active participle (form IV) (Adjective)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْمُسْتَبِينَ",
        "answer": "the clear",
        "pcklId": "522",
        "rootWordId": 173,
        "tlit": "l-mus'tabīna",
        "frequency": "523",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "117",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " وَآتَيْنَاهُمَا الْكِتَابَ الْمُسْتَبِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ب ي ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مُسْتَبِين",
        "waznEnglish": "to make clear",
        "waznTlit": "mus'tabīn",
        "waznType": "Active participle (form X)"
    },
    {
        "question": "فَأَتْبَعَهُ",
        "answer": "but follows him",
        "pcklId": "22",
        "rootWordId": 176,
        "tlit": "fa-atbaʿahu",
        "frequency": "172",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "10",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " إِلَّا مَنْ خَطِفَ الْخَطْفَةَ فَأَتْبَعَهُ شِهَابٌ ثَاقِبٌ",
        "rootWord": "ت ب ع",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَتْبَعَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to follow",
        "waznTlit": "atbaʿa",
        "waznType": "Verb (form IV)"
    },
    {
        "question": "تُرَابًا",
        "answer": "dust",
        "pcklId": "15",
        "rootWordId": 179,
        "tlit": "turāban",
        "frequency": "22",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "16",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " أَإِذَا مِتْنَا وَكُنَّا تُرَابًا وَعِظَامًا أَإِنَّا لَمَبْعُوثُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ت ر ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "تُرَاب",
        "waznEnglish": "well-matched",
        "waznTlit": "turāb",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "تُرَابًا",
        "answer": "dust",
        "pcklId": "16",
        "rootWordId": 179,
        "tlit": "turāban",
        "frequency": "22",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "53",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " أَإِذَا مِتْنَا وَكُنَّا تُرَابًا وَعِظَامًا أَإِنَّا لَمَدِينُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ت ر ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "تُرَاب",
        "waznEnglish": "well-matched",
        "waznTlit": "turāb",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَتَرَكْنَا",
        "answer": "And We left",
        "pcklId": "29",
        "rootWordId": 182,
        "tlit": "wataraknā",
        "frequency": "43",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "78",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " وَتَرَكْنَا عَلَيْهِ فِي الْآخِرِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ت ر ك",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "تَرَكَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to leave",
        "waznTlit": "taraka",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَتَرَكْنَا",
        "answer": "And We left",
        "pcklId": "30",
        "rootWordId": 182,
        "tlit": "wataraknā",
        "frequency": "43",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "108",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " وَتَرَكْنَا عَلَيْهِ فِي الْآخِرِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ت ر ك",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "تَرَكَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to leave",
        "waznTlit": "taraka",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَتَرَكْنَا",
        "answer": "And We left",
        "pcklId": "31",
        "rootWordId": 182,
        "tlit": "wataraknā",
        "frequency": "43",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "119",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " وَتَرَكْنَا عَلَيْهِمَا فِي الْآخِرِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ت ر ك",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "تَرَكَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to leave",
        "waznTlit": "taraka",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَتَرَكْنَا",
        "answer": "And We left",
        "pcklId": "32",
        "rootWordId": 182,
        "tlit": "wataraknā",
        "frequency": "43",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "129",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " وَتَرَكْنَا عَلَيْهِ فِي الْآخِرِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ت ر ك",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "تَرَكَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to leave",
        "waznTlit": "taraka",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "لَتَارِكُو",
        "answer": "to leave",
        "pcklId": "42",
        "rootWordId": 182,
        "tlit": "latārikū",
        "frequency": "43",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "36",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " وَيَقُولُونَ أَئِنَّا لَتَارِكُو آلِهَتِنَا لِشَاعِرٍ مَجْنُونٍ",
        "rootWord": "ت ر ك",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "تَارِك",
        "waznEnglish": "and left them",
        "waznTlit": "tārik",
        "waznType": "Active participle"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَتَلَّهُ",
        "answer": "and he put him down",
        "pcklId": "0",
        "rootWordId": 187,
        "tlit": "watallahu",
        "frequency": "1",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "103",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " فَلَمَّا أَسْلَمَا وَتَلَّهُ لِلْجَبِينِ",
        "rootWord": "ت ل ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ت ل ل",
        "waznEnglish": "to put down",
        "waznTlit": "tā lām lām",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "فَالتَّالِيَاتِ",
        "answer": "And those who recite",
        "pcklId": "62",
        "rootWordId": 188,
        "tlit": "fal-tāliyāti",
        "frequency": "63",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "3",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " فَالتَّالِيَاتِ ذِكْرًا",
        "rootWord": "ت ل و",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "تَّٰلِيَٰت",
        "waznEnglish": "[you] recite",
        "waznTlit": "tāliyāt",
        "waznType": "Active participle"
    },
    {
        "question": "ثَاقِبٌ",
        "answer": "piercing",
        "pcklId": "1",
        "rootWordId": 203,
        "tlit": "thāqibun",
        "frequency": "2",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "10",
        "wordnum": "7",
        "arabicAyah": " إِلَّا مَنْ خَطِفَ الْخَطْفَةَ فَأَتْبَعَهُ شِهَابٌ ثَاقِبٌ",
        "rootWord": "ث ق ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ث ق ب",
        "waznEnglish": "the piercing",
        "waznTlit": "thā qāf bā",
        "waznType": "Active participle (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "لِلْجَبِينِ",
        "answer": "upon his forehead",
        "pcklId": "0",
        "rootWordId": 220,
        "tlit": "lil'jabīni",
        "frequency": "1",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "103",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " فَلَمَّا أَسْلَمَا وَتَلَّهُ لِلْجَبِينِ",
        "rootWord": "ج ب ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ج ب ن",
        "waznEnglish": "upon his forehead",
        "waznTlit": "jīm bā nūn",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْجَحِيمِ",
        "answer": "(of) the Hellfire",
        "pcklId": "6",
        "rootWordId": 227,
        "tlit": "l-jaḥīmi",
        "frequency": "26",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "23",
        "wordnum": "7",
        "arabicAyah": " فَاهْدُوهُمْ إِلَىٰ صِرَاطِ الْجَحِيمِ",
        "rootWord": "ج ح م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ج ح م",
        "waznEnglish": "(of) the blazing Fire",
        "waznTlit": "jīm ḥā mīm",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْجَحِيمِ",
        "answer": "(of) the Hellfire",
        "pcklId": "7",
        "rootWordId": 227,
        "tlit": "l-jaḥīmi",
        "frequency": "26",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "55",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " فَاطَّلَعَ فَرَآهُ فِي سَوَاءِ الْجَحِيمِ",
        "rootWord": "ج ح م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ج ح م",
        "waznEnglish": "(of) the blazing Fire",
        "waznTlit": "jīm ḥā mīm",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْجَحِيمِ",
        "answer": "(of) the Hellfire",
        "pcklId": "8",
        "rootWordId": 227,
        "tlit": "l-jaḥīmi",
        "frequency": "26",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "64",
        "wordnum": "6",
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّهَا شَجَرَةٌ تَخْرُجُ فِي أَصْلِ الْجَحِيمِ",
        "rootWord": "ج ح م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ج ح م",
        "waznEnglish": "(of) the blazing Fire",
        "waznTlit": "jīm ḥā mīm",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْجَحِيمِ",
        "answer": "the Hellfire",
        "pcklId": "9",
        "rootWordId": 227,
        "tlit": "l-jaḥīmi",
        "frequency": "26",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "68",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " ثُمَّ إِنَّ مَرْجِعَهُمْ لَإِلَى الْجَحِيمِ",
        "rootWord": "ج ح م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ج ح م",
        "waznEnglish": "(of) the blazing Fire",
        "waznTlit": "jīm ḥā mīm",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْجَحِيمِ",
        "answer": "the blazing Fire",
        "pcklId": "10",
        "rootWordId": 227,
        "tlit": "l-jaḥīmi",
        "frequency": "26",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "97",
        "wordnum": "7",
        "arabicAyah": " قَالُوا ابْنُوا لَهُ بُنْيَانًا فَأَلْقُوهُ فِي الْجَحِيمِ",
        "rootWord": "ج ح م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ج ح م",
        "waznEnglish": "(of) the blazing Fire",
        "waznTlit": "jīm ḥā mīm",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْجَحِيمِ",
        "answer": "(in) the Hellfire",
        "pcklId": "11",
        "rootWordId": 227,
        "tlit": "l-jaḥīmi",
        "frequency": "26",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "163",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " إِلَّا مَنْ هُوَ صَالِ الْجَحِيمِ",
        "rootWord": "ج ح م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ج ح م",
        "waznEnglish": "(of) the blazing Fire",
        "waznTlit": "jīm ḥā mīm",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "بِالْمُجْرِمِينَ",
        "answer": "with the criminals",
        "pcklId": "45",
        "rootWordId": 241,
        "tlit": "bil-muj'rimīna",
        "frequency": "66",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "34",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّا كَذَٰلِكَ نَفْعَلُ بِالْمُجْرِمِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ج ر م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مُجْرِم",
        "waznEnglish": "incite you",
        "waznTlit": "muj'rim",
        "waznType": "Active participle (form IV) (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "تُجْزَوْنَ",
        "answer": "you will be recompensed",
        "pcklId": "49",
        "rootWordId": 245,
        "tlit": "tuj'zawna",
        "frequency": "118",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "39",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " وَمَا تُجْزَوْنَ إِلَّا مَا كُنْتُمْ تَعْمَلُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ج ز ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "جَزَىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "to reward, to recompense",
        "waznTlit": "jazā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "نَجْزِي",
        "answer": "[We] reward",
        "pcklId": "50",
        "rootWordId": 245,
        "tlit": "najzī",
        "frequency": "118",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "80",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّا كَذَٰلِكَ نَجْزِي الْمُحْسِنِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ج ز ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "جَزَىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "to reward, to recompense",
        "waznTlit": "jazā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "نَجْزِي",
        "answer": "[We] reward",
        "pcklId": "51",
        "rootWordId": 245,
        "tlit": "najzī",
        "frequency": "118",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "105",
        "wordnum": "6",
        "arabicAyah": " قَدْ صَدَّقْتَ الرُّؤْيَا إِنَّا كَذَٰلِكَ نَجْزِي الْمُحْسِنِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ج ز ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "جَزَىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "to reward, to recompense",
        "waznTlit": "jazā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "نَجْزِي",
        "answer": "We reward",
        "pcklId": "52",
        "rootWordId": 245,
        "tlit": "najzī",
        "frequency": "118",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "110",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " كَذَٰلِكَ نَجْزِي الْمُحْسِنِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ج ز ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "جَزَىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "to reward, to recompense",
        "waznTlit": "jazā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "نَجْزِي",
        "answer": "reward",
        "pcklId": "53",
        "rootWordId": 245,
        "tlit": "najzī",
        "frequency": "118",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "121",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّا كَذَٰلِكَ نَجْزِي الْمُحْسِنِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ج ز ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "جَزَىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "to reward, to recompense",
        "waznTlit": "jazā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "نَجْزِي",
        "answer": "reward",
        "pcklId": "54",
        "rootWordId": 245,
        "tlit": "najzī",
        "frequency": "118",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "131",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّا كَذَٰلِكَ نَجْزِي الْمُحْسِنِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ج ز ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "جَزَىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "to reward, to recompense",
        "waznTlit": "jazā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "جَعَلْنَاهَا",
        "answer": "[We] have made it",
        "pcklId": "249",
        "rootWordId": 249,
        "tlit": "jaʿalnāhā",
        "frequency": "346",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "63",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّا جَعَلْنَاهَا فِتْنَةً لِلظَّالِمِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ج ع ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "جَعَلَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to make",
        "waznTlit": "jaʿala",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَجَعَلْنَا",
        "answer": "And We made",
        "pcklId": "250",
        "rootWordId": 249,
        "tlit": "wajaʿalnā",
        "frequency": "346",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "77",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " وَجَعَلْنَا ذُرِّيَّتَهُ هُمُ الْبَاقِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ج ع ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "جَعَلَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to make",
        "waznTlit": "jaʿala",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "فَجَعَلْنَاهُمُ",
        "answer": "but We made them",
        "pcklId": "251",
        "rootWordId": 249,
        "tlit": "fajaʿalnāhumu",
        "frequency": "346",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "98",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " فَأَرَادُوا بِهِ كَيْدًا فَجَعَلْنَاهُمُ الْأَسْفَلِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ج ع ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "جَعَلَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to make",
        "waznTlit": "jaʿala",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَجَعَلُوا",
        "answer": "And they have made",
        "pcklId": "252",
        "rootWordId": 249,
        "tlit": "wajaʿalū",
        "frequency": "346",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "158",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " وَجَعَلُوا بَيْنَهُ وَبَيْنَ الْجِنَّةِ نَسَبًا",
        "rootWord": "ج ع ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "جَعَلَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to make",
        "waznTlit": "jaʿala",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "أَجْمَعِينَ",
        "answer": "all",
        "pcklId": "48",
        "rootWordId": 260,
        "tlit": "ajmaʿīna",
        "frequency": "129",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "134",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " إِذْ نَجَّيْنَاهُ وَأَهْلَهُ أَجْمَعِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ج م ع",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَجْمَعِين",
        "waznEnglish": "We will gather them",
        "waznTlit": "ajmaʿīn",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "جَانِبٍ",
        "answer": "side",
        "pcklId": "30",
        "rootWordId": 263,
        "tlit": "jānibin",
        "frequency": "33",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "8",
        "wordnum": "9",
        "arabicAyah": " إِلَى الْمَلَإِ الْأَعْلَىٰ وَيُقْذَفُونَ مِنْ كُلِّ جَانِبٍ",
        "rootWord": "ج ن ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "جَانِب",
        "waznEnglish": "and keep me away",
        "waznTlit": "jānib",
        "waznType": "Active participle (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "جُنْدَنَا",
        "answer": "Our host",
        "pcklId": "20",
        "rootWordId": 265,
        "tlit": "jundanā",
        "frequency": "29",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "173",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " وَإِنَّ جُنْدَنَا لَهُمُ الْغَالِبُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ج ن د",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ج ن د",
        "waznEnglish": "with the forces",
        "waznTlit": "jīm nūn dāl",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْجِنَّةِ",
        "answer": "the jinn",
        "pcklId": "31",
        "rootWordId": 267,
        "tlit": "l-jinati",
        "frequency": "201",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "158",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " وَجَعَلُوا بَيْنَهُ وَبَيْنَ الْجِنَّةِ نَسَبًا",
        "rootWord": "ج ن ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "جِنَّة",
        "waznEnglish": "covered",
        "waznTlit": "jinnat",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْجِنَّةُ",
        "answer": "the jinn",
        "pcklId": "32",
        "rootWordId": 267,
        "tlit": "l-jinatu",
        "frequency": "201",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "158",
        "wordnum": "8",
        "arabicAyah": " وَلَقَدْ عَلِمَتِ الْجِنَّةُ إِنَّهُمْ لَمُحْضَرُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ج ن ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "جِنَّة",
        "waznEnglish": "covered",
        "waznTlit": "jinnat",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "جَنَّاتِ",
        "answer": "Gardens",
        "pcklId": "90",
        "rootWordId": 267,
        "tlit": "jannāti",
        "frequency": "201",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "43",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " فِي جَنَّاتِ النَّعِيمِ",
        "rootWord": "ج ن ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "جَنَّة",
        "waznEnglish": "covered",
        "waznTlit": "jannat",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "مَجْنُونٍ",
        "answer": "mad",
        "pcklId": "192",
        "rootWordId": 267,
        "tlit": "majnūnin",
        "frequency": "201",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "36",
        "wordnum": "6",
        "arabicAyah": " وَيَقُولُونَ أَئِنَّا لَتَارِكُو آلِهَتِنَا لِشَاعِرٍ مَجْنُونٍ",
        "rootWord": "ج ن ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مَجْنُون",
        "waznEnglish": "covered",
        "waznTlit": "majnūn",
        "waznType": "Passive participle"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْمُجِيبُونَ",
        "answer": "(are We as) Responders",
        "pcklId": "42",
        "rootWordId": 273,
        "tlit": "l-mujībūna",
        "frequency": "43",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "75",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " وَلَقَدْ نَادَانَا نُوحٌ فَلَنِعْمَ الْمُجِيبُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ج و ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مُّجِيب",
        "waznEnglish": "carved out",
        "waznTlit": "mujīb",
        "waznType": "Active participle (form IV)"
    },
    {
        "question": "جَاءَ",
        "answer": "he has brought",
        "pcklId": "211",
        "rootWordId": 281,
        "tlit": "jāa",
        "frequency": "278",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "37",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " بَلْ جَاءَ بِالْحَقِّ وَصَدَّقَ الْمُرْسَلِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ج ي أ",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ج ي أ",
        "waznEnglish": "to come",
        "waznTlit": "jīm yā hamza",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "جَاءَ",
        "answer": "he came",
        "pcklId": "212",
        "rootWordId": 281,
        "tlit": "jāa",
        "frequency": "278",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "84",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " إِذْ جَاءَ رَبَّهُ بِقَلْبٍ سَلِيمٍ",
        "rootWord": "ج ي أ",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ج ي أ",
        "waznEnglish": "to come",
        "waznTlit": "jīm yā hamza",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "أَحْسَنَ",
        "answer": "(the) Best",
        "pcklId": "49",
        "rootWordId": 321,
        "tlit": "aḥsana",
        "frequency": "194",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "125",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " أَتَدْعُونَ بَعْلًا وَتَذَرُونَ أَحْسَنَ الْخَالِقِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ح س ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَحْسَن",
        "waznEnglish": "And excellent",
        "waznTlit": "aḥsan",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْمُحْسِنِينَ",
        "answer": "the good-doers",
        "pcklId": "182",
        "rootWordId": 321,
        "tlit": "l-muḥ'sinīna",
        "frequency": "194",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "80",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّا كَذَٰلِكَ نَجْزِي الْمُحْسِنِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ح س ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مُحْسِن",
        "waznEnglish": "And excellent",
        "waznTlit": "muḥ'sin",
        "waznType": "Active participle (form IV)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْمُحْسِنِينَ",
        "answer": "the good-doers",
        "pcklId": "183",
        "rootWordId": 321,
        "tlit": "l-muḥ'sinīna",
        "frequency": "194",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "105",
        "wordnum": "7",
        "arabicAyah": " قَدْ صَدَّقْتَ الرُّؤْيَا إِنَّا كَذَٰلِكَ نَجْزِي الْمُحْسِنِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ح س ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مُحْسِن",
        "waznEnglish": "And excellent",
        "waznTlit": "muḥ'sin",
        "waznType": "Active participle (form IV)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْمُحْسِنِينَ",
        "answer": "the good-doers",
        "pcklId": "184",
        "rootWordId": 321,
        "tlit": "l-muḥ'sinīna",
        "frequency": "194",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "110",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " كَذَٰلِكَ نَجْزِي الْمُحْسِنِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ح س ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مُحْسِن",
        "waznEnglish": "And excellent",
        "waznTlit": "muḥ'sin",
        "waznType": "Active participle (form IV)"
    },
    {
        "question": "مُحْسِنٌ",
        "answer": "(are) good-doers",
        "pcklId": "185",
        "rootWordId": 321,
        "tlit": "muḥ'sinun",
        "frequency": "194",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "113",
        "wordnum": "7",
        "arabicAyah": " وَمِنْ ذُرِّيَّتِهِمَا مُحْسِنٌ وَظَالِمٌ لِنَفْسِهِ مُبِينٌ",
        "rootWord": "ح س ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مُحْسِن",
        "waznEnglish": "And excellent",
        "waznTlit": "muḥ'sin",
        "waznType": "Active participle (form IV)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْمُحْسِنِينَ",
        "answer": "the good-doers",
        "pcklId": "186",
        "rootWordId": 321,
        "tlit": "l-muḥ'sinīna",
        "frequency": "194",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "121",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّا كَذَٰلِكَ نَجْزِي الْمُحْسِنِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ح س ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مُحْسِن",
        "waznEnglish": "And excellent",
        "waznTlit": "muḥ'sin",
        "waznType": "Active participle (form IV)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْمُحْسِنِينَ",
        "answer": "the good-doers",
        "pcklId": "187",
        "rootWordId": 321,
        "tlit": "l-muḥ'sinīna",
        "frequency": "194",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "131",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّا كَذَٰلِكَ نَجْزِي الْمُحْسِنِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ح س ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مُحْسِن",
        "waznEnglish": "And excellent",
        "waznTlit": "muḥ'sin",
        "waznType": "Active participle (form IV)"
    },
    {
        "question": "احْشُرُوا",
        "answer": "Gather",
        "pcklId": "30",
        "rootWordId": 322,
        "tlit": "uḥ'shurū",
        "frequency": "43",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "22",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " احْشُرُوا الَّذِينَ ظَلَمُوا وَأَزْوَاجَهُمْ وَمَا كَانُوا يَعْبُدُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ح ش ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "حَشَرَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to gather, to raise",
        "waznTlit": "ḥashara",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْمُحْضَرِينَ",
        "answer": "those brought",
        "pcklId": "21",
        "rootWordId": 330,
        "tlit": "l-muḥ'ḍarīna",
        "frequency": "25",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "57",
        "wordnum": "6",
        "arabicAyah": " وَلَوْلَا نِعْمَةُ رَبِّي لَكُنْتُ مِنَ الْمُحْضَرِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ح ض ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مُّحْضَر",
        "waznEnglish": "came to",
        "waznTlit": "muḥ'ḍar",
        "waznType": "Passive participle (form IV)"
    },
    {
        "question": "لَمُحْضَرُونَ",
        "answer": "(will) surely be brought",
        "pcklId": "22",
        "rootWordId": 330,
        "tlit": "lamuḥ'ḍarūna",
        "frequency": "25",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "127",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " فَكَذَّبُوهُ فَإِنَّهُمْ لَمُحْضَرُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ح ض ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مُّحْضَر",
        "waznEnglish": "came to",
        "waznTlit": "muḥ'ḍar",
        "waznType": "Passive participle (form IV)"
    },
    {
        "question": "لَمُحْضَرُونَ",
        "answer": "(will) surely be brought",
        "pcklId": "23",
        "rootWordId": 330,
        "tlit": "lamuḥ'ḍarūna",
        "frequency": "25",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "158",
        "wordnum": "10",
        "arabicAyah": " وَلَقَدْ عَلِمَتِ الْجِنَّةُ إِنَّهُمْ لَمُحْضَرُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ح ض ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مُّحْضَر",
        "waznEnglish": "came to",
        "waznTlit": "muḥ'ḍar",
        "waznType": "Passive participle (form IV)"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَحِفْظًا",
        "answer": "And (to) guard",
        "pcklId": "13",
        "rootWordId": 339,
        "tlit": "waḥif'ẓan",
        "frequency": "44",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "7",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " وَحِفْظًا مِنْ كُلِّ شَيْطَانٍ مَارِدٍ",
        "rootWord": "ح ف ظ",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "حِفْظ",
        "waznEnglish": "(orders) them to guard",
        "waznTlit": "ḥif'ẓ",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "فَحَقَّ",
        "answer": "So has been proved true",
        "pcklId": "10",
        "rootWordId": 344,
        "tlit": "faḥaqqa",
        "frequency": "287",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "31",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " فَحَقَّ عَلَيْنَا قَوْلُ رَبِّنَا إِنَّا لَذَائِقُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ح ق ق",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "حَقَّ",
        "waznEnglish": "to justify, to prove true",
        "waznTlit": "ḥaqqa",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "بِالْحَقِّ",
        "answer": "the truth",
        "pcklId": "217",
        "rootWordId": 344,
        "tlit": "bil-ḥaqi",
        "frequency": "287",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "37",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " بَلْ جَاءَ بِالْحَقِّ وَصَدَّقَ الْمُرْسَلِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ح ق ق",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "حَقّ",
        "waznEnglish": "deserved ",
        "waznTlit": "ḥaqq",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "تَحْكُمُونَ",
        "answer": "you judge",
        "pcklId": "35",
        "rootWordId": 345,
        "tlit": "taḥkumūna",
        "frequency": "210",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "154",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " مَا لَكُمْ كَيْفَ تَحْكُمُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ح ك م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "حَكَمَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to judge",
        "waznTlit": "ḥakama",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "حَلِيمٍ",
        "answer": "forbearing",
        "pcklId": "15",
        "rootWordId": 349,
        "tlit": "ḥalīmin",
        "frequency": "21",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "101",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " فَبَشَّرْنَاهُ بِغُلَامٍ حَلِيمٍ",
        "rootWord": "ح ل م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "حَلِيم",
        "waznEnglish": "dreams",
        "waznTlit": "ḥalīm",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Adjective)"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَالْحَمْدُ",
        "answer": "And all praise",
        "pcklId": "30",
        "rootWordId": 352,
        "tlit": "wal-ḥamdu",
        "frequency": "63",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "182",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " وَالْحَمْدُ لِلَّهِ رَبِّ الْعَالَمِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ح م د",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "حَمْد",
        "waznEnglish": "they be praised",
        "waznTlit": "ḥamd",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "حَمِيمٍ",
        "answer": "boiling water",
        "pcklId": "2",
        "rootWordId": 355,
        "tlit": "ḥamīmin",
        "frequency": "21",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "67",
        "wordnum": "7",
        "arabicAyah": " ثُمَّ إِنَّ لَهُمْ عَلَيْهَا لَشَوْبًا مِنْ حَمِيمٍ",
        "rootWord": "ح م م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "حَمِيم",
        "waznEnglish": "boiling water",
        "waznTlit": "ḥamīm",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْحُوتُ",
        "answer": "the fish",
        "pcklId": "3",
        "rootWordId": 364,
        "tlit": "l-ḥūtu",
        "frequency": "5",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "142",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " فَالْتَقَمَهُ الْحُوتُ وَهُوَ مُلِيمٌ",
        "rootWord": "ح و ت",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ح و ت",
        "waznEnglish": "their fish",
        "waznTlit": "ḥā wāw tā",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "حِينٍ",
        "answer": "a while",
        "pcklId": "21",
        "rootWordId": 380,
        "tlit": "ḥīnin",
        "frequency": "35",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "148",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " فَآمَنُوا فَمَتَّعْنَاهُمْ إِلَىٰ حِينٍ",
        "rootWord": "ح ي ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ح ي ن",
        "waznEnglish": "a period",
        "waznTlit": "ḥā yā nūn",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "حِينٍ",
        "answer": "a time",
        "pcklId": "22",
        "rootWordId": 380,
        "tlit": "ḥīnin",
        "frequency": "35",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "174",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " فَتَوَلَّ عَنْهُمْ حَتَّىٰ حِينٍ",
        "rootWord": "ح ي ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ح ي ن",
        "waznEnglish": "a period",
        "waznTlit": "ḥā yā nūn",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "حِينٍ",
        "answer": "a time",
        "pcklId": "23",
        "rootWordId": 380,
        "tlit": "ḥīnin",
        "frequency": "35",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "178",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " وَتَوَلَّ عَنْهُمْ حَتَّىٰ حِينٍ",
        "rootWord": "ح ي ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ح ي ن",
        "waznEnglish": "a period",
        "waznTlit": "ḥā yā nūn",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "تَخْرُجُ",
        "answer": "that grows",
        "pcklId": "38",
        "rootWordId": 397,
        "tlit": "takhruju",
        "frequency": "182",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "64",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّهَا شَجَرَةٌ تَخْرُجُ فِي أَصْلِ الْجَحِيمِ",
        "rootWord": "خ ر ج",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "خَرَجَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to go out, to come out, to depart, to leave",
        "waznTlit": "kharaja",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "خَطِفَ",
        "answer": "snatches",
        "pcklId": "2",
        "rootWordId": 420,
        "tlit": "khaṭifa",
        "frequency": "7",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "10",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " إِلَّا مَنْ خَطِفَ الْخَطْفَةَ فَأَتْبَعَهُ شِهَابٌ ثَاقِبٌ",
        "rootWord": "خ ط ف",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "خَطِفَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to snatch",
        "waznTlit": "khaṭifa",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْخَطْفَةَ",
        "answer": "(by) theft",
        "pcklId": "6",
        "rootWordId": 420,
        "tlit": "l-khaṭfata",
        "frequency": "7",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "10",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " إِلَّا مَنْ خَطِفَ الْخَطْفَةَ فَأَتْبَعَهُ شِهَابٌ ثَاقِبٌ",
        "rootWord": "خ ط ف",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "خَطْفَة",
        "waznEnglish": "snatches away",
        "waznTlit": "khaṭfat",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْمُخْلَصِينَ",
        "answer": "the chosen ones",
        "pcklId": "24",
        "rootWordId": 427,
        "tlit": "l-mukh'laṣīna",
        "frequency": "31",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "40",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " إِلَّا عِبَادَ اللَّهِ الْمُخْلَصِينَ",
        "rootWord": "خ ل ص",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مُخْلَص",
        "waznEnglish": "they secluded themselves",
        "waznTlit": "mukh'laṣ",
        "waznType": "Passive participle (form IV) (Adjective)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْمُخْلَصِينَ",
        "answer": "the chosen ones",
        "pcklId": "25",
        "rootWordId": 427,
        "tlit": "l-mukh'laṣīna",
        "frequency": "31",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "74",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " إِلَّا عِبَادَ اللَّهِ الْمُخْلَصِينَ",
        "rootWord": "خ ل ص",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مُخْلَص",
        "waznEnglish": "they secluded themselves",
        "waznTlit": "mukh'laṣ",
        "waznType": "Passive participle (form IV) (Adjective)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْمُخْلَصِينَ",
        "answer": "the chosen ones",
        "pcklId": "26",
        "rootWordId": 427,
        "tlit": "l-mukh'laṣīna",
        "frequency": "31",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "128",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " إِلَّا عِبَادَ اللَّهِ الْمُخْلَصِينَ",
        "rootWord": "خ ل ص",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مُخْلَص",
        "waznEnglish": "they secluded themselves",
        "waznTlit": "mukh'laṣ",
        "waznType": "Passive participle (form IV) (Adjective)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْمُخْلَصِينَ",
        "answer": "the chosen",
        "pcklId": "27",
        "rootWordId": 427,
        "tlit": "l-mukh'laṣīna",
        "frequency": "31",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "160",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " إِلَّا عِبَادَ اللَّهِ الْمُخْلَصِينَ",
        "rootWord": "خ ل ص",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مُخْلَص",
        "waznEnglish": "they secluded themselves",
        "waznTlit": "mukh'laṣ",
        "waznType": "Passive participle (form IV) (Adjective)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْمُخْلَصِينَ",
        "answer": "the chosen",
        "pcklId": "28",
        "rootWordId": 427,
        "tlit": "l-mukh'laṣīna",
        "frequency": "31",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "169",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " لَكُنَّا عِبَادَ اللَّهِ الْمُخْلَصِينَ",
        "rootWord": "خ ل ص",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مُخْلَص",
        "waznEnglish": "they secluded themselves",
        "waznTlit": "mukh'laṣ",
        "waznType": "Passive participle (form IV) (Adjective)"
    },
    {
        "question": "خَلَقْنَا",
        "answer": "We have created",
        "pcklId": "109",
        "rootWordId": 431,
        "tlit": "khalaqnā",
        "frequency": "261",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "11",
        "wordnum": "7",
        "arabicAyah": " فَاسْتَفْتِهِمْ أَهُمْ أَشَدُّ خَلْقًا أَمْ مَنْ خَلَقْنَا",
        "rootWord": "خ ل ق",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "خَلَقَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to create",
        "waznTlit": "khalaqa",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "خَلَقْنَاهُمْ",
        "answer": "created them",
        "pcklId": "110",
        "rootWordId": 431,
        "tlit": "khalaqnāhum",
        "frequency": "261",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "11",
        "wordnum": "9",
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّا خَلَقْنَاهُمْ مِنْ طِينٍ لَازِبٍ",
        "rootWord": "خ ل ق",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "خَلَقَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to create",
        "waznTlit": "khalaqa",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "خَلَقَكُمْ",
        "answer": "created you",
        "pcklId": "111",
        "rootWordId": 431,
        "tlit": "khalaqakum",
        "frequency": "261",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "96",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " وَاللَّهُ خَلَقَكُمْ وَمَا تَعْمَلُونَ",
        "rootWord": "خ ل ق",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "خَلَقَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to create",
        "waznTlit": "khalaqa",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "خَلَقْنَا",
        "answer": "did We create",
        "pcklId": "112",
        "rootWordId": 431,
        "tlit": "khalaqnā",
        "frequency": "261",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "150",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " أَمْ خَلَقْنَا الْمَلَائِكَةَ إِنَاثًا وَهُمْ شَاهِدُونَ",
        "rootWord": "خ ل ق",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "خَلَقَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to create",
        "waznTlit": "khalaqa",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "خَلْقًا",
        "answer": "creation",
        "pcklId": "231",
        "rootWordId": 431,
        "tlit": "khalqan",
        "frequency": "261",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "11",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " فَاسْتَفْتِهِمْ أَهُمْ أَشَدُّ خَلْقًا أَمْ مَنْ خَلَقْنَا",
        "rootWord": "خ ل ق",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "خَلْق",
        "waznEnglish": "created you",
        "waznTlit": "khalq",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْخَالِقِينَ",
        "answer": "(of) Creators ",
        "pcklId": "251",
        "rootWordId": 431,
        "tlit": "l-khāliqīna",
        "frequency": "261",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "125",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " أَتَدْعُونَ بَعْلًا وَتَذَرُونَ أَحْسَنَ الْخَالِقِينَ",
        "rootWord": "خ ل ق",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "خَٰلِق",
        "waznEnglish": "created you",
        "waznTlit": "khāliq",
        "waznType": "Active participle (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "خَيْرٌ",
        "answer": "better",
        "pcklId": "125",
        "rootWordId": 449,
        "tlit": "khayrun",
        "frequency": "196",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "62",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " أَذَٰلِكَ خَيْرٌ نُزُلًا أَمْ شَجَرَةُ الزَّقُّومِ",
        "rootWord": "خ ي ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "خَيْر",
        "waznEnglish": "they select",
        "waznTlit": "khayr",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "مُدْبِرِينَ",
        "answer": "departing",
        "pcklId": "42",
        "rootWordId": 455,
        "tlit": "mud'birīna",
        "frequency": "44",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "90",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " فَتَوَلَّوْا عَنْهُ مُدْبِرِينَ",
        "rootWord": "د ب ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مُدْبِر",
        "waznEnglish": "disposing",
        "waznTlit": "mud'bir",
        "waznType": "Active participle (form IV)"
    },
    {
        "question": "دُحُورًا",
        "answer": "Repelled",
        "pcklId": "0",
        "rootWordId": 457,
        "tlit": "duḥūran",
        "frequency": "4",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "9",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " دُحُورًا",
        "rootWord": "د ح ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "دُحُور",
        "waznEnglish": "Repelled",
        "waznTlit": "duḥūr",
        "waznType": "Verbal noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْمُدْحَضِينَ",
        "answer": "the losers",
        "pcklId": "3",
        "rootWordId": 458,
        "tlit": "l-mud'ḥaḍīna",
        "frequency": "4",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "141",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " فَسَاهَمَ فَكَانَ مِنَ الْمُدْحَضِينَ",
        "rootWord": "د ح ض",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مُدْحَضِين",
        "waznEnglish": "to refute",
        "waznTlit": "mud'ḥaḍīn",
        "waznType": "Passive participle (form IV)"
    },
    {
        "question": "دَاخِرُونَ",
        "answer": "(will be) humiliated",
        "pcklId": "2",
        "rootWordId": 460,
        "tlit": "dākhirūna",
        "frequency": "4",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "18",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " قُلْ نَعَمْ وَأَنْتُمْ دَاخِرُونَ",
        "rootWord": "د خ ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "د خ ر",
        "waznEnglish": "(are) humble",
        "waznTlit": "dāl khā rā",
        "waznType": "Active participle"
    },
    {
        "question": "أَتَدْعُونَ",
        "answer": "Do you call",
        "pcklId": "116",
        "rootWordId": 474,
        "tlit": "atadʿūna",
        "frequency": "212",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "125",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " أَتَدْعُونَ بَعْلًا وَتَذَرُونَ أَحْسَنَ الْخَالِقِينَ",
        "rootWord": "د ع و",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "دَعَا",
        "waznEnglish": "to call, to invite, to pray",
        "waznTlit": "daʿā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "دَمَّرْنَا",
        "answer": "We destroyed",
        "pcklId": "5",
        "rootWordId": 483,
        "tlit": "dammarnā",
        "frequency": "10",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "136",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " ثُمَّ دَمَّرْنَا الْآخَرِينَ",
        "rootWord": "د م ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "دَمَّرَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to destroy",
        "waznTlit": "dammara",
        "waznType": "Verb (form II)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الدُّنْيَا",
        "answer": "[the world]",
        "pcklId": "67",
        "rootWordId": 488,
        "tlit": "l-dun'yā",
        "frequency": "133",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "6",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّا زَيَّنَّا السَّمَاءَ الدُّنْيَا بِزِينَةٍ الْكَوَاكِبِ",
        "rootWord": "د ن و",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "دُّنْيَا",
        "waznEnglish": "to draw",
        "waznTlit": "dun'yā",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Adjective)"
    },
    {
        "question": "دُونِ",
        "answer": "Besides",
        "pcklId": "106",
        "rootWordId": 497,
        "tlit": "dūni",
        "frequency": "144",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "23",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " مِنْ دُونِ اللَّهِ فَاهْدُوهُمْ إِلَىٰ صِرَاطِ الْجَحِيمِ",
        "rootWord": "د و ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "د و ن",
        "waznEnglish": "other than",
        "waznTlit": "dāl wāw nūn",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "دُونَ",
        "answer": "other than",
        "pcklId": "141",
        "rootWordId": 497,
        "tlit": "dūna",
        "frequency": "144",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "86",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " أَئِفْكًا آلِهَةً دُونَ اللَّهِ تُرِيدُونَ",
        "rootWord": "د و ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "د و ن",
        "waznEnglish": "other than",
        "waznTlit": "dāl wāw nūn",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Location adverb)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الدِّينِ",
        "answer": "(of) the Recompense",
        "pcklId": "58",
        "rootWordId": 498,
        "tlit": "l-dīni",
        "frequency": "101",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "20",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " وَقَالُوا يَا وَيْلَنَا هَٰذَا يَوْمُ الدِّينِ",
        "rootWord": "د ي ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "دِين",
        "waznEnglish": "they acknowledge",
        "waznTlit": "dīn",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "لَمَدِينُونَ",
        "answer": "surely be brought to Judgment",
        "pcklId": "99",
        "rootWordId": 498,
        "tlit": "lamadīnūna",
        "frequency": "101",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "53",
        "wordnum": "7",
        "arabicAyah": " أَإِذَا مِتْنَا وَكُنَّا تُرَابًا وَعِظَامًا أَإِنَّا لَمَدِينُونَ",
        "rootWord": "د ي ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مَدِينِين",
        "waznEnglish": "they acknowledge",
        "waznTlit": "madīnīn",
        "waznType": "Passive participle"
    },
    {
        "question": "أَذْبَحُكَ",
        "answer": "sacrificing you",
        "pcklId": "4",
        "rootWordId": 502,
        "tlit": "adhbaḥuka",
        "frequency": "9",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "102",
        "wordnum": "12",
        "arabicAyah": " يَا بُنَيَّ إِنِّي أَرَىٰ فِي الْمَنَامِ أَنِّي أَذْبَحُكَ فَانْظُرْ مَاذَا تَرَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ذ ب ح",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ذُبِحَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to slaughter, to sacrifice",
        "waznTlit": "dhubiḥa",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "بِذِبْحٍ",
        "answer": "with a sacrifice",
        "pcklId": "8",
        "rootWordId": 502,
        "tlit": "bidhib'ḥin",
        "frequency": "9",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "107",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " وَفَدَيْنَاهُ بِذِبْحٍ عَظِيمٍ",
        "rootWord": "ذ ب ح",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ذِبْح",
        "waznEnglish": "you slaughter",
        "waznTlit": "dhib'ḥ",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "ذُرِّيَّتَهُ",
        "answer": "his offspring",
        "pcklId": "26",
        "rootWordId": 506,
        "tlit": "dhurriyyatahu",
        "frequency": "38",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "77",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " وَجَعَلْنَا ذُرِّيَّتَهُ هُمُ الْبَاقِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ذ ر ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ذُرِّيَّة",
        "waznEnglish": "and their descendents",
        "waznTlit": "dhurriyyat",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "ذُرِّيَّتِهِمَا",
        "answer": "their offspring",
        "pcklId": "27",
        "rootWordId": 506,
        "tlit": "dhurriyyatihimā",
        "frequency": "38",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "113",
        "wordnum": "6",
        "arabicAyah": " وَبَارَكْنَا عَلَيْهِ وَعَلَىٰ إِسْحَاقَ وَمِنْ ذُرِّيَّتِهِمَا مُحْسِنٌ وَظَالِمٌ لِنَفْسِهِ مُبِينٌ",
        "rootWord": "ذ ر ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ذُرِّيَّة",
        "waznEnglish": "and their descendents",
        "waznTlit": "dhurriyyat",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "يَذْكُرُونَ",
        "answer": "they receive admonition",
        "pcklId": "66",
        "rootWordId": 511,
        "tlit": "yadhkurūna",
        "frequency": "292",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "13",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " وَإِذَا ذُكِّرُوا لَا يَذْكُرُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ذ ك ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ذَكَرَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to remember, to mention",
        "waznTlit": "dhakara",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "ذُكِّرُوا",
        "answer": "they are reminded",
        "pcklId": "96",
        "rootWordId": 511,
        "tlit": "dhukkirū",
        "frequency": "292",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "13",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " وَإِذَا ذُكِّرُوا لَا يَذْكُرُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ذ ك ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ذُكِّرَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to remind",
        "waznTlit": "dhukkira",
        "waznType": "Verb (form II)"
    },
    {
        "question": "تَذَكَّرُونَ",
        "answer": "you pay heed",
        "pcklId": "138",
        "rootWordId": 511,
        "tlit": "tadhakkarūna",
        "frequency": "292",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "155",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " أَفَلَا تَذَكَّرُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ذ ك ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "تَذَكَّرَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to receive admonition",
        "waznTlit": "tadhakkara",
        "waznType": "Verb (form V)"
    },
    {
        "question": "ذِكْرًا",
        "answer": "(the) Message",
        "pcklId": "241",
        "rootWordId": 511,
        "tlit": "dhik'ran",
        "frequency": "292",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "3",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " فَالتَّالِيَاتِ ذِكْرًا",
        "rootWord": "ذ ك ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ذِكْر",
        "waznEnglish": "Remember",
        "waznTlit": "dhik'r",
        "waznType": "Verbal noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "ذِكْرًا",
        "answer": "a reminder",
        "pcklId": "242",
        "rootWordId": 511,
        "tlit": "dhik'ran",
        "frequency": "292",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "168",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " لَوْ أَنَّ عِنْدَنَا ذِكْرًا مِنَ الْأَوَّلِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ذ ك ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ذِكْر",
        "waznEnglish": "Remember",
        "waznTlit": "dhik'r",
        "waznType": "Verbal noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "ذَاهِبٌ",
        "answer": "going",
        "pcklId": "55",
        "rootWordId": 516,
        "tlit": "dhāhibun",
        "frequency": "56",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "99",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " وَقَالَ إِنِّي ذَاهِبٌ إِلَىٰ رَبِّي سَيَهْدِينِ",
        "rootWord": "ذ ه ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ذَاهِب",
        "waznEnglish": "took away",
        "waznTlit": "dhāhib",
        "waznType": "Active participle"
    },
    {
        "question": "لَذَائِقُونَ",
        "answer": "(will) certainly taste",
        "pcklId": "58",
        "rootWordId": 519,
        "tlit": "ladhāiqūna",
        "frequency": "63",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "31",
        "wordnum": "6",
        "arabicAyah": " فَحَقَّ عَلَيْنَا قَوْلُ رَبِّنَا إِنَّا لَذَائِقُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ذ و ق",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ذَآئِقُوا",
        "waznEnglish": "Then taste",
        "waznTlit": "dhāiqū",
        "waznType": "Active participle"
    },
    {
        "question": "لَذَائِقُو",
        "answer": "(will) surely taste",
        "pcklId": "59",
        "rootWordId": 519,
        "tlit": "ladhāiqū",
        "frequency": "63",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "38",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّكُمْ لَذَائِقُو الْعَذَابِ الْأَلِيمِ",
        "rootWord": "ذ و ق",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ذَآئِقُوا",
        "waznEnglish": "Then taste",
        "waznTlit": "dhāiqū",
        "waznType": "Active participle"
    },
    {
        "question": "رُءُوسُ",
        "answer": "(was) heads",
        "pcklId": "14",
        "rootWordId": 521,
        "tlit": "ruūsu",
        "frequency": "18",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "65",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " طَلْعُهَا كَأَنَّهُ رُءُوسُ الشَّيَاطِينِ",
        "rootWord": "ر أ س",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ر أ س",
        "waznEnglish": "your heads",
        "waznTlit": "rā hamza sīn",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "رَأَوْا",
        "answer": "they see",
        "pcklId": "178",
        "rootWordId": 523,
        "tlit": "ra-aw",
        "frequency": "328",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "14",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " وَإِذَا رَأَوْا آيَةً يَسْتَسْخِرُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ر أ ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "رَءَا",
        "waznEnglish": "to see",
        "waznTlit": "raā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "فَرَآهُ",
        "answer": "and see him",
        "pcklId": "179",
        "rootWordId": 523,
        "tlit": "faraāhu",
        "frequency": "328",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "55",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " فَاطَّلَعَ فَرَآهُ فِي سَوَاءِ الْجَحِيمِ",
        "rootWord": "ر أ ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "رَءَا",
        "waznEnglish": "to see",
        "waznTlit": "raā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "أَرَىٰ",
        "answer": "have seen",
        "pcklId": "180",
        "rootWordId": 523,
        "tlit": "arā",
        "frequency": "328",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "102",
        "wordnum": "8",
        "arabicAyah": " يَا بُنَيَّ إِنِّي أَرَىٰ فِي الْمَنَامِ أَنِّي أَذْبَحُكَ فَانْظُرْ مَاذَا تَرَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ر أ ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "رَءَا",
        "waznEnglish": "to see",
        "waznTlit": "raā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "تَرَىٰ",
        "answer": "you see",
        "pcklId": "181",
        "rootWordId": 523,
        "tlit": "tarā",
        "frequency": "328",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "102",
        "wordnum": "15",
        "arabicAyah": " إِنِّي أَرَىٰ فِي الْمَنَامِ أَنِّي أَذْبَحُكَ فَانْظُرْ مَاذَا تَرَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ر أ ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "رَءَا",
        "waznEnglish": "to see",
        "waznTlit": "raā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الرُّؤْيَا",
        "answer": "the vision",
        "pcklId": "323",
        "rootWordId": 523,
        "tlit": "l-ru'yā",
        "frequency": "328",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "105",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " قَدْ صَدَّقْتَ الرُّؤْيَا إِنَّا كَذَٰلِكَ نَجْزِي الْمُحْسِنِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ر أ ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "رُّءْيَا",
        "waznEnglish": "we see",
        "waznTlit": "ru'yā",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "رَبُّ",
        "answer": "Lord",
        "pcklId": "680",
        "rootWordId": 524,
        "tlit": "rabbu",
        "frequency": "980",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "5",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " رَبُّ السَّمَاوَاتِ وَالْأَرْضِ وَمَا بَيْنَهُمَا",
        "rootWord": "ر ب ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "رَبّ",
        "waznEnglish": "the Lord",
        "waznTlit": "rabb",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَرَبُّ",
        "answer": "and Lord",
        "pcklId": "681",
        "rootWordId": 524,
        "tlit": "warabbu",
        "frequency": "980",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "5",
        "wordnum": "6",
        "arabicAyah": " وَرَبُّ الْمَشَارِقِ",
        "rootWord": "ر ب ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "رَبّ",
        "waznEnglish": "the Lord",
        "waznTlit": "rabb",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "رَبِّنَا",
        "answer": "(of) our Lord",
        "pcklId": "682",
        "rootWordId": 524,
        "tlit": "rabbinā",
        "frequency": "980",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "31",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " فَحَقَّ عَلَيْنَا قَوْلُ رَبِّنَا إِنَّا لَذَائِقُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ر ب ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "رَبّ",
        "waznEnglish": "the Lord",
        "waznTlit": "rabb",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "رَبِّي",
        "answer": "(of) my Lord",
        "pcklId": "683",
        "rootWordId": 524,
        "tlit": "rabbī",
        "frequency": "980",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "57",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " وَلَوْلَا نِعْمَةُ رَبِّي لَكُنْتُ مِنَ الْمُحْضَرِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ر ب ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "رَبّ",
        "waznEnglish": "the Lord",
        "waznTlit": "rabb",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "رَبَّهُ",
        "answer": "(to) his Lord",
        "pcklId": "684",
        "rootWordId": 524,
        "tlit": "rabbahu",
        "frequency": "980",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "84",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " إِذْ جَاءَ رَبَّهُ بِقَلْبٍ سَلِيمٍ",
        "rootWord": "ر ب ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "رَبّ",
        "waznEnglish": "the Lord",
        "waznTlit": "rabb",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "بِرَبِّ",
        "answer": "about (the) Lord",
        "pcklId": "685",
        "rootWordId": 524,
        "tlit": "birabbi",
        "frequency": "980",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "87",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " فَمَا ظَنُّكُمْ بِرَبِّ الْعَالَمِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ر ب ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "رَبّ",
        "waznEnglish": "the Lord",
        "waznTlit": "rabb",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "رَبِّي",
        "answer": "my Lord",
        "pcklId": "686",
        "rootWordId": 524,
        "tlit": "rabbī",
        "frequency": "980",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "99",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " وَقَالَ إِنِّي ذَاهِبٌ إِلَىٰ رَبِّي سَيَهْدِينِ",
        "rootWord": "ر ب ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "رَبّ",
        "waznEnglish": "the Lord",
        "waznTlit": "rabb",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "رَبِّ",
        "answer": "My Lord",
        "pcklId": "687",
        "rootWordId": 524,
        "tlit": "rabbi",
        "frequency": "980",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "100",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " رَبِّ هَبْ لِي مِنَ الصَّالِحِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ر ب ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "رَبّ",
        "waznEnglish": "the Lord",
        "waznTlit": "rabb",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "رَبَّكُمْ",
        "answer": "your Lord",
        "pcklId": "688",
        "rootWordId": 524,
        "tlit": "rabbakum",
        "frequency": "980",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "126",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " اللَّهَ رَبَّكُمْ وَرَبَّ آبَائِكُمُ الْأَوَّلِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ر ب ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "رَبّ",
        "waznEnglish": "the Lord",
        "waznTlit": "rabb",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَرَبَّ",
        "answer": "and (the) Lord",
        "pcklId": "689",
        "rootWordId": 524,
        "tlit": "warabba",
        "frequency": "980",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "126",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " اللَّهَ رَبَّكُمْ وَرَبَّ آبَائِكُمُ الْأَوَّلِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ر ب ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "رَبّ",
        "waznEnglish": "the Lord",
        "waznTlit": "rabb",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "أَلِرَبِّكَ",
        "answer": "Does your Lord",
        "pcklId": "690",
        "rootWordId": 524,
        "tlit": "alirabbika",
        "frequency": "980",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "149",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " فَاسْتَفْتِهِمْ أَلِرَبِّكَ الْبَنَاتُ وَلَهُمُ الْبَنُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ر ب ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "رَبّ",
        "waznEnglish": "the Lord",
        "waznTlit": "rabb",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "رَبِّكَ",
        "answer": "(be to) your Lord",
        "pcklId": "691",
        "rootWordId": 524,
        "tlit": "rabbika",
        "frequency": "980",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "180",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " سُبْحَانَ رَبِّكَ رَبِّ الْعِزَّةِ عَمَّا يَصِفُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ر ب ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "رَبّ",
        "waznEnglish": "the Lord",
        "waznTlit": "rabb",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "رَبِّ",
        "answer": "(the) Lord",
        "pcklId": "692",
        "rootWordId": 524,
        "tlit": "rabbi",
        "frequency": "980",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "180",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " سُبْحَانَ رَبِّكَ رَبِّ الْعِزَّةِ عَمَّا يَصِفُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ر ب ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "رَبّ",
        "waznEnglish": "the Lord",
        "waznTlit": "rabb",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "رَبِّ",
        "answer": "(the) Lord",
        "pcklId": "693",
        "rootWordId": 524,
        "tlit": "rabbi",
        "frequency": "980",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "182",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " وَالْحَمْدُ لِلَّهِ رَبِّ الْعَالَمِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ر ب ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "رَبّ",
        "waznEnglish": "the Lord",
        "waznTlit": "rabb",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "مَرْجِعَهُمْ",
        "answer": "their return",
        "pcklId": "98",
        "rootWordId": 536,
        "tlit": "marjiʿahum",
        "frequency": "104",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "68",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " ثُمَّ إِنَّ مَرْجِعَهُمْ لَإِلَى الْجَحِيمِ",
        "rootWord": "ر ج ع",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مَرْجِع",
        "waznEnglish": "[they] will not return",
        "waznTlit": "marjiʿ",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "لَتُرْدِينِ",
        "answer": "ruined me",
        "pcklId": "2",
        "rootWordId": 550,
        "tlit": "latur'dīni",
        "frequency": "6",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "56",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " قَالَ تَاللَّهِ إِنْ كِدْتَ لَتُرْدِينِ",
        "rootWord": "ر د ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَرْدَىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "to ruin",
        "waznTlit": "ardā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form IV)"
    },
    {
        "question": "رِزْقٌ",
        "answer": "(will be) a provision",
        "pcklId": "101",
        "rootWordId": 552,
        "tlit": "riz'qun",
        "frequency": "123",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "41",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " أُولَٰئِكَ لَهُمْ رِزْقٌ مَعْلُومٌ",
        "rootWord": "ر ز ق",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "رِزْق",
        "waznEnglish": "We have provided them",
        "waznTlit": "riz'q",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "أَرْسَلْنَا",
        "answer": "We sent",
        "pcklId": "94",
        "rootWordId": 555,
        "tlit": "arsalnā",
        "frequency": "513",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "72",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " وَلَقَدْ أَرْسَلْنَا فِيهِمْ مُنْذِرِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ر س ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَرْسَلَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to send",
        "waznTlit": "arsala",
        "waznType": "Verb (form IV)"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَأَرْسَلْنَاهُ",
        "answer": "And We sent him",
        "pcklId": "95",
        "rootWordId": 555,
        "tlit": "wa-arsalnāhu",
        "frequency": "513",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "147",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " وَأَرْسَلْنَاهُ إِلَىٰ مِائَةِ أَلْفٍ أَوْ يَزِيدُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ر س ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَرْسَلَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to send",
        "waznTlit": "arsala",
        "waznType": "Verb (form IV)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْمُرْسَلِينَ",
        "answer": "the Messengers",
        "pcklId": "505",
        "rootWordId": 555,
        "tlit": "l-mur'salīna",
        "frequency": "513",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "37",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " بَلْ جَاءَ بِالْحَقِّ وَصَدَّقَ الْمُرْسَلِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ر س ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مُّرْسَل",
        "waznEnglish": "[We] have sent you",
        "waznTlit": "mur'sal",
        "waznType": "Passive participle (form IV) (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْمُرْسَلِينَ",
        "answer": "the Messengers",
        "pcklId": "506",
        "rootWordId": 555,
        "tlit": "l-mur'salīna",
        "frequency": "513",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "123",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " وَإِنَّ إِلْيَاسَ لَمِنَ الْمُرْسَلِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ر س ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مُّرْسَل",
        "waznEnglish": "[We] have sent you",
        "waznTlit": "mur'sal",
        "waznType": "Passive participle (form IV) (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْمُرْسَلِينَ",
        "answer": "the Messengers",
        "pcklId": "507",
        "rootWordId": 555,
        "tlit": "l-mur'salīna",
        "frequency": "513",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "133",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " وَإِنَّ لُوطًا لَمِنَ الْمُرْسَلِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ر س ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مُّرْسَل",
        "waznEnglish": "[We] have sent you",
        "waznTlit": "mur'sal",
        "waznType": "Passive participle (form IV) (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْمُرْسَلِينَ",
        "answer": "the Messengers",
        "pcklId": "508",
        "rootWordId": 555,
        "tlit": "l-mur'salīna",
        "frequency": "513",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "139",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " وَإِنَّ يُونُسَ لَمِنَ الْمُرْسَلِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ر س ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مُّرْسَل",
        "waznEnglish": "[We] have sent you",
        "waznTlit": "mur'sal",
        "waznType": "Passive participle (form IV) (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْمُرْسَلِينَ",
        "answer": "the Messengers",
        "pcklId": "509",
        "rootWordId": 555,
        "tlit": "l-mur'salīna",
        "frequency": "513",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "181",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " وَسَلَامٌ عَلَى الْمُرْسَلِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ر س ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مُّرْسَل",
        "waznEnglish": "[We] have sent you",
        "waznTlit": "mur'sal",
        "waznType": "Passive participle (form IV) (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْمُرْسَلِينَ",
        "answer": "the Messengers",
        "pcklId": "511",
        "rootWordId": 555,
        "tlit": "l-mur'salīna",
        "frequency": "513",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "171",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " وَلَقَدْ سَبَقَتْ كَلِمَتُنَا لِعِبَادِنَا الْمُرْسَلِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ر س ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مُّرْسَل",
        "waznEnglish": "[We] have sent you",
        "waznTlit": "mur'sal",
        "waznType": "Passive participle (form IV) (Adjective)"
    },
    {
        "question": "تُرِيدُونَ",
        "answer": "(that) you desire",
        "pcklId": "123",
        "rootWordId": 600,
        "tlit": "turīdūna",
        "frequency": "148",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "86",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " أَئِفْكًا آلِهَةً دُونَ اللَّهِ تُرِيدُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ر و د",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَرَادَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to intend, to desire, to want, to wish",
        "waznTlit": "arāda",
        "waznType": "Verb (form IV)"
    },
    {
        "question": "فَأَرَادُوا",
        "answer": "And they intended",
        "pcklId": "124",
        "rootWordId": 600,
        "tlit": "fa-arādū",
        "frequency": "148",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "98",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " فَأَرَادُوا بِهِ كَيْدًا فَجَعَلْنَاهُمُ الْأَسْفَلِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ر و د",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَرَادَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to intend, to desire, to want, to wish",
        "waznTlit": "arāda",
        "waznType": "Verb (form IV)"
    },
    {
        "question": "فَرَاغَ",
        "answer": "Then he turned",
        "pcklId": "0",
        "rootWordId": 603,
        "tlit": "farāgha",
        "frequency": "3",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "91",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " فَرَاغَ إِلَىٰ آلِهَتِهِمْ فَقَالَ أَلَا تَأْكُلُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ر و غ",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ر و غ",
        "waznEnglish": "to turn",
        "waznTlit": "rā wāw ghayn",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "فَرَاغَ",
        "answer": "Then he turned",
        "pcklId": "1",
        "rootWordId": 603,
        "tlit": "farāgha",
        "frequency": "3",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "93",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " فَرَاغَ عَلَيْهِمْ ضَرْبًا بِالْيَمِينِ",
        "rootWord": "ر و غ",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ر و غ",
        "waznEnglish": "to turn",
        "waznTlit": "rā wāw ghayn",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "زَجْرَةٌ",
        "answer": "(will be) a cry",
        "pcklId": "1",
        "rootWordId": 612,
        "tlit": "zajratun",
        "frequency": "6",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "19",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " فَإِنَّمَا هِيَ زَجْرَةٌ وَاحِدَةٌ فَإِذَا هُمْ يَنْظُرُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ز ج ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "زَجْرَة",
        "waznEnglish": "and he was repelled",
        "waznTlit": "zajrat",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "زَجْرًا",
        "answer": "strongly",
        "pcklId": "3",
        "rootWordId": 612,
        "tlit": "zajran",
        "frequency": "6",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "2",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " فَالزَّاجِرَاتِ زَجْرًا",
        "rootWord": "ز ج ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "زَجْر",
        "waznEnglish": "and he was repelled",
        "waznTlit": "zajr",
        "waznType": "Verbal noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "فَالزَّاجِرَاتِ",
        "answer": "And those who drive",
        "pcklId": "4",
        "rootWordId": 612,
        "tlit": "fal-zājirāti",
        "frequency": "6",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "2",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " فَالزَّاجِرَاتِ زَجْرًا",
        "rootWord": "ز ج ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "زَّٰجِرَٰت",
        "waznEnglish": "and he was repelled",
        "waznTlit": "zājirāt",
        "waznType": "Active participle"
    },
    {
        "question": "يَزِفُّونَ",
        "answer": "hastening",
        "pcklId": "0",
        "rootWordId": 622,
        "tlit": "yaziffūna",
        "frequency": "1",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "94",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " فَأَقْبَلُوا إِلَيْهِ يَزِفُّونَ",
        "rootWord": "ز ف ف",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ز ف ف",
        "waznEnglish": "to hasten",
        "waznTlit": "zāy fā fā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الزَّقُّومِ",
        "answer": "(of) Zaqqum",
        "pcklId": "0",
        "rootWordId": 623,
        "tlit": "l-zaqūmi",
        "frequency": "3",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "62",
        "wordnum": "6",
        "arabicAyah": " أَذَٰلِكَ خَيْرٌ نُزُلًا أَمْ شَجَرَةُ الزَّقُّومِ",
        "rootWord": "ز ق م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ز ق م",
        "waznEnglish": "(of) Zaqqum",
        "waznTlit": "zāy qāf mīm",
        "waznType": "Proper noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَأَزْوَاجَهُمْ",
        "answer": "and their kinds",
        "pcklId": "57",
        "rootWordId": 638,
        "tlit": "wa-azwājahum",
        "frequency": "81",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "22",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " احْشُرُوا الَّذِينَ ظَلَمُوا وَأَزْوَاجَهُمْ وَمَا كَانُوا يَعْبُدُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ز و ج",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "زَوْج",
        "waznEnglish": "We married her to you",
        "waznTlit": "zawj",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "يَزِيدُونَ",
        "answer": "more",
        "pcklId": "35",
        "rootWordId": 643,
        "tlit": "yazīdūna",
        "frequency": "61",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "147",
        "wordnum": "6",
        "arabicAyah": " وَأَرْسَلْنَاهُ إِلَىٰ مِائَةِ أَلْفٍ أَوْ يَزِيدُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ز ي د",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "زَادَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to increase",
        "waznTlit": "zāda",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "زَيَّنَّا",
        "answer": "[We] adorned",
        "pcklId": "17",
        "rootWordId": 646,
        "tlit": "zayyannā",
        "frequency": "46",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "6",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّا زَيَّنَّا السَّمَاءَ الدُّنْيَا بِزِينَةٍ الْكَوَاكِبِ",
        "rootWord": "ز ي ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "زَيَّنَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to make fair",
        "waznTlit": "zayyana",
        "waznType": "Verb (form II)"
    },
    {
        "question": "بِزِينَةٍ",
        "answer": "with an adornment",
        "pcklId": "44",
        "rootWordId": 646,
        "tlit": "bizīnatin",
        "frequency": "46",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "6",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّا زَيَّنَّا السَّمَاءَ الدُّنْيَا بِزِينَةٍ الْكَوَاكِبِ",
        "rootWord": "ز ي ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "زِينَة",
        "waznEnglish": "Beautified",
        "waznTlit": "zīnat",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "يَتَسَاءَلُونَ",
        "answer": "questioning one another",
        "pcklId": "110",
        "rootWordId": 647,
        "tlit": "yatasāalūna",
        "frequency": "129",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "27",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " وَأَقْبَلَ بَعْضُهُمْ عَلَىٰ بَعْضٍ يَتَسَاءَلُونَ",
        "rootWord": "س أ ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "يَتَسَآءَلُ",
        "waznEnglish": "to question, to ask, to inquire",
        "waznTlit": "yatasāalu",
        "waznType": "Verb (form VI)"
    },
    {
        "question": "يَتَسَاءَلُونَ",
        "answer": "questioning one another",
        "pcklId": "111",
        "rootWordId": 647,
        "tlit": "yatasāalūna",
        "frequency": "129",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "50",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " فَأَقْبَلَ بَعْضُهُمْ عَلَىٰ بَعْضٍ يَتَسَاءَلُونَ",
        "rootWord": "س أ ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "يَتَسَآءَلُ",
        "waznEnglish": "to question, to ask, to inquire",
        "waznTlit": "yatasāalu",
        "waznType": "Verb (form VI)"
    },
    {
        "question": "مَسْئُولُونَ",
        "answer": "(are) to be questioned",
        "pcklId": "128",
        "rootWordId": 647,
        "tlit": "masūlūna",
        "frequency": "129",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "24",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " وَقِفُوهُمْ إِنَّهُمْ مَسْئُولُونَ",
        "rootWord": "س أ ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مَسْـُٔول",
        "waznEnglish": "you have asked (for)",
        "waznTlit": "masūl",
        "waznType": "Passive participle"
    },
    {
        "question": "سُبْحَانَ",
        "answer": "Glory be",
        "pcklId": "78",
        "rootWordId": 651,
        "tlit": "sub'ḥāna",
        "frequency": "92",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "159",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " سُبْحَانَ اللَّهِ عَمَّا يَصِفُونَ",
        "rootWord": "س ب ح",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "سُبْحَٰن",
        "waznEnglish": "floating",
        "waznTlit": "sub'ḥān",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "سُبْحَانَ",
        "answer": "Glory",
        "pcklId": "79",
        "rootWordId": 651,
        "tlit": "sub'ḥāna",
        "frequency": "92",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "180",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " سُبْحَانَ رَبِّكَ رَبِّ الْعِزَّةِ عَمَّا يَصِفُونَ",
        "rootWord": "س ب ح",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "سُبْحَٰن",
        "waznEnglish": "floating",
        "waznTlit": "sub'ḥān",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْمُسَبِّحِينَ",
        "answer": "those who glorify",
        "pcklId": "90",
        "rootWordId": 651,
        "tlit": "l-musabiḥīna",
        "frequency": "92",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "143",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " فَلَوْلَا أَنَّهُ كَانَ مِنَ الْمُسَبِّحِينَ",
        "rootWord": "س ب ح",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مُسَبِّحُون",
        "waznEnglish": "floating",
        "waznTlit": "musabbiḥūn",
        "waznType": "Active participle (form II)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْمُسَبِّحُونَ",
        "answer": "glorify (Allah)",
        "pcklId": "91",
        "rootWordId": 651,
        "tlit": "l-musabiḥūna",
        "frequency": "92",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "166",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " وَإِنَّا لَنَحْنُ الْمُسَبِّحُونَ",
        "rootWord": "س ب ح",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مُسَبِّحُون",
        "waznEnglish": "floating",
        "waznTlit": "musabbiḥūn",
        "waznType": "Active participle (form II)"
    },
    {
        "question": "سَبَقَتْ",
        "answer": "has preceded",
        "pcklId": "15",
        "rootWordId": 655,
        "tlit": "sabaqat",
        "frequency": "37",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "171",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " وَلَقَدْ سَبَقَتْ كَلِمَتُنَا لِعِبَادِنَا الْمُرْسَلِينَ",
        "rootWord": "س ب ق",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "سَبَقَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to precede",
        "waznTlit": "sabaqa",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "سِحْرٌ",
        "answer": "a magic",
        "pcklId": "28",
        "rootWordId": 666,
        "tlit": "siḥ'run",
        "frequency": "63",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "15",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " وَقَالُوا إِنْ هَٰذَا إِلَّا سِحْرٌ مُبِينٌ",
        "rootWord": "س ح ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "سِحْر",
        "waznEnglish": "they bewitched",
        "waznTlit": "siḥ'r",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَيَسْخَرُونَ",
        "answer": "while they mock",
        "pcklId": "9",
        "rootWordId": 669,
        "tlit": "wayaskharūna",
        "frequency": "42",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "12",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " بَلْ عَجِبْتَ وَيَسْخَرُونَ",
        "rootWord": "س خ ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "سَخِرَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to ridicule, to mock",
        "waznTlit": "sakhira",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "يَسْتَسْخِرُونَ",
        "answer": "they mock",
        "pcklId": "33",
        "rootWordId": 669,
        "tlit": "yastaskhirūna",
        "frequency": "42",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "14",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " وَإِذَا رَأَوْا آيَةً يَسْتَسْخِرُونَ",
        "rootWord": "س خ ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "يَسْتَسْخِرُ",
        "waznEnglish": "to mock",
        "waznTlit": "yastaskhiru",
        "waznType": "Verb (form X)"
    },
    {
        "question": "سُرُرٍ",
        "answer": "thrones",
        "pcklId": "34",
        "rootWordId": 681,
        "tlit": "sururin",
        "frequency": "44",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "44",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " عَلَىٰ سُرُرٍ مُتَقَابِلِينَ",
        "rootWord": "س ر ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "سُرُر",
        "waznEnglish": "pleasing",
        "waznTlit": "surur",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "السَّعْيَ",
        "answer": "the (age of) working with him",
        "pcklId": "25",
        "rootWordId": 692,
        "tlit": "l-saʿya",
        "frequency": "30",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "102",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " فَلَمَّا بَلَغَ مَعَهُ السَّعْيَ قَالَ يَا بُنَيَّ إِنِّي أَرَىٰ فِي الْمَنَامِ أَنِّي أَذْبَحُكَ",
        "rootWord": "س ع ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "سَعْي",
        "waznEnglish": "and strives",
        "waznTlit": "saʿī",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْأَسْفَلِينَ",
        "answer": "the lowest",
        "pcklId": "1",
        "rootWordId": 698,
        "tlit": "l-asfalīna",
        "frequency": "10",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "98",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " فَأَرَادُوا بِهِ كَيْدًا فَجَعَلْنَاهُمُ الْأَسْفَلِينَ",
        "rootWord": "س ف ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَسْفَل",
        "waznEnglish": "below",
        "waznTlit": "asfal",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "سَقِيمٌ",
        "answer": "sick",
        "pcklId": "0",
        "rootWordId": 703,
        "tlit": "saqīmun",
        "frequency": "2",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "89",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " فَقَالَ إِنِّي سَقِيمٌ",
        "rootWord": "س ق م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "س ق م",
        "waznEnglish": "sick",
        "waznTlit": "sīn qāf mīm",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "سَقِيمٌ",
        "answer": "(was) ill",
        "pcklId": "1",
        "rootWordId": 703,
        "tlit": "saqīmun",
        "frequency": "2",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "145",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " فَنَبَذْنَاهُ بِالْعَرَاءِ وَهُوَ سَقِيمٌ",
        "rootWord": "س ق م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "س ق م",
        "waznEnglish": "sick",
        "waznTlit": "sīn qāf mīm",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "سُلْطَانٍ",
        "answer": "authority",
        "pcklId": "28",
        "rootWordId": 713,
        "tlit": "sul'ṭānin",
        "frequency": "39",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "30",
        "wordnum": "6",
        "arabicAyah": " وَمَا كَانَ لَنَا عَلَيْكُمْ مِنْ سُلْطَانٍ بَلْ كُنْتُمْ قَوْمًا طَاغِينَ",
        "rootWord": "س ل ط",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "سُلْطَٰن",
        "waznEnglish": "surely He (would have) given them power",
        "waznTlit": "sul'ṭān",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "سُلْطَانٌ",
        "answer": "an authority",
        "pcklId": "29",
        "rootWordId": 713,
        "tlit": "sul'ṭānun",
        "frequency": "39",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "156",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " أَمْ لَكُمْ سُلْطَانٌ مُبِينٌ",
        "rootWord": "س ل ط",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "سُلْطَٰن",
        "waznEnglish": "surely He (would have) given them power",
        "waznTlit": "sul'ṭān",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "أَسْلَمَا",
        "answer": "both of them had submitted",
        "pcklId": "21",
        "rootWordId": 718,
        "tlit": "aslamā",
        "frequency": "140",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "103",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " فَلَمَّا أَسْلَمَا وَتَلَّهُ لِلْجَبِينِ",
        "rootWord": "س ل م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَسْلَمَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to submit",
        "waznTlit": "aslama",
        "waznType": "Verb (form IV)"
    },
    {
        "question": "سَلَامٌ",
        "answer": "Peace be",
        "pcklId": "55",
        "rootWordId": 718,
        "tlit": "salāmun",
        "frequency": "140",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "79",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " سَلَامٌ عَلَىٰ نُوحٍ فِي الْعَالَمِينَ",
        "rootWord": "س ل م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "سَلَٰم",
        "waznEnglish": "you pay",
        "waznTlit": "salām",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "سَلَامٌ",
        "answer": "Peace be",
        "pcklId": "56",
        "rootWordId": 718,
        "tlit": "salāmun",
        "frequency": "140",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "109",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " سَلَامٌ عَلَىٰ إِبْرَاهِيمَ",
        "rootWord": "س ل م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "سَلَٰم",
        "waznEnglish": "you pay",
        "waznTlit": "salām",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "سَلَامٌ",
        "answer": "Peace be",
        "pcklId": "57",
        "rootWordId": 718,
        "tlit": "salāmun",
        "frequency": "140",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "120",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " سَلَامٌ عَلَىٰ مُوسَىٰ وَهَارُونَ",
        "rootWord": "س ل م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "سَلَٰم",
        "waznEnglish": "you pay",
        "waznTlit": "salām",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "سَلَامٌ",
        "answer": "Peace be",
        "pcklId": "58",
        "rootWordId": 718,
        "tlit": "salāmun",
        "frequency": "140",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "130",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " سَلَامٌ عَلَىٰ إِلْ يَاسِينَ",
        "rootWord": "س ل م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "سَلَٰم",
        "waznEnglish": "you pay",
        "waznTlit": "salām",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَسَلَامٌ",
        "answer": "And peace be",
        "pcklId": "59",
        "rootWordId": 718,
        "tlit": "wasalāmun",
        "frequency": "140",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "181",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " وَسَلَامٌ عَلَى الْمُرْسَلِينَ",
        "rootWord": "س ل م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "سَلَٰم",
        "waznEnglish": "you pay",
        "waznTlit": "salām",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "سَلِيمٍ",
        "answer": "sound",
        "pcklId": "81",
        "rootWordId": 718,
        "tlit": "salīmin",
        "frequency": "140",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "84",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " إِذْ جَاءَ رَبَّهُ بِقَلْبٍ سَلِيمٍ",
        "rootWord": "س ل م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "سَلِيم",
        "waznEnglish": "you pay",
        "waznTlit": "salīm",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "مُسْتَسْلِمُونَ",
        "answer": "(will) surrender",
        "pcklId": "139",
        "rootWordId": 718,
        "tlit": "mus'taslimūna",
        "frequency": "140",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "26",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " بَلْ هُمُ الْيَوْمَ مُسْتَسْلِمُونَ",
        "rootWord": "س ل م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مُسْتَسْلِمُون",
        "waznEnglish": "you pay",
        "waznTlit": "mus'taslimūn",
        "waznType": "Active participle (form X)"
    },
    {
        "question": "يَسَّمَّعُونَ",
        "answer": "they may listen",
        "pcklId": "91",
        "rootWordId": 722,
        "tlit": "yassammaʿūna",
        "frequency": "185",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "8",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " لَا يَسَّمَّعُونَ إِلَى الْمَلَإِ الْأَعْلَىٰ وَيُقْذَفُونَ مِنْ كُلِّ جَانِبٍ",
        "rootWord": "س م ع",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "يَسَّمَّعُ",
        "waznEnglish": "to listen",
        "waznTlit": "yassammaʿu",
        "waznType": "Verb (form V)"
    },
    {
        "question": "السَّمَاوَاتِ",
        "answer": "(of) the heavens",
        "pcklId": "248",
        "rootWordId": 726,
        "tlit": "l-samāwāti",
        "frequency": "381",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "5",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " رَبُّ السَّمَاوَاتِ وَالْأَرْضِ وَمَا بَيْنَهُمَا وَرَبُّ الْمَشَارِقِ",
        "rootWord": "س م و",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "سَمَآء",
        "waznEnglish": "[I] (have) named her",
        "waznTlit": "samā",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "السَّمَاءَ",
        "answer": "the sky",
        "pcklId": "249",
        "rootWordId": 726,
        "tlit": "l-samāa",
        "frequency": "381",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "6",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّا زَيَّنَّا السَّمَاءَ الدُّنْيَا بِزِينَةٍ الْكَوَاكِبِ",
        "rootWord": "س م و",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "سَمَآء",
        "waznEnglish": "[I] (have) named her",
        "waznTlit": "samā",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "فَسَاهَمَ",
        "answer": "Then he drew lots",
        "pcklId": "0",
        "rootWordId": 735,
        "tlit": "fasāhama",
        "frequency": "1",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "141",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " فَسَاهَمَ فَكَانَ مِنَ الْمُدْحَضِينَ",
        "rootWord": "س ه م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "س ه م",
        "waznEnglish": "to draw",
        "waznTlit": "sīn hā mīm",
        "waznType": "Verb (form III)"
    },
    {
        "question": "فَسَاءَ",
        "answer": "then evil (will be)",
        "pcklId": "24",
        "rootWordId": 737,
        "tlit": "fasāa",
        "frequency": "167",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "177",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " فَإِذَا نَزَلَ بِسَاحَتِهِمْ فَسَاءَ صَبَاحُ الْمُنْذَرِينَ",
        "rootWord": "س و أ",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "سَآءَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to be evil",
        "waznTlit": "sāa",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "بِسَاحَتِهِمْ",
        "answer": "in their territory",
        "pcklId": "0",
        "rootWordId": 738,
        "tlit": "bisāḥatihim",
        "frequency": "1",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "177",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " فَإِذَا نَزَلَ بِسَاحَتِهِمْ فَسَاءَ صَبَاحُ الْمُنْذَرِينَ",
        "rootWord": "س و ح",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "س و ح",
        "waznEnglish": "in their territory",
        "waznTlit": "sīn wāw ḥā",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "سَوَاءِ",
        "answer": "(the) midst",
        "pcklId": "68",
        "rootWordId": 747,
        "tlit": "sawāi",
        "frequency": "83",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "55",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " فَاطَّلَعَ فَرَآهُ فِي سَوَاءِ الْجَحِيمِ",
        "rootWord": "س و ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "سَوَآء",
        "waznEnglish": "was leveled",
        "waznTlit": "sawā",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "شَجَرَةُ",
        "answer": "(the) tree",
        "pcklId": "21",
        "rootWordId": 757,
        "tlit": "shajaratu",
        "frequency": "27",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "62",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " أَذَٰلِكَ خَيْرٌ نُزُلًا أَمْ شَجَرَةُ الزَّقُّومِ",
        "rootWord": "ش ج ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "شَجَرَة",
        "waznEnglish": "arises",
        "waznTlit": "shajarat",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "شَجَرَةٌ",
        "answer": "(is) a tree",
        "pcklId": "22",
        "rootWordId": 757,
        "tlit": "shajaratun",
        "frequency": "27",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "64",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّهَا شَجَرَةٌ تَخْرُجُ فِي أَصْلِ الْجَحِيمِ",
        "rootWord": "ش ج ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "شَجَرَة",
        "waznEnglish": "arises",
        "waznTlit": "shajarat",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "شَجَرَةً",
        "answer": "a plant",
        "pcklId": "23",
        "rootWordId": 757,
        "tlit": "shajaratan",
        "frequency": "27",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "146",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " وَأَنْبَتْنَا عَلَيْهِ شَجَرَةً مِنْ يَقْطِينٍ",
        "rootWord": "ش ج ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "شَجَرَة",
        "waznEnglish": "arises",
        "waznTlit": "shajarat",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْمَشْحُونِ",
        "answer": "laden",
        "pcklId": "2",
        "rootWordId": 760,
        "tlit": "l-mashḥūni",
        "frequency": "3",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "140",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " إِذْ أَبَقَ إِلَى الْفُلْكِ الْمَشْحُونِ",
        "rootWord": "ش ح ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ش ح ن",
        "waznEnglish": "laden",
        "waznTlit": "shīn ḥā nūn",
        "waznType": "Passive participle"
    },
    {
        "question": "أَشَدُّ",
        "answer": "a stronger",
        "pcklId": "24",
        "rootWordId": 762,
        "tlit": "ashaddu",
        "frequency": "102",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "11",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " فَاسْتَفْتِهِمْ أَهُمْ أَشَدُّ خَلْقًا أَمْ مَنْ خَلَقْنَا",
        "rootWord": "ش د د",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَشَدّ",
        "waznEnglish": "and harden",
        "waznTlit": "ashadd",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "لِلشَّارِبِينَ",
        "answer": "for the drinkers",
        "pcklId": "35",
        "rootWordId": 763,
        "tlit": "lilshāribīna",
        "frequency": "39",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "46",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " بَيْضَاءَ لَذَّةٍ لِلشَّارِبِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ش ر ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "شَّٰرِبِين",
        "waznEnglish": "and drink",
        "waznTlit": "shāribīn",
        "waznType": "Active participle"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْمَشَارِقِ",
        "answer": "(of) each point of sunrise",
        "pcklId": "9",
        "rootWordId": 770,
        "tlit": "l-mashāriqi",
        "frequency": "17",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "5",
        "wordnum": "7",
        "arabicAyah": " رَبُّ السَّمَاوَاتِ وَالْأَرْضِ وَمَا بَيْنَهُمَا وَرَبُّ الْمَشَارِقِ",
        "rootWord": "ش ر ق",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مَشْرِق",
        "waznEnglish": "And (will) shine",
        "waznTlit": "mashriq",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "مُشْتَرِكُونَ",
        "answer": "(will be) sharers",
        "pcklId": "166",
        "rootWordId": 771,
        "tlit": "mush'tarikūna",
        "frequency": "168",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "33",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " فَإِنَّهُمْ يَوْمَئِذٍ فِي الْعَذَابِ مُشْتَرِكُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ش ر ك",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مُشْتَرِكُون",
        "waznEnglish": "and be a partner",
        "waznTlit": "mush'tarikūn",
        "waznType": "Active participle (form VIII)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الشَّيَاطِينِ",
        "answer": "(of) the devils",
        "pcklId": "68",
        "rootWordId": 776,
        "tlit": "l-shayāṭīni",
        "frequency": "88",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "65",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " طَلْعُهَا كَأَنَّهُ رُءُوسُ الشَّيَاطِينِ",
        "rootWord": "ش ط ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ش ط ن",
        "waznEnglish": "the Shaitaan",
        "waznTlit": "shīn ṭā nūn",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Proper noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "شَيْطَانٍ",
        "answer": "devil",
        "pcklId": "85",
        "rootWordId": 776,
        "tlit": "shayṭānin",
        "frequency": "88",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "7",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " وَحِفْظًا مِنْ كُلِّ شَيْطَانٍ مَارِدٍ",
        "rootWord": "ش ط ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ش ط ن",
        "waznEnglish": "the Shaitaan",
        "waznTlit": "shīn ṭā nūn",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "لِشَاعِرٍ",
        "answer": "for a poet",
        "pcklId": "29",
        "rootWordId": 778,
        "tlit": "lishāʿirin",
        "frequency": "40",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "36",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " وَيَقُولُونَ أَئِنَّا لَتَارِكُو آلِهَتِنَا لِشَاعِرٍ مَجْنُونٍ",
        "rootWord": "ش ع ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "شَاعِر",
        "waznEnglish": "they realize (it)",
        "waznTlit": "shāʿir",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "شِهَابٌ",
        "answer": "a burning flame",
        "pcklId": "2",
        "rootWordId": 800,
        "tlit": "shihābun",
        "frequency": "5",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "10",
        "wordnum": "6",
        "arabicAyah": " إِلَّا مَنْ خَطِفَ الْخَطْفَةَ فَأَتْبَعَهُ شِهَابٌ ثَاقِبٌ",
        "rootWord": "ش ه ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "شِهَاب",
        "waznEnglish": "a burning flame",
        "waznTlit": "shihāb",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "شَاهِدُونَ",
        "answer": "(were) witnesses",
        "pcklId": "149",
        "rootWordId": 801,
        "tlit": "shāhidūna",
        "frequency": "160",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "150",
        "wordnum": "6",
        "arabicAyah": " أَمْ خَلَقْنَا الْمَلَائِكَةَ إِنَاثًا وَهُمْ شَاهِدُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ش ه د",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "شَاهِد",
        "waznEnglish": "(were) witnessing",
        "waznTlit": "shāhid",
        "waznType": "Active participle (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "لَشَوْبًا",
        "answer": "(is) a mixture",
        "pcklId": "0",
        "rootWordId": 805,
        "tlit": "lashawban",
        "frequency": "1",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "67",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " ثُمَّ إِنَّ لَهُمْ عَلَيْهَا لَشَوْبًا مِنْ حَمِيمٍ",
        "rootWord": "ش و ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ش و ب",
        "waznEnglish": "(is) a mixture",
        "waznTlit": "shīn wāw bā",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "شَاءَ",
        "answer": "Allah wills",
        "pcklId": "174",
        "rootWordId": 810,
        "tlit": "shāa",
        "frequency": "519",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "102",
        "wordnum": "23",
        "arabicAyah": " قَالَ يَا أَبَتِ افْعَلْ مَا تُؤْمَرُ سَتَجِدُنِي إِنْ شَاءَ اللَّهُ مِنَ الصَّابِرِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ش ي أ",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "شَآءَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to will, to wish",
        "waznTlit": "shāa",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "شِيعَتِهِ",
        "answer": "his kind",
        "pcklId": "10",
        "rootWordId": 814,
        "tlit": "shīʿatihi",
        "frequency": "12",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "83",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " وَإِنَّ مِنْ شِيعَتِهِ لَإِبْرَاهِيمَ",
        "rootWord": "ش ي ع",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "شِيعَة",
        "waznEnglish": "(should) spread",
        "waznTlit": "shīʿat",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "صَبَاحُ",
        "answer": "(the) morning",
        "pcklId": "29",
        "rootWordId": 817,
        "tlit": "ṣabāḥu",
        "frequency": "45",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "177",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " فَإِذَا نَزَلَ بِسَاحَتِهِمْ فَسَاءَ صَبَاحُ الْمُنْذَرِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ص ب ح",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "صَبَاح",
        "waznEnglish": "seized them in the morning",
        "waznTlit": "ṣabāḥ",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "مُصْبِحِينَ",
        "answer": "(in the) morning",
        "pcklId": "42",
        "rootWordId": 817,
        "tlit": "muṣ'biḥīna",
        "frequency": "45",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "137",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " وَإِنَّكُمْ لَتَمُرُّونَ عَلَيْهِمْ مُصْبِحِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ص ب ح",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مُصْبِحِين",
        "waznEnglish": "seized them in the morning",
        "waznTlit": "muṣ'biḥīn",
        "waznType": "Active participle (form IV)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الصَّابِرِينَ",
        "answer": "the patient ones",
        "pcklId": "96",
        "rootWordId": 818,
        "tlit": "l-ṣābirīna",
        "frequency": "103",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "102",
        "wordnum": "26",
        "arabicAyah": " سَتَجِدُنِي إِنْ شَاءَ اللَّهُ مِنَ الصَّابِرِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ص ب ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "صَابِر",
        "waznEnglish": "we endure",
        "waznTlit": "ṣābir",
        "waznType": "Active participle (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَصَدَّقَ",
        "answer": "and confirmed",
        "pcklId": "17",
        "rootWordId": 830,
        "tlit": "waṣaddaqa",
        "frequency": "155",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "37",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " بَلْ جَاءَ بِالْحَقِّ وَصَدَّقَ الْمُرْسَلِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ص د ق",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "صَدَّقَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to accept truth, to admit, to confirm, to believe",
        "waznTlit": "ṣaddaqa",
        "waznType": "Verb (form II)"
    },
    {
        "question": "صَدَّقْتَ",
        "answer": "you have fulfilled",
        "pcklId": "18",
        "rootWordId": 830,
        "tlit": "ṣaddaqta",
        "frequency": "155",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "105",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " قَدْ صَدَّقْتَ الرُّؤْيَا إِنَّا كَذَٰلِكَ نَجْزِي الْمُحْسِنِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ص د ق",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "صَدَّقَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to accept truth, to admit, to confirm, to believe",
        "waznTlit": "ṣaddaqa",
        "waznType": "Verb (form II)"
    },
    {
        "question": "صَادِقِينَ",
        "answer": "truthful",
        "pcklId": "113",
        "rootWordId": 830,
        "tlit": "ṣādiqīna",
        "frequency": "155",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "157",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " فَأْتُوا بِكِتَابِكُمْ إِنْ كُنْتُمْ صَادِقِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ص د ق",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "صَادِق",
        "waznEnglish": "are true",
        "waznTlit": "ṣādiq",
        "waznType": "Active participle"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْمُصَدِّقِينَ",
        "answer": "those who believe",
        "pcklId": "142",
        "rootWordId": 830,
        "tlit": "l-muṣadiqīna",
        "frequency": "155",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "52",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " يَقُولُ أَإِنَّكَ لَمِنَ الْمُصَدِّقِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ص د ق",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مُصَدِّق",
        "waznEnglish": "are true",
        "waznTlit": "muṣaddiq",
        "waznType": "Active participle (form II) (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "صِرَاطِ",
        "answer": "(the) Path",
        "pcklId": "34",
        "rootWordId": 836,
        "tlit": "ṣirāṭi",
        "frequency": "45",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "23",
        "wordnum": "6",
        "arabicAyah": " مِنْ دُونِ اللَّهِ فَاهْدُوهُمْ إِلَىٰ صِرَاطِ الْجَحِيمِ",
        "rootWord": "ص ر ط",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ص ر ط",
        "waznEnglish": "(to) the path",
        "waznTlit": "ṣād rā ṭā",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "الصِّرَاطَ",
        "answer": "(to) the Path",
        "pcklId": "35",
        "rootWordId": 836,
        "tlit": "l-ṣirāṭa",
        "frequency": "45",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "118",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " وَهَدَيْنَاهُمَا الصِّرَاطَ الْمُسْتَقِيمَ",
        "rootWord": "ص ر ط",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ص ر ط",
        "waznEnglish": "(to) the path",
        "waznTlit": "ṣād rā ṭā",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "صَفًّا",
        "answer": "(in) rows",
        "pcklId": "3",
        "rootWordId": 849,
        "tlit": "ṣaffan",
        "frequency": "14",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "1",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " وَالصَّافَّاتِ صَفًّا",
        "rootWord": "ص ف ف",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "صَفّ",
        "waznEnglish": "(when) lined up",
        "waznTlit": "ṣaff",
        "waznType": "Verbal noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَالصَّافَّاتِ",
        "answer": "By those lined",
        "pcklId": "9",
        "rootWordId": 849,
        "tlit": "wal-ṣāfāti",
        "frequency": "14",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "1",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " وَالصَّافَّاتِ صَفًّا",
        "rootWord": "ص ف ف",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "صَآفَّٰت",
        "waznEnglish": "(when) lined up",
        "waznTlit": "ṣāffāt",
        "waznType": "Active participle"
    },
    {
        "question": "الصَّافُّونَ",
        "answer": "stand in rows",
        "pcklId": "11",
        "rootWordId": 849,
        "tlit": "l-ṣāfūna",
        "frequency": "14",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "165",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " وَإِنَّا لَنَحْنُ الصَّافُّونَ",
        "rootWord": "ص ف ف",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "صَّآفُّون",
        "waznEnglish": "(when) lined up",
        "waznTlit": "ṣāffūn",
        "waznType": "Active participle"
    },
    {
        "question": "أَصْطَفَى",
        "answer": "Has He chosen",
        "pcklId": "12",
        "rootWordId": 851,
        "tlit": "aṣṭafā",
        "frequency": "17",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "153",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " أَصْطَفَى الْبَنَاتِ عَلَى الْبَنِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ص ف و",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ٱصْطَفَىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "to choose",
        "waznTlit": "iṣ'ṭafā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form VIII)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الصَّالِحِينَ",
        "answer": "the righteous",
        "pcklId": "88",
        "rootWordId": 854,
        "tlit": "l-ṣāliḥīna",
        "frequency": "180",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "100",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " رَبِّ هَبْ لِي مِنَ الصَّالِحِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ص ل ح",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "صَٰلِح",
        "waznEnglish": "(were) righteous",
        "waznTlit": "ṣāliḥ",
        "waznType": "Active participle (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الصَّالِحِينَ",
        "answer": "the righteous",
        "pcklId": "89",
        "rootWordId": 854,
        "tlit": "l-ṣāliḥīna",
        "frequency": "180",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "112",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " وَبَشَّرْنَاهُ بِإِسْحَاقَ نَبِيًّا مِنَ الصَّالِحِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ص ل ح",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "صَٰلِح",
        "waznEnglish": "(were) righteous",
        "waznTlit": "ṣāliḥ",
        "waznType": "Active participle (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "صَالِ",
        "answer": "(is) to burn",
        "pcklId": "21",
        "rootWordId": 858,
        "tlit": "ṣāli",
        "frequency": "25",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "163",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " إِلَّا مَنْ هُوَ صَالِ الْجَحِيمِ",
        "rootWord": "ص ل ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "صَال",
        "waznEnglish": "and they will be burned",
        "waznTlit": "ṣāl",
        "waznType": "Active participle"
    },
    {
        "question": "ضَرْبًا",
        "answer": "striking",
        "pcklId": "56",
        "rootWordId": 884,
        "tlit": "ḍarban",
        "frequency": "58",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "93",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " فَرَاغَ عَلَيْهِمْ ضَرْبًا بِالْيَمِينِ",
        "rootWord": "ض ر ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ضَرْب",
        "waznEnglish": "set forth",
        "waznTlit": "ḍarb",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "ضَلَّ",
        "answer": "went astray",
        "pcklId": "42",
        "rootWordId": 891,
        "tlit": "ḍalla",
        "frequency": "191",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "71",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " وَلَقَدْ ضَلَّ قَبْلَهُمْ أَكْثَرُ الْأَوَّلِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ض ل ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ضَلَّ",
        "waznEnglish": "to go astray, to err, to lose",
        "waznTlit": "ḍalla",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "ضَالِّينَ",
        "answer": "astray",
        "pcklId": "179",
        "rootWordId": 891,
        "tlit": "ḍāllīna",
        "frequency": "191",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "69",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّهُمْ أَلْفَوْا آبَاءَهُمْ ضَالِّينَ",
        "rootWord": "ض ل ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ضَآلّ",
        "waznEnglish": "he went astray (from)",
        "waznTlit": "ḍāll",
        "waznType": "Active participle (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الطَّرْفِ",
        "answer": "(will be) companions of modest gaze",
        "pcklId": "2",
        "rootWordId": 908,
        "tlit": "l-ṭarfi",
        "frequency": "11",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "48",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " وَعِنْدَهُمْ قَاصِرَاتُ الطَّرْفِ عِينٌ",
        "rootWord": "ط ر ف",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "طَرْف",
        "waznEnglish": "their gaze",
        "waznTlit": "ṭarf",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "طَاغِينَ",
        "answer": "transgressing",
        "pcklId": "36",
        "rootWordId": 913,
        "tlit": "ṭāghīna",
        "frequency": "39",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "30",
        "wordnum": "10",
        "arabicAyah": " وَمَا كَانَ لَنَا عَلَيْكُمْ مِنْ سُلْطَانٍ بَلْ كُنْتُمْ قَوْمًا طَاغِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ط غ ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "طَٰغِين",
        "waznEnglish": "transgress",
        "waznTlit": "ṭāghīn",
        "waznType": "Active participle (Adjective)"
    },
    {
        "question": "فَاطَّلَعَ",
        "answer": "Then he (will) look",
        "pcklId": "7",
        "rootWordId": 920,
        "tlit": "fa-iṭṭalaʿa",
        "frequency": "19",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "55",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " فَاطَّلَعَ فَرَآهُ فِي سَوَاءِ الْجَحِيمِ",
        "rootWord": "ط ل ع",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "طَّلَعَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to look",
        "waznTlit": "ṭalaʿa",
        "waznType": "Verb (form VIII)"
    },
    {
        "question": "طَلْعُهَا",
        "answer": "Its emerging fruit",
        "pcklId": "12",
        "rootWordId": 920,
        "tlit": "ṭalʿuhā",
        "frequency": "19",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "65",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " طَلْعُهَا كَأَنَّهُ رُءُوسُ الشَّيَاطِينِ",
        "rootWord": "ط ل ع",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "طَلْع",
        "waznEnglish": "it rose",
        "waznTlit": "ṭalʿ",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "مُطَّلِعُونَ",
        "answer": "be looking",
        "pcklId": "18",
        "rootWordId": 920,
        "tlit": "muṭṭaliʿūna",
        "frequency": "19",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "54",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " قَالَ هَلْ أَنْتُمْ مُطَّلِعُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ط ل ع",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مُّطَّلِعُون",
        "waznEnglish": "it rose",
        "waznTlit": "muṭṭaliʿūn",
        "waznType": "Active participle (form VIII)"
    },
    {
        "question": "يُطَافُ",
        "answer": "Will be circulated",
        "pcklId": "0",
        "rootWordId": 932,
        "tlit": "yuṭāfu",
        "frequency": "41",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "45",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " يُطَافُ عَلَيْهِمْ بِكَأْسٍ مِنْ مَعِينٍ",
        "rootWord": "ط و ف",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "طَافَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to circulate, to go around",
        "waznTlit": "ṭāfa",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "طِينٍ",
        "answer": "a clay",
        "pcklId": "8",
        "rootWordId": 938,
        "tlit": "ṭīnin",
        "frequency": "12",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "11",
        "wordnum": "11",
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّا خَلَقْنَاهُمْ مِنْ طِينٍ لَازِبٍ",
        "rootWord": "ط ي ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ط ي ن",
        "waznEnglish": "[the] clay",
        "waznTlit": "ṭā yā nūn",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "ظَلَمُوا",
        "answer": "wronged",
        "pcklId": "95",
        "rootWordId": 942,
        "tlit": "ẓalamū",
        "frequency": "315",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "22",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " احْشُرُوا الَّذِينَ ظَلَمُوا وَأَزْوَاجَهُمْ وَمَا كَانُوا يَعْبُدُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ظ ل م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ظَلَمَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to oppress, to wrong",
        "waznTlit": "ẓalama",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "لِلظَّالِمِينَ",
        "answer": "for the wrongdoers",
        "pcklId": "263",
        "rootWordId": 942,
        "tlit": "lilẓẓālimīna",
        "frequency": "315",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "63",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّا جَعَلْنَاهَا فِتْنَةً لِلظَّالِمِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ظ ل م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ظَالِم",
        "waznEnglish": "[you] have wronged",
        "waznTlit": "ẓālim",
        "waznType": "Active participle (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَظَالِمٌ",
        "answer": "and unjust",
        "pcklId": "264",
        "rootWordId": 942,
        "tlit": "waẓālimun",
        "frequency": "315",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "113",
        "wordnum": "8",
        "arabicAyah": " وَمِنْ ذُرِّيَّتِهِمَا مُحْسِنٌ وَظَالِمٌ لِنَفْسِهِ مُبِينٌ",
        "rootWord": "ظ ل م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ظَالِم",
        "waznEnglish": "[you] have wronged",
        "waznTlit": "ẓālim",
        "waznType": "Active participle (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "ظَنُّكُمْ",
        "answer": "(do) you think",
        "pcklId": "57",
        "rootWordId": 944,
        "tlit": "ẓannukum",
        "frequency": "69",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "87",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " فَمَا ظَنُّكُمْ بِرَبِّ الْعَالَمِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ظ ن ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ظَنّ",
        "waznEnglish": "believe",
        "waznTlit": "ẓann",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "يَعْبُدُونَ",
        "answer": "worship",
        "pcklId": "91",
        "rootWordId": 948,
        "tlit": "yaʿbudūna",
        "frequency": "275",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "22",
        "wordnum": "7",
        "arabicAyah": " احْشُرُوا الَّذِينَ ظَلَمُوا وَأَزْوَاجَهُمْ وَمَا كَانُوا يَعْبُدُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ع ب د",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "عَبَدَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to worship",
        "waznTlit": "ʿabada",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "تَعْبُدُونَ",
        "answer": "you worship",
        "pcklId": "92",
        "rootWordId": 948,
        "tlit": "taʿbudūna",
        "frequency": "275",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "85",
        "wordnum": "6",
        "arabicAyah": " إِذْ قَالَ لِأَبِيهِ وَقَوْمِهِ مَاذَا تَعْبُدُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ع ب د",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "عَبَدَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to worship",
        "waznTlit": "ʿabada",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "أَتَعْبُدُونَ",
        "answer": "Do you worship",
        "pcklId": "93",
        "rootWordId": 948,
        "tlit": "ataʿbudūna",
        "frequency": "275",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "95",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " قَالَ أَتَعْبُدُونَ مَا تَنْحِتُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ع ب د",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "عَبَدَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to worship",
        "waznTlit": "ʿabada",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "تَعْبُدُونَ",
        "answer": "you worship",
        "pcklId": "94",
        "rootWordId": 948,
        "tlit": "taʿbudūna",
        "frequency": "275",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "161",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " فَإِنَّكُمْ وَمَا تَعْبُدُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ع ب د",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "عَبَدَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to worship",
        "waznTlit": "ʿabada",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "عِبَادَ",
        "answer": "(the) slaves",
        "pcklId": "209",
        "rootWordId": 948,
        "tlit": "ʿibāda",
        "frequency": "275",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "40",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " إِلَّا عِبَادَ اللَّهِ الْمُخْلَصِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ع ب د",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "عَبْد",
        "waznEnglish": "we worship",
        "waznTlit": "ʿabd",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "عِبَادَ",
        "answer": "(the) slaves",
        "pcklId": "210",
        "rootWordId": 948,
        "tlit": "ʿibāda",
        "frequency": "275",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "74",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " إِلَّا عِبَادَ اللَّهِ الْمُخْلَصِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ع ب د",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "عَبْد",
        "waznEnglish": "we worship",
        "waznTlit": "ʿabd",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "عِبَادِنَا",
        "answer": "Our slaves",
        "pcklId": "211",
        "rootWordId": 948,
        "tlit": "ʿibādinā",
        "frequency": "275",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "81",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّهُ مِنْ عِبَادِنَا الْمُؤْمِنِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ع ب د",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "عَبْد",
        "waznEnglish": "we worship",
        "waznTlit": "ʿabd",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "عِبَادِنَا",
        "answer": "Our slaves",
        "pcklId": "212",
        "rootWordId": 948,
        "tlit": "ʿibādinā",
        "frequency": "275",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "111",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّهُ مِنْ عِبَادِنَا الْمُؤْمِنِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ع ب د",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "عَبْد",
        "waznEnglish": "we worship",
        "waznTlit": "ʿabd",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "عِبَادِنَا",
        "answer": "Our slaves",
        "pcklId": "213",
        "rootWordId": 948,
        "tlit": "ʿibādinā",
        "frequency": "275",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "122",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّهُمَا مِنْ عِبَادِنَا الْمُؤْمِنِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ع ب د",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "عَبْد",
        "waznEnglish": "we worship",
        "waznTlit": "ʿabd",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "عِبَادَ",
        "answer": "(the) slaves",
        "pcklId": "214",
        "rootWordId": 948,
        "tlit": "ʿibāda",
        "frequency": "275",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "128",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " إِلَّا عِبَادَ اللَّهِ الْمُخْلَصِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ع ب د",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "عَبْد",
        "waznEnglish": "we worship",
        "waznTlit": "ʿabd",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "عِبَادِنَا",
        "answer": "Our slaves",
        "pcklId": "215",
        "rootWordId": 948,
        "tlit": "ʿibādinā",
        "frequency": "275",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "132",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّهُ مِنْ عِبَادِنَا الْمُؤْمِنِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ع ب د",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "عَبْد",
        "waznEnglish": "we worship",
        "waznTlit": "ʿabd",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "عِبَادَ",
        "answer": "(the) slaves",
        "pcklId": "216",
        "rootWordId": 948,
        "tlit": "ʿibāda",
        "frequency": "275",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "160",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " إِلَّا عِبَادَ اللَّهِ الْمُخْلَصِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ع ب د",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "عَبْد",
        "waznEnglish": "we worship",
        "waznTlit": "ʿabd",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "عِبَادَ",
        "answer": "slaves",
        "pcklId": "217",
        "rootWordId": 948,
        "tlit": "ʿibāda",
        "frequency": "275",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "169",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " لَكُنَّا عِبَادَ اللَّهِ الْمُخْلَصِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ع ب د",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "عَبْد",
        "waznEnglish": "we worship",
        "waznTlit": "ʿabd",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "لِعِبَادِنَا",
        "answer": "for Our slaves",
        "pcklId": "218",
        "rootWordId": 948,
        "tlit": "liʿibādinā",
        "frequency": "275",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "171",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " وَلَقَدْ سَبَقَتْ كَلِمَتُنَا لِعِبَادِنَا الْمُرْسَلِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ع ب د",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "عَبْد",
        "waznEnglish": "we worship",
        "waznTlit": "ʿabd",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "عَجِبْتَ",
        "answer": "you wonder",
        "pcklId": "4",
        "rootWordId": 959,
        "tlit": "ʿajib'ta",
        "frequency": "27",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "12",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " بَلْ عَجِبْتَ وَيَسْخَرُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ع ج ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "عَجِبُ",
        "waznEnglish": "to wonder, to be amazed, to be astonished",
        "waznTlit": "ʿajibu",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "عَجُوزًا",
        "answer": "an old woman",
        "pcklId": "9",
        "rootWordId": 960,
        "tlit": "ʿajūzan",
        "frequency": "26",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "135",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " إِلَّا عَجُوزًا فِي الْغَابِرِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ع ج ز",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "عَجُوز",
        "waznEnglish": "Am I unable",
        "waznTlit": "ʿajūz",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "يَسْتَعْجِلُونَ",
        "answer": "they hasten",
        "pcklId": "25",
        "rootWordId": 962,
        "tlit": "yastaʿjilūna",
        "frequency": "47",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "176",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " أَفَبِعَذَابِنَا يَسْتَعْجِلُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ع ج ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ٱسْتَعْجَلَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to seek to hasten",
        "waznTlit": "is'taʿjala",
        "waznType": "Verb (form X)"
    },
    {
        "question": "عَذَابٌ",
        "answer": "(is) a punishment",
        "pcklId": "259",
        "rootWordId": 968,
        "tlit": "ʿadhābun",
        "frequency": "373",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "9",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " دُحُورًا وَلَهُمْ عَذَابٌ وَاصِبٌ",
        "rootWord": "ع ذ ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "عَذَاب",
        "waznEnglish": "and He will punish",
        "waznTlit": "ʿadhāb",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْعَذَابِ",
        "answer": "the punishment",
        "pcklId": "260",
        "rootWordId": 968,
        "tlit": "l-ʿadhābi",
        "frequency": "373",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "33",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " فَإِنَّهُمْ يَوْمَئِذٍ فِي الْعَذَابِ مُشْتَرِكُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ع ذ ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "عَذَاب",
        "waznEnglish": "and He will punish",
        "waznTlit": "ʿadhāb",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْعَذَابِ",
        "answer": "the punishment",
        "pcklId": "261",
        "rootWordId": 968,
        "tlit": "l-ʿadhābi",
        "frequency": "373",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "38",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّكُمْ لَذَائِقُو الْعَذَابِ الْأَلِيمِ",
        "rootWord": "ع ذ ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "عَذَاب",
        "waznEnglish": "and He will punish",
        "waznTlit": "ʿadhāb",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "أَفَبِعَذَابِنَا",
        "answer": "Then is (it) for Our punishment",
        "pcklId": "262",
        "rootWordId": 968,
        "tlit": "afabiʿadhābinā",
        "frequency": "373",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "176",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " أَفَبِعَذَابِنَا يَسْتَعْجِلُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ع ذ ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "عَذَاب",
        "waznEnglish": "and He will punish",
        "waznTlit": "ʿadhāb",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "بِمُعَذَّبِينَ",
        "answer": "will be punished",
        "pcklId": "372",
        "rootWordId": 968,
        "tlit": "bimuʿadhabīna",
        "frequency": "373",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "59",
        "wordnum": "6",
        "arabicAyah": " إِلَّا مَوْتَتَنَا الْأُولَىٰ وَمَا نَحْنُ بِمُعَذَّبِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ع ذ ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مُعَذَّبِين",
        "waznEnglish": "and He will punish",
        "waznTlit": "muʿadhabīn",
        "waznType": "Passive participle (form II)"
    },
    {
        "question": "بِالْعَرَاءِ",
        "answer": "onto the open shore",
        "pcklId": "1",
        "rootWordId": 979,
        "tlit": "bil-ʿarāi",
        "frequency": "3",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "145",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " فَنَبَذْنَاهُ بِالْعَرَاءِ وَهُوَ سَقِيمٌ",
        "rootWord": "ع ر ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "عَرَآء",
        "waznEnglish": "you will be unclothed",
        "waznTlit": "ʿarā",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْعِزَّةِ",
        "answer": "(of) Honor",
        "pcklId": "115",
        "rootWordId": 982,
        "tlit": "l-ʿizati",
        "frequency": "119",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "180",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " سُبْحَانَ رَبِّكَ رَبِّ الْعِزَّةِ عَمَّا يَصِفُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ع ز ز",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "عِزَّة",
        "waznEnglish": "and he overpowered me",
        "waznTlit": "ʿizzat",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْعَظِيمُ",
        "answer": "great",
        "pcklId": "80",
        "rootWordId": 1005,
        "tlit": "l-ʿaẓīmu",
        "frequency": "128",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "60",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّ هَٰذَا لَهُوَ الْفَوْزُ الْعَظِيمُ",
        "rootWord": "ع ظ م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "عَظِيم",
        "waznEnglish": "honors",
        "waznTlit": "ʿaẓīm",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Adjective)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْعَظِيمِ",
        "answer": "the great",
        "pcklId": "81",
        "rootWordId": 1005,
        "tlit": "l-ʿaẓīmi",
        "frequency": "128",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "76",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " وَنَجَّيْنَاهُ وَأَهْلَهُ مِنَ الْكَرْبِ الْعَظِيمِ",
        "rootWord": "ع ظ م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "عَظِيم",
        "waznEnglish": "honors",
        "waznTlit": "ʿaẓīm",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Adjective)"
    },
    {
        "question": "عَظِيمٍ",
        "answer": "great",
        "pcklId": "82",
        "rootWordId": 1005,
        "tlit": "ʿaẓīmin",
        "frequency": "128",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "107",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " وَفَدَيْنَاهُ بِذِبْحٍ عَظِيمٍ",
        "rootWord": "ع ظ م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "عَظِيم",
        "waznEnglish": "honors",
        "waznTlit": "ʿaẓīm",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Adjective)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْعَظِيمِ",
        "answer": "the great",
        "pcklId": "83",
        "rootWordId": 1005,
        "tlit": "l-ʿaẓīmi",
        "frequency": "128",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "115",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " وَنَجَّيْنَاهُمَا وَقَوْمَهُمَا مِنَ الْكَرْبِ الْعَظِيمِ",
        "rootWord": "ع ظ م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "عَظِيم",
        "waznEnglish": "honors",
        "waznTlit": "ʿaẓīm",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Adjective)"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَعِظَامًا",
        "answer": "and bones",
        "pcklId": "122",
        "rootWordId": 1005,
        "tlit": "waʿiẓāman",
        "frequency": "128",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "16",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " أَإِذَا مِتْنَا وَكُنَّا تُرَابًا وَعِظَامًا أَإِنَّا لَمَبْعُوثُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ع ظ م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "عَظِيم",
        "waznEnglish": "honors",
        "waznTlit": "ʿaẓīm",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَعِظَامًا",
        "answer": "and bones",
        "pcklId": "123",
        "rootWordId": 1005,
        "tlit": "waʿiẓāman",
        "frequency": "128",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "53",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " أَإِذَا مِتْنَا وَكُنَّا تُرَابًا وَعِظَامًا أَإِنَّا لَمَدِينُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ع ظ م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "عَظِيم",
        "waznEnglish": "honors",
        "waznTlit": "ʿaẓīm",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "عَاقِبَةُ",
        "answer": "(the) end",
        "pcklId": "34",
        "rootWordId": 1009,
        "tlit": "ʿāqibatu",
        "frequency": "80",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "73",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " فَانْظُرْ كَيْفَ كَانَ عَاقِبَةُ الْمُنْذَرِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ع ق ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "عَٰقِبَة",
        "waznEnglish": "look back",
        "waznTlit": "ʿāqibat",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "تَعْقِلُونَ",
        "answer": "you use reason",
        "pcklId": "40",
        "rootWordId": 1012,
        "tlit": "taʿqilūna",
        "frequency": "49",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "138",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " وَبِاللَّيْلِ أَفَلَا تَعْقِلُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ع ق ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ع ق ل",
        "waznEnglish": "to understand, to reason",
        "waznTlit": "ʿayn qāf lām",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "عَلِمَتِ",
        "answer": "know",
        "pcklId": "297",
        "rootWordId": 1016,
        "tlit": "ʿalimati",
        "frequency": "854",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "158",
        "wordnum": "7",
        "arabicAyah": " وَلَقَدْ عَلِمَتِ الْجِنَّةُ إِنَّهُمْ لَمُحْضَرُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ع ل م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "عَلِمَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to know",
        "waznTlit": "ʿalima",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "يَعْلَمُونَ",
        "answer": "they will know",
        "pcklId": "298",
        "rootWordId": 1016,
        "tlit": "yaʿlamūna",
        "frequency": "854",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "170",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " فَكَفَرُوا بِهِ فَسَوْفَ يَعْلَمُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ع ل م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "عَلِمَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to know",
        "waznTlit": "ʿalima",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْعَالَمِينَ",
        "answer": "the worlds",
        "pcklId": "529",
        "rootWordId": 1016,
        "tlit": "l-ʿālamīna",
        "frequency": "854",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "79",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " سَلَامٌ عَلَىٰ نُوحٍ فِي الْعَالَمِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ع ل م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "عَٰلَمِين",
        "waznEnglish": "they know",
        "waznTlit": "ʿālamīn",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْعَالَمِينَ",
        "answer": "(of) the worlds",
        "pcklId": "530",
        "rootWordId": 1016,
        "tlit": "l-ʿālamīna",
        "frequency": "854",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "87",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " فَمَا ظَنُّكُمْ بِرَبِّ الْعَالَمِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ع ل م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "عَٰلَمِين",
        "waznEnglish": "they know",
        "waznTlit": "ʿālamīn",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْعَالَمِينَ",
        "answer": "(of) the worlds",
        "pcklId": "531",
        "rootWordId": 1016,
        "tlit": "l-ʿālamīna",
        "frequency": "854",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "182",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " وَالْحَمْدُ لِلَّهِ رَبِّ الْعَالَمِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ع ل م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "عَٰلَمِين",
        "waznEnglish": "they know",
        "waznTlit": "ʿālamīn",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "مَعْلُومٌ",
        "answer": "determined",
        "pcklId": "847",
        "rootWordId": 1016,
        "tlit": "maʿlūmun",
        "frequency": "854",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "41",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " أُولَٰئِكَ لَهُمْ رِزْقٌ مَعْلُومٌ",
        "rootWord": "ع ل م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مَّعْلُوم",
        "waznEnglish": "they know",
        "waznTlit": "maʿlūm",
        "waznType": "Passive participle (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "مَعْلُومٌ",
        "answer": "known",
        "pcklId": "848",
        "rootWordId": 1016,
        "tlit": "maʿlūmun",
        "frequency": "854",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "164",
        "wordnum": "6",
        "arabicAyah": " وَمَا مِنَّا إِلَّا لَهُ مَقَامٌ مَعْلُومٌ",
        "rootWord": "ع ل م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مَّعْلُوم",
        "waznEnglish": "they know",
        "waznTlit": "maʿlūm",
        "waznType": "Passive participle (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْأَعْلَىٰ",
        "answer": "[the] exalted",
        "pcklId": "34",
        "rootWordId": 1018,
        "tlit": "l-aʿlā",
        "frequency": "70",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "8",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " لَا يَسَّمَّعُونَ إِلَى الْمَلَإِ الْأَعْلَىٰ وَيُقْذَفُونَ مِنْ كُلِّ جَانِبٍ",
        "rootWord": "ع ل و",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَعْلَىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "and Exalted",
        "waznTlit": "aʿlā",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "تَعْمَلُونَ",
        "answer": "do",
        "pcklId": "201",
        "rootWordId": 1022,
        "tlit": "taʿmalūna",
        "frequency": "360",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "39",
        "wordnum": "6",
        "arabicAyah": " وَمَا تُجْزَوْنَ إِلَّا مَا كُنْتُمْ تَعْمَلُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ع م ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "عَمِلَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to do, to work",
        "waznTlit": "ʿamila",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "فَلْيَعْمَلِ",
        "answer": "let work",
        "pcklId": "202",
        "rootWordId": 1022,
        "tlit": "falyaʿmali",
        "frequency": "360",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "61",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " لِمِثْلِ هَٰذَا فَلْيَعْمَلِ الْعَامِلُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ع م ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "عَمِلَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to do, to work",
        "waznTlit": "ʿamila",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "تَعْمَلُونَ",
        "answer": "you make",
        "pcklId": "203",
        "rootWordId": 1022,
        "tlit": "taʿmalūna",
        "frequency": "360",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "96",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " وَاللَّهُ خَلَقَكُمْ وَمَا تَعْمَلُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ع م ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "عَمِلَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to do, to work",
        "waznTlit": "ʿamila",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْعَامِلُونَ",
        "answer": "the workers",
        "pcklId": "355",
        "rootWordId": 1022,
        "tlit": "l-ʿāmilūna",
        "frequency": "360",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "61",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " لِمِثْلِ هَٰذَا فَلْيَعْمَلِ الْعَامِلُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ع م ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "عَٰمِل",
        "waznEnglish": "and do",
        "waznTlit": "ʿāmil",
        "waznType": "Active participle"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَعِنْدَهُمْ",
        "answer": "And with them",
        "pcklId": "115",
        "rootWordId": 1028,
        "tlit": "waʿindahum",
        "frequency": "201",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "48",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " وَعِنْدَهُمْ قَاصِرَاتُ الطَّرْفِ عِينٌ",
        "rootWord": "ع ن د",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "عِند",
        "waznEnglish": "with",
        "waznTlit": "ʿind",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Location adverb)"
    },
    {
        "question": "عِنْدَنَا",
        "answer": "we had",
        "pcklId": "116",
        "rootWordId": 1028,
        "tlit": "ʿindanā",
        "frequency": "201",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "168",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " لَوْ أَنَّ عِنْدَنَا ذِكْرًا مِنَ الْأَوَّلِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ع ن د",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "عِند",
        "waznEnglish": "with",
        "waznTlit": "ʿind",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Location adverb)"
    },
    {
        "question": "عِينٌ",
        "answer": "(having) beautiful eyes",
        "pcklId": "0",
        "rootWordId": 1046,
        "tlit": "ʿīnun",
        "frequency": "65",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "48",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " وَعِنْدَهُمْ قَاصِرَاتُ الطَّرْفِ عِينٌ",
        "rootWord": "ع ي ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "عِين",
        "waznEnglish": "(having) beautiful eyes",
        "waznTlit": "ʿīn",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "مَعِينٍ",
        "answer": "a flowing spring",
        "pcklId": "62",
        "rootWordId": 1046,
        "tlit": "maʿīnin",
        "frequency": "65",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "45",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " يُطَافُ عَلَيْهِمْ بِكَأْسٍ مِنْ مَعِينٍ",
        "rootWord": "ع ي ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مَّعِين",
        "waznEnglish": "(having) beautiful eyes",
        "waznTlit": "maʿīn",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْغَابِرِينَ",
        "answer": "those who remained behind",
        "pcklId": "7",
        "rootWordId": 1048,
        "tlit": "l-ghābirīna",
        "frequency": "8",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "135",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " إِلَّا عَجُوزًا فِي الْغَابِرِينَ",
        "rootWord": "غ ب ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "غَٰبِرِين",
        "waznEnglish": "(will be) dust",
        "waznTlit": "ghābirīn",
        "waznType": "Active participle"
    },
    {
        "question": "أَغْرَقْنَا",
        "answer": "We drowned",
        "pcklId": "14",
        "rootWordId": 1057,
        "tlit": "aghraqnā",
        "frequency": "23",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "82",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " ثُمَّ أَغْرَقْنَا الْآخَرِينَ",
        "rootWord": "غ ر ق",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أُغْرِقُ",
        "waznEnglish": "to drown",
        "waznTlit": "ugh'riqu",
        "waznType": "Verb (form IV)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْغَالِبِينَ",
        "answer": "the victors",
        "pcklId": "28",
        "rootWordId": 1073,
        "tlit": "l-ghālibīna",
        "frequency": "31",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "116",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " وَنَصَرْنَاهُمْ فَكَانُوا هُمُ الْغَالِبِينَ",
        "rootWord": "غ ل ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "غَالِب",
        "waznEnglish": "overcame",
        "waznTlit": "ghālib",
        "waznType": "Active participle"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْغَالِبُونَ",
        "answer": "(will be) those who overcome",
        "pcklId": "29",
        "rootWordId": 1073,
        "tlit": "l-ghālibūna",
        "frequency": "31",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "173",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " وَإِنَّ جُنْدَنَا لَهُمُ الْغَالِبُونَ",
        "rootWord": "غ ل ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "غَالِب",
        "waznEnglish": "overcame",
        "waznTlit": "ghālib",
        "waznType": "Active participle"
    },
    {
        "question": "بِغُلَامٍ",
        "answer": "of a boy",
        "pcklId": "10",
        "rootWordId": 1078,
        "tlit": "bighulāmin",
        "frequency": "13",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "101",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " فَبَشَّرْنَاهُ بِغُلَامٍ حَلِيمٍ",
        "rootWord": "غ ل م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "غ ل م",
        "waznEnglish": "a son",
        "waznTlit": "ghayn lām mīm",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "غَوْلٌ",
        "answer": "(is) bad effect",
        "pcklId": "0",
        "rootWordId": 1091,
        "tlit": "ghawlun",
        "frequency": "1",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "47",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " لَا فِيهَا غَوْلٌ وَلَا هُمْ عَنْهَا يُنْزَفُونَ",
        "rootWord": "غ و ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "غ و ل",
        "waznEnglish": "(is) bad effect",
        "waznTlit": "ghayn wāw lām",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "فَأَغْوَيْنَاكُمْ",
        "answer": "So we led you astray",
        "pcklId": "9",
        "rootWordId": 1092,
        "tlit": "fa-aghwaynākum",
        "frequency": "22",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "32",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " فَأَغْوَيْنَاكُمْ إِنَّا كُنَّا غَاوِينَ",
        "rootWord": "غ و ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَغْوَيْ",
        "waznEnglish": "to mislead, to lead astray",
        "waznTlit": "aghway",
        "waznType": "Verb (form IV)"
    },
    {
        "question": "غَاوِينَ",
        "answer": "astray",
        "pcklId": "21",
        "rootWordId": 1092,
        "tlit": "ghāwīna",
        "frequency": "22",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "32",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " فَأَغْوَيْنَاكُمْ إِنَّا كُنَّا غَاوِينَ",
        "rootWord": "غ و ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "غَٰوِين",
        "waznEnglish": "and erred",
        "waznTlit": "ghāwīn",
        "waznType": "Active participle"
    },
    {
        "question": "فِتْنَةً",
        "answer": "a trial",
        "pcklId": "50",
        "rootWordId": 1105,
        "tlit": "fit'natan",
        "frequency": "60",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "63",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّا جَعَلْنَاهَا فِتْنَةً لِلظَّالِمِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ف ت ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "فِتْنَة",
        "waznEnglish": "(may) harm you",
        "waznTlit": "fit'nat",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "بِفَاتِنِينَ",
        "answer": "can tempt away (anyone)",
        "pcklId": "58",
        "rootWordId": 1105,
        "tlit": "bifātinīna",
        "frequency": "60",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "162",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " مَا أَنْتُمْ عَلَيْهِ بِفَاتِنِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ف ت ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "فَٰتِنِين",
        "waznEnglish": "(may) harm you",
        "waznTlit": "fātinīn",
        "waznType": "Active participle"
    },
    {
        "question": "فَاسْتَفْتِهِمْ",
        "answer": "Then ask them",
        "pcklId": "9",
        "rootWordId": 1106,
        "tlit": "fa-is'taftihim",
        "frequency": "21",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "11",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " فَاسْتَفْتِهِمْ أَهُمْ أَشَدُّ خَلْقًا",
        "rootWord": "ف ت ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "يَسْتَفْتُ",
        "waznEnglish": "to seek ruling, to inquire, to ask",
        "waznTlit": "yastaftu",
        "waznType": "Verb (form X)"
    },
    {
        "question": "فَاسْتَفْتِهِمْ",
        "answer": "Then ask them",
        "pcklId": "10",
        "rootWordId": 1106,
        "tlit": "fa-is'taftihim",
        "frequency": "21",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "149",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " فَاسْتَفْتِهِمْ أَلِرَبِّكَ الْبَنَاتُ وَلَهُمُ الْبَنُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ف ت ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "يَسْتَفْتُ",
        "waznEnglish": "to seek ruling, to inquire, to ask",
        "waznTlit": "yastaftu",
        "waznType": "Verb (form X)"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَفَدَيْنَاهُ",
        "answer": "And We ransomed him",
        "pcklId": "0",
        "rootWordId": 1112,
        "tlit": "wafadaynāhu",
        "frequency": "13",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "107",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " وَفَدَيْنَاهُ بِذِبْحٍ عَظِيمٍ",
        "rootWord": "ف د ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "فَدَيْ",
        "waznEnglish": "to ransom",
        "waznTlit": "faday",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْفَصْلِ",
        "answer": "(of) Judgment",
        "pcklId": "25",
        "rootWordId": 1135,
        "tlit": "l-faṣli",
        "frequency": "43",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "21",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " هَٰذَا يَوْمُ الْفَصْلِ الَّذِي كُنْتُمْ بِهِ تُكَذِّبُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ف ص ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "فَصْل",
        "waznEnglish": "set out",
        "waznTlit": "faṣl",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "نَفْعَلُ",
        "answer": "We deal",
        "pcklId": "68",
        "rootWordId": 1143,
        "tlit": "nafʿalu",
        "frequency": "108",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "34",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّا كَذَٰلِكَ نَفْعَلُ بِالْمُجْرِمِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ف ع ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "فَعَلَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to do",
        "waznTlit": "faʿala",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "افْعَلْ",
        "answer": "Do",
        "pcklId": "69",
        "rootWordId": 1143,
        "tlit": "if'ʿal",
        "frequency": "108",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "102",
        "wordnum": "18",
        "arabicAyah": " قَالَ يَا أَبَتِ افْعَلْ مَا تُؤْمَرُ سَتَجِدُنِي إِنْ شَاءَ اللَّهُ مِنَ الصَّابِرِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ف ع ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "فَعَلَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to do",
        "waznTlit": "faʿala",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "فَوَاكِهُ",
        "answer": "Fruits",
        "pcklId": "14",
        "rootWordId": 1150,
        "tlit": "fawākihu",
        "frequency": "19",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "42",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " فَوَاكِهُ وَهُمْ مُكْرَمُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ف ك ه",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "فَوَٰكِه",
        "waznEnglish": "wondering",
        "waznTlit": "fawākih",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْفُلْكِ",
        "answer": "the ship",
        "pcklId": "21",
        "rootWordId": 1153,
        "tlit": "l-ful'ki",
        "frequency": "25",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "140",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " إِذْ أَبَقَ إِلَى الْفُلْكِ الْمَشْحُونِ",
        "rootWord": "ف ل ك",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "فُلْك",
        "waznEnglish": "an orbit",
        "waznTlit": "ful'k",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْفَوْزُ",
        "answer": "(is) the attainment",
        "pcklId": "13",
        "rootWordId": 1162,
        "tlit": "l-fawzu",
        "frequency": "29",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "60",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّ هَٰذَا لَهُوَ الْفَوْزُ الْعَظِيمُ",
        "rootWord": "ف و ز",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "فَوْز",
        "waznEnglish": "he is successful",
        "waznTlit": "fawz",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَأَقْبَلَ",
        "answer": "And will approach",
        "pcklId": "12",
        "rootWordId": 1174,
        "tlit": "wa-aqbala",
        "frequency": "294",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "27",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " وَأَقْبَلَ بَعْضُهُمْ عَلَىٰ بَعْضٍ يَتَسَاءَلُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ق ب ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَقْبَلَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to approach",
        "waznTlit": "aqbala",
        "waznType": "Verb (form IV)"
    },
    {
        "question": "فَأَقْبَلَ",
        "answer": "And (will) approach",
        "pcklId": "13",
        "rootWordId": 1174,
        "tlit": "fa-aqbala",
        "frequency": "294",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "50",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " فَأَقْبَلَ بَعْضُهُمْ عَلَىٰ بَعْضٍ يَتَسَاءَلُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ق ب ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَقْبَلَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to approach",
        "waznTlit": "aqbala",
        "waznType": "Verb (form IV)"
    },
    {
        "question": "فَأَقْبَلُوا",
        "answer": "Then they advanced",
        "pcklId": "14",
        "rootWordId": 1174,
        "tlit": "fa-aqbalū",
        "frequency": "294",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "94",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " فَأَقْبَلُوا إِلَيْهِ يَزِفُّونَ",
        "rootWord": "ق ب ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَقْبَلَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to approach",
        "waznTlit": "aqbala",
        "waznType": "Verb (form IV)"
    },
    {
        "question": "قَبْلَهُمْ",
        "answer": "before them",
        "pcklId": "258",
        "rootWordId": 1174,
        "tlit": "qablahum",
        "frequency": "294",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "71",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " وَلَقَدْ ضَلَّ قَبْلَهُمْ أَكْثَرُ الْأَوَّلِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ق ب ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "قَبْل",
        "waznEnglish": "will be accepted",
        "waznTlit": "qabl",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Time adverb)"
    },
    {
        "question": "مُتَقَابِلِينَ",
        "answer": "facing each other",
        "pcklId": "290",
        "rootWordId": 1174,
        "tlit": "mutaqābilīna",
        "frequency": "294",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "44",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " عَلَىٰ سُرُرٍ مُتَقَابِلِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ق ب ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مُّتَقَٰبِلِين",
        "waznEnglish": "will be accepted",
        "waznTlit": "mutaqābilīn",
        "waznType": "Active participle (form VI)"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَيُقْذَفُونَ",
        "answer": "are pelted",
        "pcklId": "7",
        "rootWordId": 1185,
        "tlit": "wayuq'dhafūna",
        "frequency": "9",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "8",
        "wordnum": "6",
        "arabicAyah": " لَا يَسَّمَّعُونَ إِلَى الْمَلَإِ الْأَعْلَىٰ وَيُقْذَفُونَ مِنْ كُلِّ جَانِبٍ",
        "rootWord": "ق ذ ف",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ق ذ ف",
        "waznEnglish": "to cast, to throw, to hurl",
        "waznTlit": "qāf dhāl fā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "قَرِينٌ",
        "answer": "a companion",
        "pcklId": "25",
        "rootWordId": 1195,
        "tlit": "qarīnun",
        "frequency": "36",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "51",
        "wordnum": "7",
        "arabicAyah": " قَالَ قَائِلٌ مِنْهُمْ إِنِّي كَانَ لِي قَرِينٌ",
        "rootWord": "ق ر ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "قَرِين",
        "waznEnglish": "generations",
        "waznTlit": "qarīn",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "قَاصِرَاتُ",
        "answer": "(will be) companions of modest gaze",
        "pcklId": "7",
        "rootWordId": 1205,
        "tlit": "qāṣirātu",
        "frequency": "11",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "48",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " وَعِنْدَهُمْ قَاصِرَاتُ الطَّرْفِ عِينٌ",
        "rootWord": "ق ص ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "قَٰصِرَٰت",
        "waznEnglish": "you shorten",
        "waznTlit": "qāṣirāt",
        "waznType": "Active participle"
    },
    {
        "question": "بِقَلْبٍ",
        "answer": "with a heart",
        "pcklId": "120",
        "rootWordId": 1222,
        "tlit": "biqalbin",
        "frequency": "168",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "84",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " إِذْ جَاءَ رَبَّهُ بِقَلْبٍ سَلِيمٍ",
        "rootWord": "ق ل ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "قَلْب",
        "waznEnglish": "you will be returned",
        "waznTlit": "qalb",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَقَالُوا",
        "answer": "And they say",
        "pcklId": "1300",
        "rootWordId": 1245,
        "tlit": "waqālū",
        "frequency": "1722",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "15",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " وَقَالُوا إِنْ هَٰذَا إِلَّا سِحْرٌ مُبِينٌ",
        "rootWord": "ق و ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "قَالَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to say",
        "waznTlit": "qāla",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "قُلْ",
        "answer": "Say",
        "pcklId": "1301",
        "rootWordId": 1245,
        "tlit": "qul",
        "frequency": "1722",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "18",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " قُلْ نَعَمْ وَأَنْتُمْ دَاخِرُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ق و ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "قَالَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to say",
        "waznTlit": "qāla",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَقَالُوا",
        "answer": "And they will say",
        "pcklId": "1302",
        "rootWordId": 1245,
        "tlit": "waqālū",
        "frequency": "1722",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "20",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " وَقَالُوا يَا وَيْلَنَا هَٰذَا يَوْمُ الدِّينِ",
        "rootWord": "ق و ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "قَالَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to say",
        "waznTlit": "qāla",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "قَالُوا",
        "answer": "They will say",
        "pcklId": "1303",
        "rootWordId": 1245,
        "tlit": "qālū",
        "frequency": "1722",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "28",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " قَالُوا إِنَّكُمْ كُنْتُمْ تَأْتُونَنَا عَنِ الْيَمِينِ",
        "rootWord": "ق و ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "قَالَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to say",
        "waznTlit": "qāla",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "قَالُوا",
        "answer": "They will say",
        "pcklId": "1304",
        "rootWordId": 1245,
        "tlit": "qālū",
        "frequency": "1722",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "29",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " قَالُوا بَلْ لَمْ تَكُونُوا مُؤْمِنِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ق و ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "قَالَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to say",
        "waznTlit": "qāla",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "قِيلَ",
        "answer": "it was said",
        "pcklId": "1305",
        "rootWordId": 1245,
        "tlit": "qīla",
        "frequency": "1722",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "35",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّهُمْ كَانُوا إِذَا قِيلَ لَهُمْ لَا إِلَٰهَ إِلَّا اللَّهُ يَسْتَكْبِرُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ق و ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "قَالَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to say",
        "waznTlit": "qāla",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَيَقُولُونَ",
        "answer": "And they say",
        "pcklId": "1306",
        "rootWordId": 1245,
        "tlit": "wayaqūlūna",
        "frequency": "1722",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "36",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " وَيَقُولُونَ أَئِنَّا لَتَارِكُو آلِهَتِنَا لِشَاعِرٍ مَجْنُونٍ",
        "rootWord": "ق و ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "قَالَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to say",
        "waznTlit": "qāla",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "قَالَ",
        "answer": "Will say",
        "pcklId": "1307",
        "rootWordId": 1245,
        "tlit": "qāla",
        "frequency": "1722",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "51",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " قَالَ قَائِلٌ مِنْهُمْ إِنِّي كَانَ لِي قَرِينٌ",
        "rootWord": "ق و ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "قَالَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to say",
        "waznTlit": "qāla",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "يَقُولُ",
        "answer": "Who (would) say",
        "pcklId": "1308",
        "rootWordId": 1245,
        "tlit": "yaqūlu",
        "frequency": "1722",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "52",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " يَقُولُ أَإِنَّكَ لَمِنَ الْمُصَدِّقِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ق و ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "قَالَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to say",
        "waznTlit": "qāla",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "قَالَ",
        "answer": "He (will) say",
        "pcklId": "1309",
        "rootWordId": 1245,
        "tlit": "qāla",
        "frequency": "1722",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "54",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " قَالَ هَلْ أَنْتُمْ مُطَّلِعُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ق و ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "قَالَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to say",
        "waznTlit": "qāla",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "قَالَ",
        "answer": "He (will) say",
        "pcklId": "1310",
        "rootWordId": 1245,
        "tlit": "qāla",
        "frequency": "1722",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "56",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " قَالَ تَاللَّهِ إِنْ كِدْتَ لَتُرْدِينِ",
        "rootWord": "ق و ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "قَالَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to say",
        "waznTlit": "qāla",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "قَالَ",
        "answer": "he said",
        "pcklId": "1311",
        "rootWordId": 1245,
        "tlit": "qāla",
        "frequency": "1722",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "85",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " إِذْ قَالَ لِأَبِيهِ وَقَوْمِهِ مَاذَا تَعْبُدُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ق و ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "قَالَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to say",
        "waznTlit": "qāla",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "فَقَالَ",
        "answer": "And he said",
        "pcklId": "1312",
        "rootWordId": 1245,
        "tlit": "faqāla",
        "frequency": "1722",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "89",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " فَقَالَ إِنِّي سَقِيمٌ",
        "rootWord": "ق و ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "قَالَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to say",
        "waznTlit": "qāla",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "فَقَالَ",
        "answer": "and said",
        "pcklId": "1313",
        "rootWordId": 1245,
        "tlit": "faqāla",
        "frequency": "1722",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "91",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " فَرَاغَ إِلَىٰ آلِهَتِهِمْ فَقَالَ أَلَا تَأْكُلُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ق و ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "قَالَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to say",
        "waznTlit": "qāla",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "قَالَ",
        "answer": "He said",
        "pcklId": "1314",
        "rootWordId": 1245,
        "tlit": "qāla",
        "frequency": "1722",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "95",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " قَالَ أَتَعْبُدُونَ مَا تَنْحِتُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ق و ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "قَالَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to say",
        "waznTlit": "qāla",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "قَالُوا",
        "answer": "They said",
        "pcklId": "1315",
        "rootWordId": 1245,
        "tlit": "qālū",
        "frequency": "1722",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "97",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " قَالُوا ابْنُوا لَهُ بُنْيَانًا فَأَلْقُوهُ فِي الْجَحِيمِ",
        "rootWord": "ق و ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "قَالَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to say",
        "waznTlit": "qāla",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَقَالَ",
        "answer": "And he said",
        "pcklId": "1316",
        "rootWordId": 1245,
        "tlit": "waqāla",
        "frequency": "1722",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "99",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " وَقَالَ إِنِّي ذَاهِبٌ إِلَىٰ رَبِّي سَيَهْدِينِ",
        "rootWord": "ق و ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "قَالَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to say",
        "waznTlit": "qāla",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "قَالَ",
        "answer": "he said",
        "pcklId": "1317",
        "rootWordId": 1245,
        "tlit": "qāla",
        "frequency": "1722",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "102",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " فَلَمَّا بَلَغَ مَعَهُ السَّعْيَ قَالَ يَا بُنَيَّ إِنِّي أَرَىٰ فِي الْمَنَامِ أَنِّي أَذْبَحُكَ",
        "rootWord": "ق و ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "قَالَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to say",
        "waznTlit": "qāla",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "قَالَ",
        "answer": "He said",
        "pcklId": "1318",
        "rootWordId": 1245,
        "tlit": "qāla",
        "frequency": "1722",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "102",
        "wordnum": "16",
        "arabicAyah": " قَالَ يَا أَبَتِ افْعَلْ مَا تُؤْمَرُ",
        "rootWord": "ق و ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "قَالَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to say",
        "waznTlit": "qāla",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "قَالَ",
        "answer": "he said",
        "pcklId": "1319",
        "rootWordId": 1245,
        "tlit": "qāla",
        "frequency": "1722",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "124",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " إِذْ قَالَ لِقَوْمِهِ أَلَا تَتَّقُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ق و ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "قَالَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to say",
        "waznTlit": "qāla",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "لَيَقُولُونَ",
        "answer": "[they] say",
        "pcklId": "1320",
        "rootWordId": 1245,
        "tlit": "layaqūlūna",
        "frequency": "1722",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "151",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " أَلَا إِنَّهُمْ مِنْ إِفْكِهِمْ لَيَقُولُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ق و ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "قَالَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to say",
        "waznTlit": "qāla",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "لَيَقُولُونَ",
        "answer": "say",
        "pcklId": "1321",
        "rootWordId": 1245,
        "tlit": "layaqūlūna",
        "frequency": "1722",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "167",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " وَإِنْ كَانُوا لَيَقُولُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ق و ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "قَالَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to say",
        "waznTlit": "qāla",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "قَوْلُ",
        "answer": "(the) Word",
        "pcklId": "1693",
        "rootWordId": 1245,
        "tlit": "qawlu",
        "frequency": "1722",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "31",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " فَحَقَّ عَلَيْنَا قَوْلُ رَبِّنَا إِنَّا لَذَائِقُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ق و ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "قَوْل",
        "waznEnglish": "say",
        "waznTlit": "qawl",
        "waznType": "Verbal noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "قَائِلٌ",
        "answer": "a speaker",
        "pcklId": "1721",
        "rootWordId": 1245,
        "tlit": "qāilun",
        "frequency": "1722",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "51",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " قَالَ قَائِلٌ مِنْهُمْ إِنِّي كَانَ لِي قَرِينٌ",
        "rootWord": "ق و ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "قَآئِل",
        "waznEnglish": "say",
        "waznTlit": "qāil",
        "waznType": "Active participle"
    },
    {
        "question": "قَوْمًا",
        "answer": "a people",
        "pcklId": "406",
        "rootWordId": 1246,
        "tlit": "qawman",
        "frequency": "660",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "30",
        "wordnum": "9",
        "arabicAyah": " وَمَا كَانَ لَنَا عَلَيْكُمْ مِنْ سُلْطَانٍ بَلْ كُنْتُمْ قَوْمًا طَاغِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ق و م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "قَوْم",
        "waznEnglish": "they stand (still)",
        "waznTlit": "qawm",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَقَوْمِهِ",
        "answer": "and his people",
        "pcklId": "407",
        "rootWordId": 1246,
        "tlit": "waqawmihi",
        "frequency": "660",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "85",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " إِذْ قَالَ لِأَبِيهِ وَقَوْمِهِ مَاذَا تَعْبُدُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ق و م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "قَوْم",
        "waznEnglish": "they stand (still)",
        "waznTlit": "qawm",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَقَوْمَهُمَا",
        "answer": "and their people",
        "pcklId": "408",
        "rootWordId": 1246,
        "tlit": "waqawmahumā",
        "frequency": "660",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "115",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " وَنَجَّيْنَاهُمَا وَقَوْمَهُمَا مِنَ الْكَرْبِ الْعَظِيمِ",
        "rootWord": "ق و م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "قَوْم",
        "waznEnglish": "they stand (still)",
        "waznTlit": "qawm",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "لِقَوْمِهِ",
        "answer": "to his people",
        "pcklId": "409",
        "rootWordId": 1246,
        "tlit": "liqawmihi",
        "frequency": "660",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "124",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " إِذْ قَالَ لِقَوْمِهِ أَلَا تَتَّقُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ق و م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "قَوْم",
        "waznEnglish": "they stand (still)",
        "waznTlit": "qawm",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "مَقَامٌ",
        "answer": "(is) a position",
        "pcklId": "578",
        "rootWordId": 1246,
        "tlit": "maqāmun",
        "frequency": "660",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "164",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " وَمَا مِنَّا إِلَّا لَهُ مَقَامٌ مَعْلُومٌ",
        "rootWord": "ق و م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مَقَام",
        "waznEnglish": "they stand (still)",
        "waznTlit": "maqām",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْمُسْتَقِيمَ",
        "answer": "the Straight",
        "pcklId": "658",
        "rootWordId": 1246,
        "tlit": "l-mus'taqīma",
        "frequency": "660",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "118",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " وَهَدَيْنَاهُمَا الصِّرَاطَ الْمُسْتَقِيمَ",
        "rootWord": "ق و م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مُّسْتَقِيم",
        "waznEnglish": "they stand (still)",
        "waznTlit": "mus'taqīm",
        "waznType": "Active participle (form X) (Adjective)"
    },
    {
        "question": "بِكَأْسٍ",
        "answer": "a cup",
        "pcklId": "0",
        "rootWordId": 1250,
        "tlit": "bikasin",
        "frequency": "6",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "45",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " يُطَافُ عَلَيْهِمْ بِكَأْسٍ مِنْ مَعِينٍ",
        "rootWord": "ك أ س",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ك أ س",
        "waznEnglish": "a cup",
        "waznTlit": "kāf hamza sīn",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "يَسْتَكْبِرُونَ",
        "answer": "were arrogant",
        "pcklId": "41",
        "rootWordId": 1254,
        "tlit": "yastakbirūna",
        "frequency": "161",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "35",
        "wordnum": "10",
        "arabicAyah": " كَانُوا إِذَا قِيلَ لَهُمْ لَا إِلَٰهَ إِلَّا اللَّهُ يَسْتَكْبِرُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ك ب ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ٱسْتَكْبَرَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to be arrogant",
        "waznTlit": "is'takbara",
        "waznType": "Verb (form X)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْكِتَابَ",
        "answer": "the Book",
        "pcklId": "250",
        "rootWordId": 1256,
        "tlit": "l-kitāba",
        "frequency": "319",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "117",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " وَآتَيْنَاهُمَا الْكِتَابَ الْمُسْتَبِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ك ت ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كِتَٰب",
        "waznEnglish": "write",
        "waznTlit": "kitāb",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "بِكِتَابِكُمْ",
        "answer": "your book",
        "pcklId": "251",
        "rootWordId": 1256,
        "tlit": "bikitābikum",
        "frequency": "319",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "157",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " فَأْتُوا بِكِتَابِكُمْ إِنْ كُنْتُمْ صَادِقِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ك ت ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كِتَٰب",
        "waznEnglish": "write",
        "waznTlit": "kitāb",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "أَكْثَرُ",
        "answer": "most",
        "pcklId": "72",
        "rootWordId": 1259,
        "tlit": "aktharu",
        "frequency": "167",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "71",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " وَلَقَدْ ضَلَّ قَبْلَهُمْ أَكْثَرُ الْأَوَّلِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ك ث ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَكْثَر",
        "waznEnglish": "much ",
        "waznTlit": "akthar",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "تُكَذِّبُونَ",
        "answer": "deny",
        "pcklId": "110",
        "rootWordId": 1263,
        "tlit": "tukadhibūna",
        "frequency": "282",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "21",
        "wordnum": "7",
        "arabicAyah": " هَٰذَا يَوْمُ الْفَصْلِ الَّذِي كُنْتُمْ بِهِ تُكَذِّبُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ك ذ ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كَذَّبَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to deny, to reject",
        "waznTlit": "kadhaba",
        "waznType": "Verb (form II)"
    },
    {
        "question": "فَكَذَّبُوهُ",
        "answer": "But they denied him",
        "pcklId": "111",
        "rootWordId": 1263,
        "tlit": "fakadhabūhu",
        "frequency": "282",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "127",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " فَكَذَّبُوهُ فَإِنَّهُمْ لَمُحْضَرُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ك ذ ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كَذَّبَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to deny, to reject",
        "waznTlit": "kadhaba",
        "waznType": "Verb (form II)"
    },
    {
        "question": "لَكَاذِبُونَ",
        "answer": "surely (are) liars",
        "pcklId": "248",
        "rootWordId": 1263,
        "tlit": "lakādhibūna",
        "frequency": "282",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "152",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " وَلَدَ اللَّهُ وَإِنَّهُمْ لَكَاذِبُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ك ذ ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كَٰذِب",
        "waznEnglish": "[they] lie",
        "waznTlit": "kādhib",
        "waznType": "Active participle (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْكَرْبِ",
        "answer": "the distress",
        "pcklId": "2",
        "rootWordId": 1264,
        "tlit": "l-karbi",
        "frequency": "4",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "76",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " وَنَجَّيْنَاهُ وَأَهْلَهُ مِنَ الْكَرْبِ الْعَظِيمِ",
        "rootWord": "ك ر ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ك ر ب",
        "waznEnglish": "distress",
        "waznTlit": "kāf rā bā",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْكَرْبِ",
        "answer": "the distress",
        "pcklId": "3",
        "rootWordId": 1264,
        "tlit": "l-karbi",
        "frequency": "4",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "115",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " وَنَجَّيْنَاهُمَا وَقَوْمَهُمَا مِنَ الْكَرْبِ الْعَظِيمِ",
        "rootWord": "ك ر ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ك ر ب",
        "waznEnglish": "distress",
        "waznTlit": "kāf rā bā",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "مُكْرَمُونَ",
        "answer": "(will) be honored",
        "pcklId": "44",
        "rootWordId": 1267,
        "tlit": "muk'ramūna",
        "frequency": "47",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "42",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " فَوَاكِهُ وَهُمْ مُكْرَمُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ك ر م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مُّكْرَمُون",
        "waznEnglish": "You have honored",
        "waznTlit": "muk'ramūn",
        "waznType": "Passive participle (form IV) (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "فَكَفَرُوا",
        "answer": "But they disbelieved",
        "pcklId": "213",
        "rootWordId": 1280,
        "tlit": "fakafarū",
        "frequency": "525",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "170",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " فَكَفَرُوا بِهِ فَسَوْفَ يَعْلَمُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ك ف ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كَفَرَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to disbelieve",
        "waznTlit": "kafara",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "كُلِّ",
        "answer": "every",
        "pcklId": "270",
        "rootWordId": 1288,
        "tlit": "kulli",
        "frequency": "377",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "7",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " وَحِفْظًا مِنْ كُلِّ شَيْطَانٍ مَارِدٍ",
        "rootWord": "ك ل ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كُلّ",
        "waznEnglish": "(is) a burden",
        "waznTlit": "kull",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "كُلِّ",
        "answer": "every",
        "pcklId": "271",
        "rootWordId": 1288,
        "tlit": "kulli",
        "frequency": "377",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "8",
        "wordnum": "8",
        "arabicAyah": " لَا يَسَّمَّعُونَ إِلَى الْمَلَإِ الْأَعْلَىٰ وَيُقْذَفُونَ مِنْ كُلِّ جَانِبٍ",
        "rootWord": "ك ل ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كُلّ",
        "waznEnglish": "(is) a burden",
        "waznTlit": "kull",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "كَلِمَتُنَا",
        "answer": "Our Word",
        "pcklId": "65",
        "rootWordId": 1289,
        "tlit": "kalimatunā",
        "frequency": "75",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "171",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " وَلَقَدْ سَبَقَتْ كَلِمَتُنَا لِعِبَادِنَا الْمُرْسَلِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ك ل م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كَلِمَة",
        "waznEnglish": "speaks to us",
        "waznTlit": "kalimat",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "مَكْنُونٌ",
        "answer": "well protected",
        "pcklId": "8",
        "rootWordId": 1297,
        "tlit": "maknūnun",
        "frequency": "12",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "49",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " كَأَنَّهُنَّ بَيْضٌ مَكْنُونٌ",
        "rootWord": "ك ن ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مَّكْنُون",
        "waznEnglish": "you conceal it",
        "waznTlit": "maknūn",
        "waznType": "Passive participle (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "كِدْتَ",
        "answer": "you almost",
        "pcklId": "18",
        "rootWordId": 1302,
        "tlit": "kidtta",
        "frequency": "24",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "56",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " قَالَ تَاللَّهِ إِنْ كِدْتَ لَتُرْدِينِ",
        "rootWord": "ك و د",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ك و د",
        "waznEnglish": "to be near, to nearly do, to almost do",
        "waznTlit": "kāf wāw dāl",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْكَوَاكِبِ",
        "answer": "(of) the stars",
        "pcklId": "3",
        "rootWordId": 1304,
        "tlit": "l-kawākibi",
        "frequency": "5",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "6",
        "wordnum": "6",
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّا زَيَّنَّا السَّمَاءَ الدُّنْيَا بِزِينَةٍ الْكَوَاكِبِ",
        "rootWord": "ك و ك ب",
        "rootWordType": "quadriliteral root",
        "wazn": "ك و ك ب",
        "waznEnglish": "a star",
        "waznTlit": "kāf wāw kāf bā",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَكُنَّا",
        "answer": "and have become",
        "pcklId": "1068",
        "rootWordId": 1305,
        "tlit": "wakunnā",
        "frequency": "1390",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "16",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " أَإِذَا مِتْنَا وَكُنَّا تُرَابًا وَعِظَامًا أَإِنَّا لَمَبْعُوثُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ك و ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كَانَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to be",
        "waznTlit": "kāna",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "كُنْتُمْ",
        "answer": "you used to",
        "pcklId": "1069",
        "rootWordId": 1305,
        "tlit": "kuntum",
        "frequency": "1390",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "21",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " هَٰذَا يَوْمُ الْفَصْلِ الَّذِي كُنْتُمْ بِهِ تُكَذِّبُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ك و ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كَانَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to be",
        "waznTlit": "kāna",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "كَانُوا",
        "answer": "they used (to)",
        "pcklId": "1070",
        "rootWordId": 1305,
        "tlit": "kānū",
        "frequency": "1390",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "22",
        "wordnum": "6",
        "arabicAyah": " احْشُرُوا الَّذِينَ ظَلَمُوا وَأَزْوَاجَهُمْ وَمَا كَانُوا يَعْبُدُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ك و ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كَانَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to be",
        "waznTlit": "kāna",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "كُنْتُمْ",
        "answer": "[you] used (to)",
        "pcklId": "1071",
        "rootWordId": 1305,
        "tlit": "kuntum",
        "frequency": "1390",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "28",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " قَالُوا إِنَّكُمْ كُنْتُمْ تَأْتُونَنَا عَنِ الْيَمِينِ",
        "rootWord": "ك و ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كَانَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to be",
        "waznTlit": "kāna",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "تَكُونُوا",
        "answer": "you were",
        "pcklId": "1072",
        "rootWordId": 1305,
        "tlit": "takūnū",
        "frequency": "1390",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "29",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " قَالُوا بَلْ لَمْ تَكُونُوا مُؤْمِنِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ك و ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كَانَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to be",
        "waznTlit": "kāna",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "كَانَ",
        "answer": "was",
        "pcklId": "1073",
        "rootWordId": 1305,
        "tlit": "kāna",
        "frequency": "1390",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "30",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " وَمَا كَانَ لَنَا عَلَيْكُمْ مِنْ سُلْطَانٍ بَلْ كُنْتُمْ قَوْمًا طَاغِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ك و ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كَانَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to be",
        "waznTlit": "kāna",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "كُنْتُمْ",
        "answer": "you were",
        "pcklId": "1074",
        "rootWordId": 1305,
        "tlit": "kuntum",
        "frequency": "1390",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "30",
        "wordnum": "8",
        "arabicAyah": " وَمَا كَانَ لَنَا عَلَيْكُمْ مِنْ سُلْطَانٍ بَلْ كُنْتُمْ قَوْمًا طَاغِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ك و ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كَانَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to be",
        "waznTlit": "kāna",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "كُنَّا",
        "answer": "were",
        "pcklId": "1075",
        "rootWordId": 1305,
        "tlit": "kunnā",
        "frequency": "1390",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "32",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " فَأَغْوَيْنَاكُمْ إِنَّا كُنَّا غَاوِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ك و ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كَانَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to be",
        "waznTlit": "kāna",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "كَانُوا",
        "answer": "were",
        "pcklId": "1076",
        "rootWordId": 1305,
        "tlit": "kānū",
        "frequency": "1390",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "35",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّهُمْ كَانُوا إِذَا قِيلَ لَهُمْ لَا إِلَٰهَ إِلَّا اللَّهُ يَسْتَكْبِرُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ك و ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كَانَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to be",
        "waznTlit": "kāna",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "كُنْتُمْ",
        "answer": "you used to",
        "pcklId": "1077",
        "rootWordId": 1305,
        "tlit": "kuntum",
        "frequency": "1390",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "39",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " وَمَا تُجْزَوْنَ إِلَّا مَا كُنْتُمْ تَعْمَلُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ك و ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كَانَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to be",
        "waznTlit": "kāna",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "كَانَ",
        "answer": "had",
        "pcklId": "1078",
        "rootWordId": 1305,
        "tlit": "kāna",
        "frequency": "1390",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "51",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " قَالَ قَائِلٌ مِنْهُمْ إِنِّي كَانَ لِي قَرِينٌ",
        "rootWord": "ك و ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كَانَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to be",
        "waznTlit": "kāna",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَكُنَّا",
        "answer": "and become",
        "pcklId": "1079",
        "rootWordId": 1305,
        "tlit": "wakunnā",
        "frequency": "1390",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "53",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " أَإِذَا مِتْنَا وَكُنَّا تُرَابًا وَعِظَامًا أَإِنَّا لَمَدِينُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ك و ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كَانَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to be",
        "waznTlit": "kāna",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "لَكُنْتُ",
        "answer": "certainly, I (would) have been",
        "pcklId": "1080",
        "rootWordId": 1305,
        "tlit": "lakuntu",
        "frequency": "1390",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "57",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " وَلَوْلَا نِعْمَةُ رَبِّي لَكُنْتُ مِنَ الْمُحْضَرِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ك و ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كَانَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to be",
        "waznTlit": "kāna",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "كَانَ",
        "answer": "was",
        "pcklId": "1081",
        "rootWordId": 1305,
        "tlit": "kāna",
        "frequency": "1390",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "73",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " فَانْظُرْ كَيْفَ كَانَ عَاقِبَةُ الْمُنْذَرِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ك و ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كَانَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to be",
        "waznTlit": "kāna",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "فَكَانُوا",
        "answer": "so they became",
        "pcklId": "1082",
        "rootWordId": 1305,
        "tlit": "fakānū",
        "frequency": "1390",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "116",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " وَنَصَرْنَاهُمْ فَكَانُوا هُمُ الْغَالِبِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ك و ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كَانَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to be",
        "waznTlit": "kāna",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "فَكَانَ",
        "answer": "and was",
        "pcklId": "1083",
        "rootWordId": 1305,
        "tlit": "fakāna",
        "frequency": "1390",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "141",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " فَسَاهَمَ فَكَانَ مِنَ الْمُدْحَضِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ك و ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كَانَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to be",
        "waznTlit": "kāna",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "كَانَ",
        "answer": "was",
        "pcklId": "1084",
        "rootWordId": 1305,
        "tlit": "kāna",
        "frequency": "1390",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "143",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " فَلَوْلَا أَنَّهُ كَانَ مِنَ الْمُسَبِّحِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ك و ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كَانَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to be",
        "waznTlit": "kāna",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "كُنْتُمْ",
        "answer": "you are",
        "pcklId": "1085",
        "rootWordId": 1305,
        "tlit": "kuntum",
        "frequency": "1390",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "157",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " فَأْتُوا بِكِتَابِكُمْ إِنْ كُنْتُمْ صَادِقِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ك و ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كَانَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to be",
        "waznTlit": "kāna",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "كَانُوا",
        "answer": "they used to",
        "pcklId": "1086",
        "rootWordId": 1305,
        "tlit": "kānū",
        "frequency": "1390",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "167",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " وَإِنْ كَانُوا لَيَقُولُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ك و ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كَانَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to be",
        "waznTlit": "kāna",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "لَكُنَّا",
        "answer": "Certainly, we (would) have been",
        "pcklId": "1087",
        "rootWordId": 1305,
        "tlit": "lakunnā",
        "frequency": "1390",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "169",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " لَكُنَّا عِبَادَ اللَّهِ الْمُخْلَصِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ك و ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كَانَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to be",
        "waznTlit": "kāna",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "كَيْدًا",
        "answer": "a plot",
        "pcklId": "24",
        "rootWordId": 1307,
        "tlit": "kaydan",
        "frequency": "35",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "98",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " فَأَرَادُوا بِهِ كَيْدًا فَجَعَلْنَاهُمُ الْأَسْفَلِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ك ي د",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كَيْد",
        "waznEnglish": "scheme against me",
        "waznTlit": "kayd",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "كَيْفَ",
        "answer": "how",
        "pcklId": "54",
        "rootWordId": 1308,
        "tlit": "kayfa",
        "frequency": "83",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "73",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " فَانْظُرْ كَيْفَ كَانَ عَاقِبَةُ الْمُنْذَرِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ك ي ف",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ك ي ف",
        "waznEnglish": "How",
        "waznTlit": "kāf yā fā",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Interogative particle)"
    },
    {
        "question": "كَيْفَ",
        "answer": "How",
        "pcklId": "55",
        "rootWordId": 1308,
        "tlit": "kayfa",
        "frequency": "83",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "154",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " مَا لَكُمْ كَيْفَ تَحْكُمُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ك ي ف",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ك ي ف",
        "waznEnglish": "How",
        "waznTlit": "kāf yā fā",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Interogative particle)"
    },
    {
        "question": "لَلَبِثَ",
        "answer": "Certainly, he (would have) remained",
        "pcklId": "27",
        "rootWordId": 1313,
        "tlit": "lalabitha",
        "frequency": "31",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "144",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " لَلَبِثَ فِي بَطْنِهِ إِلَىٰ يَوْمِ يُبْعَثُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ل ب ث",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "لَبِثَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to remain, to stay, to hesitate, to delay",
        "waznTlit": "labitha",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "لَذَّةٍ",
        "answer": "delicious",
        "pcklId": "1",
        "rootWordId": 1327,
        "tlit": "ladhatin",
        "frequency": "3",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "46",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " بَيْضَاءَ لَذَّةٍ لِلشَّارِبِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ل ذ ذ",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "لَذَّة",
        "waznEnglish": "and delights",
        "waznTlit": "ladhat",
        "waznType": "Adjective"
    },
    {
        "question": "لَازِبٍ",
        "answer": "sticky",
        "pcklId": "0",
        "rootWordId": 1328,
        "tlit": "lāzibin",
        "frequency": "1",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "11",
        "wordnum": "12",
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّا خَلَقْنَاهُمْ مِنْ طِينٍ لَازِبٍ",
        "rootWord": "ل ز ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ل ز ب",
        "waznEnglish": "sticky",
        "waznTlit": "lām zāy bā",
        "waznType": "Active participle"
    },
    {
        "question": "أَلْفَوْا",
        "answer": "found",
        "pcklId": "2",
        "rootWordId": 1341,
        "tlit": "alfaw",
        "frequency": "3",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "69",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّهُمْ أَلْفَوْا آبَاءَهُمْ ضَالِّينَ",
        "rootWord": "ل ف و",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ل ف و",
        "waznEnglish": "to find",
        "waznTlit": "lām fā wāw",
        "waznType": "Verb (form IV)"
    },
    {
        "question": "فَالْتَقَمَهُ",
        "answer": "Then swallowed him",
        "pcklId": "0",
        "rootWordId": 1346,
        "tlit": "fal-taqamahu",
        "frequency": "1",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "142",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " فَالْتَقَمَهُ الْحُوتُ وَهُوَ مُلِيمٌ",
        "rootWord": "ل ق م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ل ق م",
        "waznEnglish": "to swallow",
        "waznTlit": "lām qāf mīm",
        "waznType": "Verb (form VIII)"
    },
    {
        "question": "فَأَلْقُوهُ",
        "answer": "and throw him",
        "pcklId": "78",
        "rootWordId": 1347,
        "tlit": "fa-alqūhu",
        "frequency": "146",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "97",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " قَالُوا ابْنُوا لَهُ بُنْيَانًا فَأَلْقُوهُ فِي الْجَحِيمِ",
        "rootWord": "ل ق ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَلْقَىٰٓ",
        "waznEnglish": "to cast, to throw, to meet, to offer",
        "waznTlit": "alqā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form IV)"
    },
    {
        "question": "مُلِيمٌ",
        "answer": "(was) blameworthy",
        "pcklId": "12",
        "rootWordId": 1359,
        "tlit": "mulīmun",
        "frequency": "14",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "142",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " فَالْتَقَمَهُ الْحُوتُ وَهُوَ مُلِيمٌ",
        "rootWord": "ل و م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مُلِيم",
        "waznEnglish": "you blamed me",
        "waznTlit": "mulīm",
        "waznType": "Active participle (form IV)"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَبِاللَّيْلِ",
        "answer": "And at night",
        "pcklId": "52",
        "rootWordId": 1364,
        "tlit": "wabi-al-layli",
        "frequency": "92",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "138",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " وَبِاللَّيْلِ أَفَلَا تَعْقِلُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ل ي ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "لَيْل",
        "waznEnglish": "of the night",
        "waznTlit": "layl",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "مِائَةِ",
        "answer": "a hundred",
        "pcklId": "9",
        "rootWordId": 1366,
        "tlit": "mi-ati",
        "frequency": "10",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "147",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " وَأَرْسَلْنَاهُ إِلَىٰ مِائَةِ أَلْفٍ أَوْ يَزِيدُونَ",
        "rootWord": "م أ ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "م أ ي",
        "waznEnglish": "(for) a hundred",
        "waznTlit": "mīm hamza yā",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "فَمَتَّعْنَاهُمْ",
        "answer": "so We gave them enjoyment",
        "pcklId": "16",
        "rootWordId": 1367,
        "tlit": "famattaʿnāhum",
        "frequency": "70",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "148",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " فَآمَنُوا فَمَتَّعْنَاهُمْ إِلَىٰ حِينٍ",
        "rootWord": "م ت ع",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مَّتَّعْ",
        "waznEnglish": "to grant, to bestow, to provide",
        "waznTlit": "mattaʿ",
        "waznType": "Verb (form II)"
    },
    {
        "question": "لِمِثْلِ",
        "answer": "For (the) like",
        "pcklId": "150",
        "rootWordId": 1369,
        "tlit": "limith'li",
        "frequency": "169",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "61",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " لِمِثْلِ هَٰذَا فَلْيَعْمَلِ الْعَامِلُونَ",
        "rootWord": "م ث ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مِثْل",
        "waznEnglish": "then he assumed for her the likeness",
        "waznTlit": "mith'l",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "مَارِدٍ",
        "answer": "rebellious",
        "pcklId": "3",
        "rootWordId": 1384,
        "tlit": "māridin",
        "frequency": "5",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "7",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " وَحِفْظًا مِنْ كُلِّ شَيْطَانٍ مَارِدٍ",
        "rootWord": "م ر د",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مَّارِد",
        "waznEnglish": "They persist",
        "waznTlit": "mārid",
        "waznType": "Active participle"
    },
    {
        "question": "لَتَمُرُّونَ",
        "answer": "surely pass",
        "pcklId": "8",
        "rootWordId": 1385,
        "tlit": "latamurrūna",
        "frequency": "35",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "137",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " وَإِنَّكُمْ لَتَمُرُّونَ عَلَيْهِمْ مُصْبِحِينَ",
        "rootWord": "م ر ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مَرَّ",
        "waznEnglish": "to pass, to continue",
        "waznTlit": "marra",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْمَلَإِ",
        "answer": "the assembly",
        "pcklId": "33",
        "rootWordId": 1412,
        "tlit": "l-mala-i",
        "frequency": "40",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "8",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " لَا يَسَّمَّعُونَ إِلَى الْمَلَإِ الْأَعْلَىٰ وَيُقْذَفُونَ مِنْ كُلِّ جَانِبٍ",
        "rootWord": "م ل أ",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مَلَأ",
        "waznEnglish": "surely, I will fill",
        "waznTlit": "mala",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "فَمَالِئُونَ",
        "answer": "and fill",
        "pcklId": "38",
        "rootWordId": 1412,
        "tlit": "famāliūna",
        "frequency": "40",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "66",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " فَإِنَّهُمْ لَآكِلُونَ مِنْهَا فَمَالِئُونَ مِنْهَا الْبُطُونَ",
        "rootWord": "م ل أ",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مَالِـُٔون",
        "waznEnglish": "surely, I will fill",
        "waznTlit": "māliūn",
        "waznType": "Active participle"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْمَلَائِكَةَ",
        "answer": "the Angels",
        "pcklId": "128",
        "rootWordId": 1415,
        "tlit": "l-malāikata",
        "frequency": "206",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "150",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " أَمْ خَلَقْنَا الْمَلَائِكَةَ إِنَاثًا وَهُمْ شَاهِدُونَ",
        "rootWord": "م ل ك",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مَلَك",
        "waznEnglish": "possesses",
        "waznTlit": "malak",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "مَنَنَّا",
        "answer": "We conferred Favor",
        "pcklId": "9",
        "rootWordId": 1419,
        "tlit": "manannā",
        "frequency": "27",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "114",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " وَلَقَدْ مَنَنَّا عَلَىٰ مُوسَىٰ وَهَارُونَ",
        "rootWord": "م ن ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مَنَّ",
        "waznEnglish": "to favor",
        "waznTlit": "manna",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "مِتْنَا",
        "answer": "we are dead",
        "pcklId": "31",
        "rootWordId": 1424,
        "tlit": "mit'nā",
        "frequency": "165",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "16",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " أَإِذَا مِتْنَا وَكُنَّا تُرَابًا وَعِظَامًا أَإِنَّا لَمَبْعُوثُونَ",
        "rootWord": "م و ت",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مَّاتَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to die",
        "waznTlit": "māta",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "مِتْنَا",
        "answer": "we have died",
        "pcklId": "32",
        "rootWordId": 1424,
        "tlit": "mit'nā",
        "frequency": "165",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "53",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " أَإِذَا مِتْنَا وَكُنَّا تُرَابًا وَعِظَامًا أَإِنَّا لَمَدِينُونَ",
        "rootWord": "م و ت",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مَّاتَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to die",
        "waznTlit": "māta",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "مَوْتَتَنَا",
        "answer": "our death",
        "pcklId": "113",
        "rootWordId": 1424,
        "tlit": "mawtatanā",
        "frequency": "165",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "59",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " إِلَّا مَوْتَتَنَا الْأُولَىٰ وَمَا نَحْنُ بِمُعَذَّبِينَ",
        "rootWord": "م و ت",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مَوْتَت",
        "waznEnglish": "(should) you die",
        "waznTlit": "mawtat",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "بِمَيِّتِينَ",
        "answer": "(to) die",
        "pcklId": "143",
        "rootWordId": 1424,
        "tlit": "bimayyitīna",
        "frequency": "165",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "58",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " أَفَمَا نَحْنُ بِمَيِّتِينَ",
        "rootWord": "م و ت",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مَّيِّت",
        "waznEnglish": "(should) you die",
        "waznTlit": "mayyit",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "نَبِيًّا",
        "answer": "a Prophet",
        "pcklId": "149",
        "rootWordId": 1434,
        "tlit": "nabiyyan",
        "frequency": "160",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "112",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " وَبَشَّرْنَاهُ بِإِسْحَاقَ نَبِيًّا مِنَ الصَّالِحِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ن ب أ",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "نَّبِىّ",
        "waznEnglish": "Shall I inform you",
        "waznTlit": "nabiīī",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَأَنْبَتْنَا",
        "answer": "And We caused to grow",
        "pcklId": "12",
        "rootWordId": 1435,
        "tlit": "wa-anbatnā",
        "frequency": "26",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "146",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " وَأَنْبَتْنَا عَلَيْهِ شَجَرَةً مِنْ يَقْطِينٍ",
        "rootWord": "ن ب ت",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَنۢبَتَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to make grow",
        "waznTlit": "anbata",
        "waznType": "Verb (form IV)"
    },
    {
        "question": "فَنَبَذْنَاهُ",
        "answer": "But We cast him",
        "pcklId": "6",
        "rootWordId": 1436,
        "tlit": "fanabadhnāhu",
        "frequency": "12",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "145",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " فَنَبَذْنَاهُ بِالْعَرَاءِ وَهُوَ سَقِيمٌ",
        "rootWord": "ن ب ذ",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "نَبَذَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to throw, to cast",
        "waznTlit": "nabadha",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "النُّجُومِ",
        "answer": "the stars",
        "pcklId": "5",
        "rootWordId": 1444,
        "tlit": "l-nujūmi",
        "frequency": "13",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "88",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " فَنَظَرَ نَظْرَةً فِي النُّجُومِ",
        "rootWord": "ن ج م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ن ج م",
        "waznEnglish": "the stars",
        "waznTlit": "nūn jīm mīm",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَنَجَّيْنَاهُ",
        "answer": "And We saved him",
        "pcklId": "30",
        "rootWordId": 1445,
        "tlit": "wanajjaynāhu",
        "frequency": "84",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "76",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " وَنَجَّيْنَاهُ وَأَهْلَهُ مِنَ الْكَرْبِ الْعَظِيمِ",
        "rootWord": "ن ج و",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "نَجَّىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "to save, to deliver",
        "waznTlit": "najjā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form II)"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَنَجَّيْنَاهُمَا",
        "answer": "And We saved both of them",
        "pcklId": "31",
        "rootWordId": 1445,
        "tlit": "wanajjaynāhumā",
        "frequency": "84",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "115",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " وَنَجَّيْنَاهُمَا وَقَوْمَهُمَا مِنَ الْكَرْبِ الْعَظِيمِ",
        "rootWord": "ن ج و",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "نَجَّىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "to save, to deliver",
        "waznTlit": "najjā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form II)"
    },
    {
        "question": "نَجَّيْنَاهُ",
        "answer": "We saved him",
        "pcklId": "32",
        "rootWordId": 1445,
        "tlit": "najjaynāhu",
        "frequency": "84",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "134",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " إِذْ نَجَّيْنَاهُ وَأَهْلَهُ أَجْمَعِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ن ج و",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "نَجَّىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "to save, to deliver",
        "waznTlit": "najjā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form II)"
    },
    {
        "question": "تَنْحِتُونَ",
        "answer": "you carve",
        "pcklId": "3",
        "rootWordId": 1447,
        "tlit": "tanḥitūna",
        "frequency": "4",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "95",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " قَالَ أَتَعْبُدُونَ مَا تَنْحِتُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ن ح ت",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ن ح ت",
        "waznEnglish": "to carve",
        "waznTlit": "nūn ḥā tā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "نَادَانَا",
        "answer": "called Us",
        "pcklId": "28",
        "rootWordId": 1455,
        "tlit": "nādānā",
        "frequency": "53",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "75",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " وَلَقَدْ نَادَانَا نُوحٌ فَلَنِعْمَ الْمُجِيبُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ن د و",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "نَادَىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "to call",
        "waznTlit": "nādā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form III)"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَنَادَيْنَاهُ",
        "answer": "And We called out to him",
        "pcklId": "29",
        "rootWordId": 1455,
        "tlit": "wanādaynāhu",
        "frequency": "53",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "104",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " وَنَادَيْنَاهُ أَنْ يَا إِبْرَاهِيمُ",
        "rootWord": "ن د و",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "نَادَىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "to call",
        "waznTlit": "nādā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form III)"
    },
    {
        "question": "مُنْذِرِينَ",
        "answer": "warners",
        "pcklId": "118",
        "rootWordId": 1456,
        "tlit": "mundhirīna",
        "frequency": "130",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "72",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " وَلَقَدْ أَرْسَلْنَا فِيهِمْ مُنْذِرِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ن ذ ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مُنذِر",
        "waznEnglish": "you vow",
        "waznTlit": "mundhir",
        "waznType": "Active participle (form IV)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْمُنْذَرِينَ",
        "answer": "(of) those who were warned",
        "pcklId": "128",
        "rootWordId": 1456,
        "tlit": "l-mundharīna",
        "frequency": "130",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "73",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " فَانْظُرْ كَيْفَ كَانَ عَاقِبَةُ الْمُنْذَرِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ن ذ ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مُنذَرِين",
        "waznEnglish": "you vow",
        "waznTlit": "mundharīn",
        "waznType": "Passive participle (form IV)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْمُنْذَرِينَ",
        "answer": "(for) those who were warned",
        "pcklId": "129",
        "rootWordId": 1456,
        "tlit": "l-mundharīna",
        "frequency": "130",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "177",
        "wordnum": "6",
        "arabicAyah": " فَإِذَا نَزَلَ بِسَاحَتِهِمْ فَسَاءَ صَبَاحُ الْمُنْذَرِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ن ذ ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مُنذَرِين",
        "waznEnglish": "you vow",
        "waznTlit": "mundharīn",
        "waznType": "Passive participle (form IV)"
    },
    {
        "question": "يُنْزَفُونَ",
        "answer": "will be intoxicated",
        "pcklId": "0",
        "rootWordId": 1459,
        "tlit": "yunzafūna",
        "frequency": "2",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "47",
        "wordnum": "7",
        "arabicAyah": " لَا فِيهَا غَوْلٌ وَلَا هُمْ عَنْهَا يُنْزَفُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ن ز ف",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ن ز ف",
        "waznEnglish": "to be intoxicated",
        "waznTlit": "nūn zāy fā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form IV)"
    },
    {
        "question": "نَزَلَ",
        "answer": "it descends",
        "pcklId": "3",
        "rootWordId": 1460,
        "tlit": "nazala",
        "frequency": "293",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "177",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " فَإِذَا نَزَلَ بِسَاحَتِهِمْ فَسَاءَ صَبَاحُ الْمُنْذَرِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ن ز ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "نَزَلَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to descend, to bring down",
        "waznTlit": "nazala",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "نُزُلًا",
        "answer": "(as) hospitality",
        "pcklId": "264",
        "rootWordId": 1460,
        "tlit": "nuzulan",
        "frequency": "293",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "62",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " أَذَٰلِكَ خَيْرٌ نُزُلًا أَمْ شَجَرَةُ الزَّقُّومِ",
        "rootWord": "ن ز ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "نُزُل",
        "waznEnglish": "it descended",
        "waznTlit": "nuzul",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "نَسَبًا",
        "answer": "a relationship",
        "pcklId": "2",
        "rootWordId": 1462,
        "tlit": "nasaban",
        "frequency": "3",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "158",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " وَجَعَلُوا بَيْنَهُ وَبَيْنَ الْجِنَّةِ نَسَبًا",
        "rootWord": "ن س ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ن س ب",
        "waznEnglish": "(there) will be relationship",
        "waznTlit": "nūn sīn bā",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَنَصَرْنَاهُمْ",
        "answer": "And We helped them",
        "pcklId": "40",
        "rootWordId": 1477,
        "tlit": "wanaṣarnāhum",
        "frequency": "158",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "116",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " وَنَصَرْنَاهُمْ فَكَانُوا هُمُ الْغَالِبِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ن ص ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "نَصَرَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to help",
        "waznTlit": "naṣara",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "تَنَاصَرُونَ",
        "answer": "you help one another",
        "pcklId": "59",
        "rootWordId": 1477,
        "tlit": "tanāṣarūna",
        "frequency": "158",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "25",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " مَا لَكُمْ لَا تَنَاصَرُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ن ص ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "تَنَاصَرُ",
        "waznEnglish": "to help",
        "waznTlit": "tanāṣaru",
        "waznType": "Verb (form VI)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْمَنْصُورُونَ",
        "answer": "(would be) the victorious",
        "pcklId": "153",
        "rootWordId": 1477,
        "tlit": "l-manṣūrūna",
        "frequency": "158",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "172",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّهُمْ لَهُمُ الْمَنْصُورُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ن ص ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مَنصُور",
        "waznEnglish": "will be helped",
        "waznTlit": "manṣūr",
        "waznType": "Passive participle"
    },
    {
        "question": "تَنْطِقُونَ",
        "answer": "you speak",
        "pcklId": "4",
        "rootWordId": 1486,
        "tlit": "tanṭiqūna",
        "frequency": "12",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "92",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " مَا لَكُمْ لَا تَنْطِقُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ن ط ق",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "يَنطِقُ",
        "waznEnglish": "to speak",
        "waznTlit": "yanṭiqu",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "يَنْظُرُونَ",
        "answer": "will see",
        "pcklId": "61",
        "rootWordId": 1487,
        "tlit": "yanẓurūna",
        "frequency": "129",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "19",
        "wordnum": "7",
        "arabicAyah": " فَإِنَّمَا هِيَ زَجْرَةٌ وَاحِدَةٌ فَإِذَا هُمْ يَنْظُرُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ن ظ ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "نَّظَرَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to look, to see",
        "waznTlit": "naẓara",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "فَانْظُرْ",
        "answer": "Then see",
        "pcklId": "62",
        "rootWordId": 1487,
        "tlit": "fa-unẓur",
        "frequency": "129",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "73",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " فَانْظُرْ كَيْفَ كَانَ عَاقِبَةُ الْمُنْذَرِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ن ظ ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "نَّظَرَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to look, to see",
        "waznTlit": "naẓara",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "فَنَظَرَ",
        "answer": "Then he glanced",
        "pcklId": "63",
        "rootWordId": 1487,
        "tlit": "fanaẓara",
        "frequency": "129",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "88",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " فَنَظَرَ نَظْرَةً فِي النُّجُومِ",
        "rootWord": "ن ظ ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "نَّظَرَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to look, to see",
        "waznTlit": "naẓara",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "فَانْظُرْ",
        "answer": "so look",
        "pcklId": "64",
        "rootWordId": 1487,
        "tlit": "fa-unẓur",
        "frequency": "129",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "102",
        "wordnum": "13",
        "arabicAyah": " يَا بُنَيَّ إِنِّي أَرَىٰ فِي الْمَنَامِ أَنِّي أَذْبَحُكَ فَانْظُرْ مَاذَا تَرَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ن ظ ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "نَّظَرَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to look, to see",
        "waznTlit": "naẓara",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "نَظْرَةً",
        "answer": "a glance",
        "pcklId": "108",
        "rootWordId": 1487,
        "tlit": "naẓratan",
        "frequency": "129",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "88",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " فَنَظَرَ نَظْرَةً فِي النُّجُومِ",
        "rootWord": "ن ظ ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "نَظْرَة",
        "waznEnglish": "(were) looking",
        "waznTlit": "naẓrat",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "فَلَنِعْمَ",
        "answer": "and Best",
        "pcklId": "12",
        "rootWordId": 1492,
        "tlit": "falaniʿ'ma",
        "frequency": "140",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "75",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " وَلَقَدْ نَادَانَا نُوحٌ فَلَنِعْمَ الْمُجِيبُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ن ع م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "نِعْمَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to be excellent",
        "waznTlit": "niʿ'ma",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "نِعْمَةُ",
        "answer": "(for the) Grace",
        "pcklId": "107",
        "rootWordId": 1492,
        "tlit": "niʿ'matu",
        "frequency": "140",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "57",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " وَلَوْلَا نِعْمَةُ رَبِّي لَكُنْتُ مِنَ الْمُحْضَرِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ن ع م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "نِعْمَة",
        "waznEnglish": "then good",
        "waznTlit": "niʿ'mat",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "النَّعِيمِ",
        "answer": "(of) Delight",
        "pcklId": "128",
        "rootWordId": 1492,
        "tlit": "l-naʿīmi",
        "frequency": "140",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "43",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " فِي جَنَّاتِ النَّعِيمِ",
        "rootWord": "ن ع م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "نَعِيم",
        "waznEnglish": "then good",
        "waznTlit": "naʿīm",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "لِنَفْسِهِ",
        "answer": "to himself",
        "pcklId": "243",
        "rootWordId": 1500,
        "tlit": "linafsihi",
        "frequency": "298",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "113",
        "wordnum": "9",
        "arabicAyah": " وَمِنْ ذُرِّيَّتِهِمَا مُحْسِنٌ وَظَالِمٌ لِنَفْسِهِ مُبِينٌ",
        "rootWord": "ن ف س",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "نَفْس",
        "waznEnglish": "self, soul, person, mind",
        "waznTlit": "nafs",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْمَنَامِ",
        "answer": "the dream",
        "pcklId": "2",
        "rootWordId": 1534,
        "tlit": "l-manāmi",
        "frequency": "9",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "102",
        "wordnum": "10",
        "arabicAyah": " يَا بُنَيَّ إِنِّي أَرَىٰ فِي الْمَنَامِ أَنِّي أَذْبَحُكَ فَانْظُرْ مَاذَا تَرَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ن و م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مَنَام",
        "waznEnglish": "your dream",
        "waznTlit": "manām",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "فَاهْدُوهُمْ",
        "answer": "then lead them",
        "pcklId": "106",
        "rootWordId": 1547,
        "tlit": "fa-ih'dūhum",
        "frequency": "316",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "23",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " فَاهْدُوهُمْ إِلَىٰ صِرَاطِ الْجَحِيمِ",
        "rootWord": "ه د ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "هَدَى",
        "waznEnglish": "to guide",
        "waznTlit": "hadā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "سَيَهْدِينِ",
        "answer": "He will guide me",
        "pcklId": "107",
        "rootWordId": 1547,
        "tlit": "sayahdīni",
        "frequency": "316",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "99",
        "wordnum": "6",
        "arabicAyah": " وَقَالَ إِنِّي ذَاهِبٌ إِلَىٰ رَبِّي سَيَهْدِينِ",
        "rootWord": "ه د ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "هَدَى",
        "waznEnglish": "to guide",
        "waznTlit": "hadā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَهَدَيْنَاهُمَا",
        "answer": "And We guided both of them",
        "pcklId": "108",
        "rootWordId": 1547,
        "tlit": "wahadaynāhumā",
        "frequency": "316",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "118",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " وَهَدَيْنَاهُمَا الصِّرَاطَ الْمُسْتَقِيمَ",
        "rootWord": "ه د ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "هَدَى",
        "waznEnglish": "to guide",
        "waznTlit": "hadā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "يُهْرَعُونَ",
        "answer": "they hastened",
        "pcklId": "1",
        "rootWordId": 1549,
        "tlit": "yuh'raʿūna",
        "frequency": "2",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "70",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " فَهُمْ عَلَىٰ آثَارِهِمْ يُهْرَعُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ه ر ع",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ه ر ع",
        "waznEnglish": "to rush, to hasten",
        "waznTlit": "hā rā ʿayn",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "سَتَجِدُنِي",
        "answer": "You will find me",
        "pcklId": "86",
        "rootWordId": 1588,
        "tlit": "satajidunī",
        "frequency": "107",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "102",
        "wordnum": "21",
        "arabicAyah": " افْعَلْ مَا تُؤْمَرُ سَتَجِدُنِي إِنْ شَاءَ اللَّهُ مِنَ الصَّابِرِينَ",
        "rootWord": "و ج د",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "وَجَدَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to find",
        "waznTlit": "wajada",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "لَوَاحِدٌ",
        "answer": "(is) surely One",
        "pcklId": "28",
        "rootWordId": 1593,
        "tlit": "lawāḥidun",
        "frequency": "68",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "4",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّ إِلَٰهَكُمْ لَوَاحِدٌ",
        "rootWord": "و ح د",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "وَٰحِد",
        "waznEnglish": "(of) one (kind)",
        "waznTlit": "wāḥid",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَاحِدَةٌ",
        "answer": "single",
        "pcklId": "44",
        "rootWordId": 1593,
        "tlit": "wāḥidatun",
        "frequency": "68",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "19",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " فَإِنَّمَا هِيَ زَجْرَةٌ وَاحِدَةٌ فَإِذَا هُمْ يَنْظُرُونَ",
        "rootWord": "و ح د",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "وَٰحِدَة",
        "waznEnglish": "(of) one (kind)",
        "waznTlit": "wāḥidat",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَتَذَرُونَ",
        "answer": "and you forsake",
        "pcklId": "27",
        "rootWordId": 1600,
        "tlit": "watadharūna",
        "frequency": "45",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "125",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " أَتَدْعُونَ بَعْلًا وَتَذَرُونَ أَحْسَنَ الْخَالِقِينَ",
        "rootWord": "و ذ ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "و ذ ر",
        "waznEnglish": "to leave, to forsake",
        "waznTlit": "wāw dhāl rā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَاصِبٌ",
        "answer": "perpetual",
        "pcklId": "1",
        "rootWordId": 1616,
        "tlit": "wāṣibun",
        "frequency": "2",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "9",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " دُحُورًا وَلَهُمْ عَذَابٌ وَاصِبٌ",
        "rootWord": "و ص ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "و ص ب",
        "waznEnglish": "constantly",
        "waznTlit": "wāw ṣād bā",
        "waznType": "Active participle"
    },
    {
        "question": "يَصِفُونَ",
        "answer": "they attribute",
        "pcklId": "10",
        "rootWordId": 1618,
        "tlit": "yaṣifūna",
        "frequency": "14",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "159",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " سُبْحَانَ اللَّهِ عَمَّا يَصِفُونَ",
        "rootWord": "و ص ف",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "يَصِفُ",
        "waznEnglish": "to attribute, to ascribe",
        "waznTlit": "yaṣifu",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "يَصِفُونَ",
        "answer": "they attribute",
        "pcklId": "11",
        "rootWordId": 1618,
        "tlit": "yaṣifūna",
        "frequency": "14",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "180",
        "wordnum": "6",
        "arabicAyah": " سُبْحَانَ رَبِّكَ رَبِّ الْعِزَّةِ عَمَّا يَصِفُونَ",
        "rootWord": "و ص ف",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "يَصِفُ",
        "waznEnglish": "to attribute, to ascribe",
        "waznTlit": "yaṣifu",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَقِفُوهُمْ",
        "answer": "And stop them",
        "pcklId": "2",
        "rootWordId": 1640,
        "tlit": "waqifūhum",
        "frequency": "4",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "24",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " وَقِفُوهُمْ إِنَّهُمْ مَسْئُولُونَ",
        "rootWord": "و ق ف",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "وُقِفُ",
        "waznEnglish": "to make stand",
        "waznTlit": "wuqifu",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "تَتَّقُونَ",
        "answer": "you fear",
        "pcklId": "152",
        "rootWordId": 1641,
        "tlit": "tattaqūna",
        "frequency": "258",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "124",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " إِذْ قَالَ لِقَوْمِهِ أَلَا تَتَّقُونَ",
        "rootWord": "و ق ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ٱتَّقَىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "to be righteous, to fear (Allah)",
        "waznTlit": "ittaqā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form VIII)"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَلَدَ",
        "answer": "Allah has begotten",
        "pcklId": "3",
        "rootWordId": 1647,
        "tlit": "walada",
        "frequency": "102",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "152",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " وَلَدَ اللَّهُ وَإِنَّهُمْ لَكَاذِبُونَ",
        "rootWord": "و ل د",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "وَلَدَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to beget, to be born",
        "waznTlit": "walada",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "فَتَوَلَّوْا",
        "answer": "So they turned away",
        "pcklId": "81",
        "rootWordId": 1648,
        "tlit": "fatawallaw",
        "frequency": "232",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "90",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " فَتَوَلَّوْا عَنْهُ مُدْبِرِينَ",
        "rootWord": "و ل ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "تَوَلَّىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "to turn",
        "waznTlit": "tawallā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form V)"
    },
    {
        "question": "فَتَوَلَّ",
        "answer": "So turn away",
        "pcklId": "82",
        "rootWordId": 1648,
        "tlit": "fatawalla",
        "frequency": "232",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "174",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " فَتَوَلَّ عَنْهُمْ حَتَّىٰ حِينٍ",
        "rootWord": "و ل ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "تَوَلَّىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "to turn",
        "waznTlit": "tawallā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form V)"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَتَوَلَّ",
        "answer": "So turn away",
        "pcklId": "83",
        "rootWordId": 1648,
        "tlit": "watawalla",
        "frequency": "232",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "178",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " وَتَوَلَّ عَنْهُمْ حَتَّىٰ حِينٍ",
        "rootWord": "و ل ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "تَوَلَّىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "to turn",
        "waznTlit": "tawallā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form V)"
    },
    {
        "question": "هَبْ",
        "answer": "grant",
        "pcklId": "16",
        "rootWordId": 1650,
        "tlit": "hab",
        "frequency": "25",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "100",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " رَبِّ هَبْ لِي مِنَ الصَّالِحِينَ",
        "rootWord": "و ه ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "وَهَبَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to grant, to bestow",
        "waznTlit": "wahaba",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْيَمِينِ",
        "answer": "the right",
        "pcklId": "50",
        "rootWordId": 1662,
        "tlit": "l-yamīni",
        "frequency": "71",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "28",
        "wordnum": "6",
        "arabicAyah": " قَالُوا إِنَّكُمْ كُنْتُمْ تَأْتُونَنَا عَنِ الْيَمِينِ",
        "rootWord": "ي م ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "يَمِين",
        "waznEnglish": "the right",
        "waznTlit": "yamīn",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "بِالْيَمِينِ",
        "answer": "with the right hand",
        "pcklId": "51",
        "rootWordId": 1662,
        "tlit": "bil-yamīni",
        "frequency": "71",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "93",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " فَرَاغَ عَلَيْهِمْ ضَرْبًا بِالْيَمِينِ",
        "rootWord": "ي م ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "يَمِين",
        "waznEnglish": "the right",
        "waznTlit": "yamīn",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "يَوْمُ",
        "answer": "(is the) Day",
        "pcklId": "196",
        "rootWordId": 1664,
        "tlit": "yawmu",
        "frequency": "405",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "20",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " وَقَالُوا يَا وَيْلَنَا هَٰذَا يَوْمُ الدِّينِ",
        "rootWord": "ي و م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ي و م",
        "waznEnglish": "(of the) Day",
        "waznTlit": "yā wāw mīm",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "يَوْمُ",
        "answer": "(is the) Day",
        "pcklId": "197",
        "rootWordId": 1664,
        "tlit": "yawmu",
        "frequency": "405",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "21",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " هَٰذَا يَوْمُ الْفَصْلِ الَّذِي كُنْتُمْ بِهِ تُكَذِّبُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ي و م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ي و م",
        "waznEnglish": "(of the) Day",
        "waznTlit": "yā wāw mīm",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْيَوْمَ",
        "answer": "(on) that Day",
        "pcklId": "198",
        "rootWordId": 1664,
        "tlit": "l-yawma",
        "frequency": "405",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "26",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " بَلْ هُمُ الْيَوْمَ مُسْتَسْلِمُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ي و م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ي و م",
        "waznEnglish": "(of the) Day",
        "waznTlit": "yā wāw mīm",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "يَوْمِ",
        "answer": "the Day",
        "pcklId": "199",
        "rootWordId": 1664,
        "tlit": "yawmi",
        "frequency": "405",
        "surahnum": "37",
        "ayahnum": "144",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " لَلَبِثَ فِي بَطْنِهِ إِلَىٰ يَوْمِ يُبْعَثُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ي و م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ي و م",
        "waznEnglish": "(of the) Day",
        "waznTlit": "yā wāw mīm",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    }
]; 
export default words;